EOG8BP3T3	GO:0003676	name: nucleic acid binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any nucleic acid." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8BP3T3	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8BP3T3	GO:0005634	name: nucleus	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A membrane-bounded organelle of eukaryotic cells in which chromosomes are housed and replicated. In most cells, the nucleus contains all of the cell's chromosomes except the organellar chromosomes, and is the site of RNA synthesis and processing. In some species, or in specialized cell types, RNA metabolism or DNA replication may be absent." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8BP3T3	GO:0046872	name: metal ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any metal ion." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8BP3T3	GO:0035556	name: intracellular signal transduction	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which a signal is passed on to downstream components within the cell, which become activated themselves to further propagate the signal and finally trigger a change in the function or state of the cell." [GOC:bf, GOC:jl, GOC:signaling, ISBN:3527303782]	
EOG8XSP6B	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8XSP6B	GO:0003723	name: RNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an RNA molecule or a portion thereof." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8XSP6B	GO:0003964	name: RNA-directed DNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: deoxynucleoside triphosphate + DNA(n) = diphosphate + DNA(n+1). Catalyzes RNA-template-directed extension of the 3'- end of a DNA strand by one deoxynucleotide at a time." [EC:2.7.7.49]	
EOG8XSP6B	GO:0004190	name: aspartic-type endopeptidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of internal, alpha-peptide bonds in a polypeptide chain by a mechanism in which a water molecule bound by the side chains of aspartic residues at the active center acts as a nucleophile." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8XSP6B	GO:0005882	name: intermediate filament	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A cytoskeletal structure that forms a distinct elongated structure, characteristically 10 nm in diameter, that occurs in the cytoplasm of eukaryotic cells. Intermediate filaments form a fibrous system, composed of chemically heterogeneous subunits and involved in mechanically integrating the various components of the cytoplasmic space. Intermediate filaments may be divided into five chemically distinct classes: Type I, acidic keratins; Type II, basic keratins; Type III, including desmin, vimentin and others; Type IV, neurofilaments and related filaments; and Type V, lamins." [http://www.cytochemistry.net/Cell-biology/intermediate_filaments.htm, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8XSP6B	GO:0005198	name: structural molecule activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "The action of a molecule that contributes to the structural integrity of a complex or assembly within or outside a cell." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8XSP6B	GO:0006355	name: regulation of transcription, DNA-templated	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that modulates the frequency, rate or extent of cellular DNA-templated transcription." [GOC:go_curators, GOC:txnOH]	
EOG8XSP6B	GO:0016787	name: hydrolase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of various bonds, e.g. C-O, C-N, C-C, phosphoric anhydride bonds, etc. Hydrolase is the systematic name for any enzyme of EC class 3." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8XSP6B	GO:0015074	name: DNA integration	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which a segment of DNA is incorporated into another, usually larger, DNA molecule such as a chromosome." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8XSP6B	GO:0005634	name: nucleus	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A membrane-bounded organelle of eukaryotic cells in which chromosomes are housed and replicated. In most cells, the nucleus contains all of the cell's chromosomes except the organellar chromosomes, and is the site of RNA synthesis and processing. In some species, or in specialized cell types, RNA metabolism or DNA replication may be absent." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8NCPTT	GO:0003677	name: DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular function by which a gene product interacts selectively and non-covalently with DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid)." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:tb, GOC:vw]	
EOG8NCPTT	GO:0003964	name: RNA-directed DNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: deoxynucleoside triphosphate + DNA(n) = diphosphate + DNA(n+1). Catalyzes RNA-template-directed extension of the 3'- end of a DNA strand by one deoxynucleotide at a time." [EC:2.7.7.49]	
EOG8NCPTT	GO:0003723	name: RNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an RNA molecule or a portion thereof." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8KWN7R	GO:0003677	name: DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular function by which a gene product interacts selectively and non-covalently with DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid)." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:tb, GOC:vw]	
EOG8KWN7R	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8KWN7R	GO:0033014	name: tetrapyrrole biosynthetic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways leading to the formation of tetrapyrroles, natural pigments containing four pyrrole rings joined by one-carbon units linking position 2 of one pyrrole ring to position 5 of the next." [CHEBI:26932, GOC:mah]	
EOG8KWN7R	GO:0004852	name: uroporphyrinogen-III synthase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: hydroxymethylbilane = H(2)O + uroporphyrinogen III." [EC:4.2.1.75, RHEA:18968]	
EOG8KWN7R	GO:0035556	name: intracellular signal transduction	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which a signal is passed on to downstream components within the cell, which become activated themselves to further propagate the signal and finally trigger a change in the function or state of the cell." [GOC:bf, GOC:jl, GOC:signaling, ISBN:3527303782]	
EOG8WDGTK	GO:0019028	name: viral capsid	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The protein coat that surrounds the infective nucleic acid in some virus particles. It comprises numerous regularly arranged subunits, or capsomeres." [GOC:mtg_sensu, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8XH2H5	GO:0003723	name: RNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an RNA molecule or a portion thereof." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8XH2H5	GO:0022857	name: transmembrane transporter activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Enables the transfer of a substance from one side of a membrane to the other." [GOC:mtg_transport, ISBN:0815340729]	
EOG8XH2H5	GO:0016021	name: integral component of membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The component of a membrane consisting of the gene products and protein complexes having at least some part of their peptide sequence embedded in the hydrophobic region of the membrane." [GOC:dos, GOC:go_curators]	
EOG80P6ND	GO:0022891	name: substrate-specific transmembrane transporter activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Enables the transfer of a specific substance or group of related substances from one side of a membrane to the other." [GOC:jid, GOC:mtg_transport, ISBN:0815340729]	
EOG80P6ND	GO:0022857	name: transmembrane transporter activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Enables the transfer of a substance from one side of a membrane to the other." [GOC:mtg_transport, ISBN:0815340729]	
EOG80P6ND	GO:0008643	name: carbohydrate transport	namespace: biological_process	def: "The directed movement of carbohydrate into, out of or within a cell, or between cells, by means of some agent such as a transporter or pore. Carbohydrates are any of a group of organic compounds based of the general formula Cx(H2O)y." [GOC:ai]	
EOG80P6ND	GO:0005886	name: plasma membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The membrane surrounding a cell that separates the cell from its external environment. It consists of a phospholipid bilayer and associated proteins." [ISBN:0716731363]	
EOG80P6ND	GO:0015771	name: trehalose transport	namespace: biological_process	def: "The directed movement of trehalose into, out of or within a cell, or between cells, by means of some agent such as a transporter or pore. Trehalose is a disaccharide isomeric with sucrose and obtained from certain lichens and fungi." [GOC:ai]	
EOG80P6ND	GO:0015574	name: trehalose transmembrane transporter activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Enables the transfer of trehalose from one side of the membrane to the other. Trehalose is the disaccharide alpha-D-glucopyranosyl-alpha-D-glucopyranoside that acts of a reserve carbohydrate in certain fungi, algae and lichens." [GOC:mtg_transport, ISBN:0198506732, ISBN:0815340729]	
EOG80P6ND	GO:0032440	name: 2-alkenal reductase [NAD(P)] activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: n-alkanal + NAD(P)+ = alk-2-enal + NAD(P)H + H+." [EC:1.3.1.74, PMID:16299173]	
EOG80P6ND	GO:0016020	name: membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A lipid bilayer along with all the proteins and protein complexes embedded in it an attached to it." [GOC:dos, GOC:mah, ISBN:0815316194]	
EOG80P6ND	GO:0046427	name: positive regulation of JAK-STAT cascade	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that activates or increases the frequency, rate or extent of the JAK-STAT signaling pathway activity." [GOC:bf]	
EOG8284G8	GO:0055085	name: transmembrane transport	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which a solute is transported across a lipid bilayer, from one side of a membrane to the other" [GOC:dph, GOC:jid]	
EOG8284G8	GO:0005215	name: transporter activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Enables the directed movement of substances (such as macromolecules, small molecules, ions) into, out of or within a cell, or between cells." [GOC:ai, GOC:dgf]	
EOG8284G8	GO:0015114	name: phosphate ion transmembrane transporter activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Enables the transfer of phosphate (PO4 3-) ions from one side of a membrane to the other." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8284G8	GO:0005886	name: plasma membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The membrane surrounding a cell that separates the cell from its external environment. It consists of a phospholipid bilayer and associated proteins." [ISBN:0716731363]	
EOG8284G8	GO:0006814	name: sodium ion transport	namespace: biological_process	def: "The directed movement of sodium ions (Na+) into, out of or within a cell, or between cells, by means of some agent such as a transporter or pore." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8284G8	GO:0015293	name: symporter activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Enables the active transport of a solute across a membrane by a mechanism whereby two or more species are transported together in the same direction in a tightly coupled process not directly linked to a form of energy other than chemiosmotic energy." [GOC:mtg_transport, ISBN:0815340729, PMID:10839820]	
EOG8284G8	GO:0005314	name: high-affinity glutamate transmembrane transporter activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Enables the transfer of a solute or solutes from one side of a membrane to the other according to the reaction: glutamate(out) + H+(out) = glutamate(in) + H+(in). In high-affinity transport the transporter is able to bind the solute even if it is only present at very low concentrations." [TC:2.A.3.10.5]	
EOG8284G8	GO:0015321	name: sodium-dependent phosphate transmembrane transporter activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Enables the transfer of phosphate (PO4 3-) ions from one side of a membrane to the other, requiring sodium ions." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8284G8	GO:0051938	name: L-glutamate import	namespace: biological_process	def: "The directed movement of L-glutamate, the L-enantiomer of the anion of 2-aminopentanedioic acid, into a cell or organelle." [GOC:ai, GOC:jsg, GOC:mah]	
EOG8284G8	GO:0048190	name: wing disc dorsal/ventral pattern formation	namespace: biological_process	def: "The establishment, maintenance and elaboration of the dorsal/ventral axis of the wing disc, a precursor to the adult wing." [GOC:jid]	
EOG8284G8	GO:0006541	name: glutamine metabolic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways involving glutamine, 2-amino-4-carbamoylbutanoic acid." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8284G8	GO:0035725	name: sodium ion transmembrane transport	namespace: biological_process	def: "A process in which a sodium ion is transported from one side of a membrane to the other by means of some agent such as a transporter or pore." [GOC:vw]	
EOG8284G8	GO:0001666	name: response to hypoxia	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that results in a change in state or activity of a cell or an organism (in terms of movement, secretion, enzyme production, gene expression, etc.) as a result of a stimulus indicating lowered oxygen tension. Hypoxia, defined as a decline in O2 levels below normoxic levels of 20.8 - 20.95%, results in metabolic adaptation at both the cellular and organismal level." [GOC:hjd]	
EOG8284G8	GO:0007005	name: mitochondrion organization	namespace: biological_process	def: "A process that is carried out at the cellular level which results in the assembly, arrangement of constituent parts, or disassembly of a mitochondrion; includes mitochondrial morphogenesis and distribution, and replication of the mitochondrial genome as well as synthesis of new mitochondrial components." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:mah, GOC:sgd_curators, PMID:9786946]	
EOG8284G8	GO:0035435	name: phosphate ion transmembrane transport	namespace: biological_process	def: "The directed movement of phosphate across a membrane by means of some agent such as a transporter or pore." [GOC:vw]	
EOG8284G8	GO:0044341	name: sodium-dependent phosphate transport	namespace: biological_process	def: "The directed movement of phosphate into, out of or within a cell, or between cells, by means of some agent such as a transporter or pore, by a mechanism dependent upon sodium ions." [GOC:BHF, GOC:jl]	
EOG8284G8	GO:0005436	name: sodium:phosphate symporter activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the transfer of a solute or solutes from one side of a membrane to the other according to the reaction: Na+(out) + phosphate(out) = Na+(in) + phosphate(in)." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8284G8	GO:0004930	name: G-protein coupled receptor activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Combining with an extracellular signal and transmitting the signal across the membrane by activating an associated G-protein; promotes the exchange of GDP for GTP on the alpha subunit of a heterotrimeric G-protein complex." [GOC:bf, http://www.iuphar-db.org, Wikipedia:GPCR]	
EOG89W4VJ	GO:0022891	name: substrate-specific transmembrane transporter activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Enables the transfer of a specific substance or group of related substances from one side of a membrane to the other." [GOC:jid, GOC:mtg_transport, ISBN:0815340729]	
EOG89W4VJ	GO:0022857	name: transmembrane transporter activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Enables the transfer of a substance from one side of a membrane to the other." [GOC:mtg_transport, ISBN:0815340729]	
EOG89W4VJ	GO:0008643	name: carbohydrate transport	namespace: biological_process	def: "The directed movement of carbohydrate into, out of or within a cell, or between cells, by means of some agent such as a transporter or pore. Carbohydrates are any of a group of organic compounds based of the general formula Cx(H2O)y." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8CRPGZ	GO:0006351	name: transcription, DNA-templated	namespace: biological_process	def: "The cellular synthesis of RNA on a template of DNA." [GOC:jl, GOC:txnOH]	
EOG8CRPGZ	GO:0003899	name: DNA-directed RNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: nucleoside triphosphate + RNA(n) = diphosphate + RNA(n+1). Utilizes a DNA template, i.e. the catalysis of DNA-template-directed extension of the 3'-end of an RNA strand by one nucleotide at a time. Can initiate a chain 'de novo'." [EC:2.7.7.6]	
EOG8CRPGZ	GO:0003676	name: nucleic acid binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any nucleic acid." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8C8B8R	GO:0015074	name: DNA integration	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which a segment of DNA is incorporated into another, usually larger, DNA molecule such as a chromosome." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8C8B8R	GO:0005634	name: nucleus	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A membrane-bounded organelle of eukaryotic cells in which chromosomes are housed and replicated. In most cells, the nucleus contains all of the cell's chromosomes except the organellar chromosomes, and is the site of RNA synthesis and processing. In some species, or in specialized cell types, RNA metabolism or DNA replication may be absent." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8C8B8R	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8C8B8R	GO:0046872	name: metal ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any metal ion." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8C8B8R	GO:0005524	name: ATP binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with ATP, adenosine 5'-triphosphate, a universally important coenzyme and enzyme regulator." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8C8B8R	GO:0015937	name: coenzyme A biosynthetic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways resulting in the formation of coenzyme A, 3'-phosphoadenosine-(5')diphospho(4')pantatheine, an acyl carrier in many acylation and acyl-transfer reactions in which the intermediate is a thiol ester." [ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG8C8B8R	GO:0004594	name: pantothenate kinase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: ATP + pantothenate = ADP + D-4'-phosphopantothenate." [EC:2.7.1.33]	
EOG8X6FPX	GO:0047077	name: Photinus-luciferin 4-monooxygenase (ATP-hydrolyzing) activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: O2 + ATP + Photinus luciferin = light + diphosphate + AMP + CO2 + oxidized Photinus luciferin." [EC:1.13.12.7, MetaCyc:1.13.12.7-RXN]	
EOG8X6FPX	GO:0016874	name: ligase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the joining of two substances, or two groups within a single molecule, with the concomitant hydrolysis of the diphosphate bond in ATP or a similar triphosphate." [EC:6, GOC:mah]	
EOG8X6FPX	GO:0004497	name: monooxygenase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the incorporation of one atom from molecular oxygen into a compound and the reduction of the other atom of oxygen to water." [http://www.onelook.com/, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8X6FPX	GO:0008756	name: o-succinylbenzoate-CoA ligase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: 2-succinylbenzoate + ATP + CoA = 2-succinylbenzoyl-CoA + AMP + diphosphate." [EC:6.2.1.26]	
EOG8X6FPX	GO:0004467	name: long-chain fatty acid-CoA ligase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: ATP + a long-chain carboxylic acid + CoA = AMP + diphosphate + an acyl-CoA; a long-chain fatty acid is a fatty acid with a chain length between C13 and C22." [CHEBI:15904, EC:6.2.1.3]	
EOG8X6FPX	GO:0005524	name: ATP binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with ATP, adenosine 5'-triphosphate, a universally important coenzyme and enzyme regulator." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8X6FPX	GO:0006637	name: acyl-CoA metabolic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways involving acyl-CoA, any derivative of coenzyme A in which the sulfhydryl group is in thiolester linkage with an acyl group." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8X6FPX	GO:0046627	name: negative regulation of insulin receptor signaling pathway	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that stops, prevents, or reduces the frequency, rate or extent of insulin receptor signaling." [GOC:bf]	
EOG8X6FPX	GO:0046949	name: fatty-acyl-CoA biosynthetic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways resulting in the formation of a fatty-acyl-CoA, any derivative of coenzyme A in which the sulfhydryl group is in thiolester linkage with a fatty-acyl group." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8X6FPX	GO:0005777	name: peroxisome	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A small organelle enclosed by a single membrane, and found in most eukaryotic cells. Contains peroxidases and other enzymes involved in a variety of metabolic processes including free radical detoxification, lipid catabolism and biosynthesis, and hydrogen peroxide metabolism." [GOC:pm, PMID:9302272, UniProtKB-KW:KW-0576]	
EOG8X6FPX	GO:0019433	name: triglyceride catabolic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways resulting in the breakdown of a triglyceride, any triester of glycerol." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8X6FPX	GO:0001676	name: long-chain fatty acid metabolic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways involving long-chain fatty acids, A long-chain fatty acid is a fatty acid with a chain length between C13 and C22." [CHEBI:15904, GOC:ajp]	
EOG8X6FPX	GO:0004321	name: fatty-acyl-CoA synthase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: acetyl-CoA + n malonyl-CoA + 2n NADH + 2n NADPH + 4n H+ = a long-chain acyl-CoA + n CoA + n CO2 + 2n NAD+ + 2n NADP+." [EC:2.3.1.86]	
EOG8X6FPX	GO:0071616	name: acyl-CoA biosynthetic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways resulting in the formation of acyl-CoA, any derivative of coenzyme A in which the sulfhydryl group is in thiolester linkage with an acyl group." [GOC:cjk]	
EOG8X6FPX	GO:0016021	name: integral component of membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The component of a membrane consisting of the gene products and protein complexes having at least some part of their peptide sequence embedded in the hydrophobic region of the membrane." [GOC:dos, GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8X6FPX	GO:0042626	name: ATPase activity, coupled to transmembrane movement of substances	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: ATP + H2O = ADP + phosphate, to directly drive the active transport of a substance across a membrane." [EC:3.6.1.3, GOC:jl]	
EOG8X6FPX	GO:0009062	name: fatty acid catabolic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways resulting in the breakdown of a fatty acid, any of the aliphatic monocarboxylic acids that can be liberated by hydrolysis from naturally occurring fats and oils. Fatty acids are predominantly straight-chain acids of 4 to 24 carbon atoms, which may be saturated or unsaturated; branched fatty acids and hydroxy fatty acids also occur, and very long chain acids of over 30 carbons are found in waxes." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8X6FPX	GO:0016887	name: ATPase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: ATP + H2O = ADP + phosphate + 2 H+. May or may not be coupled to another reaction." [EC:3.6.1.3, GOC:jl]	
EOG8X6FPX	GO:0008218	name: bioluminescence	namespace: biological_process	def: "The production of light by certain enzyme-catalyzed reactions in cells." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8GTNT0	GO:0015074	name: DNA integration	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which a segment of DNA is incorporated into another, usually larger, DNA molecule such as a chromosome." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8GTNT0	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
