EOG8XSP3N	GO:0005576	name: extracellular region	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The space external to the outermost structure of a cell. For cells without external protective or external encapsulating structures this refers to space outside of the plasma membrane. This term covers the host cell environment outside an intracellular parasite." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8XSP3N	GO:0006030	name: chitin metabolic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways involving chitin, a linear polysaccharide consisting of beta-(1->4)-linked N-acetyl-D-glucosamine residues." [GOC:jl, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8XSP3N	GO:0004252	name: serine-type endopeptidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of internal, alpha-peptide bonds in a polypeptide chain by a catalytic mechanism that involves a catalytic triad consisting of a serine nucleophile that is activated by a proton relay involving an acidic residue (e.g. aspartate or glutamate) and a basic residue (usually histidine)." [GOC:mah, http://merops.sanger.ac.uk/about/glossary.htm#CATTYPE, ISBN:0716720094]	
EOG8XSP3N	GO:0005044	name: scavenger receptor activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Combining with any modified low-density lipoprotein (LDL) or other polyanionic ligand and delivering the ligand into the cell via endocytosis. Ligands include acetylated and oxidized LDL, Gram-positive and Gram-negative bacteria, apoptotic cells, beta-amyloid fibrils, and advanced glycation end products (AGEs)." [GOC:bf, PMID:11790542, PMID:12379907, PMID:12621157, PMID:20981357]	
EOG8XSP3N	GO:0016020	name: membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A lipid bilayer along with all the proteins and protein complexes embedded in it an attached to it." [GOC:dos, GOC:mah, ISBN:0815316194]	
EOG8XSP3N	GO:0006032	name: chitin catabolic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways resulting in the breakdown of chitin, a linear polysaccharide consisting of beta-(1->4)-linked N-acetyl-D-glucosamine residues." [GOC:jl, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8XSP3N	GO:0005975	name: carbohydrate metabolic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways involving carbohydrates, any of a group of organic compounds based of the general formula Cx(H2O)y. Includes the formation of carbohydrate derivatives by the addition of a carbohydrate residue to another molecule." [GOC:mah, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8XSP3N	GO:0004568	name: chitinase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of (1->4)-beta linkages of N-acetyl-D-glucosamine (GlcNAc) polymers of chitin and chitodextrins." [EC:3.2.1.14, GOC:bf, GOC:kah, GOC:pde, PMID:11468293]	
EOG8XSP3N	GO:0006955	name: immune response	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any immune system process that functions in the calibrated response of an organism to a potential internal or invasive threat." [GO_REF:0000022, GOC:add, GOC:mtg_15nov05]	
EOG8XSP3N	GO:0030247	name: polysaccharide binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any polysaccharide, a polymer of many (typically more than 10) monosaccharide residues linked glycosidically." [CHEBI:18154, GOC:mah]	
EOG8XSP3N	GO:0030246	name: carbohydrate binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any carbohydrate, which includes monosaccharides, oligosaccharides and polysaccharides as well as substances derived from monosaccharides by reduction of the carbonyl group (alditols), by oxidation of one or more hydroxy groups to afford the corresponding aldehydes, ketones, or carboxylic acids, or by replacement of one or more hydroxy group(s) by a hydrogen atom. Cyclitols are generally not regarded as carbohydrates." [CHEBI:16646, GOC:mah]	
EOG8XSP3N	GO:0006508	name: proteolysis	namespace: biological_process	def: "The hydrolysis of proteins into smaller polypeptides and/or amino acids by cleavage of their peptide bonds." [GOC:bf, GOC:mah]	
EOG8XSP3N	GO:0007616	name: long-term memory	namespace: biological_process	def: "The memory process that deals with the storage, retrieval and modification of information a long time (typically weeks, months or years) after receiving that information. This type of memory is typically dependent on gene transcription regulated by second messenger activation." [http://hebb.mit.edu/courses/9.03/lecture4.html, ISBN:0582227089]	
EOG8XSP3N	GO:0004190	name: aspartic-type endopeptidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of internal, alpha-peptide bonds in a polypeptide chain by a mechanism in which a water molecule bound by the side chains of aspartic residues at the active center acts as a nucleophile." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8XSP3N	GO:0007614	name: short-term memory	namespace: biological_process	def: "The memory process that deals with the storage, retrieval and modification of information received a short time (up to about 30 minutes) ago. This type of memory is typically dependent on direct, transient effects of second messenger activation." [http://hebb.mit.edu/courses/9.03/lecture4.html, ISBN:0582227089]	
EOG81K1TV	GO:0001530	name: lipopolysaccharide binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with lipopolysaccharide." [PMID:11079463]	
EOG81K1TV	GO:0030882	name: lipid antigen binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with a lipid antigen." [PMID:14500461]	
EOG81K1TV	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG81K1TV	GO:0022008	name: neurogenesis	namespace: biological_process	def: "Generation of cells within the nervous system." [GO_REF:0000021, GOC:cls, GOC:curators, GOC:dgh, GOC:dph, GOC:jid, GOC:mtg_15jun06]	
EOG81K1TV	GO:0005615	name: extracellular space	namespace: cellular_component	def: "That part of a multicellular organism outside the cells proper, usually taken to be outside the plasma membranes, and occupied by fluid." [ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG81K1TV	GO:0070891	name: lipoteichoic acid binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with lipoteichoic acid." [GOC:add, PMID:14665680]	
EOG81K1TV	GO:0061057	name: peptidoglycan recognition protein signaling pathway	namespace: biological_process	def: "A series of molecular signals initiated by binding of peptidoglycan to a receptor on the surface of the target cell and ending with regulation of a downstream cellular process. The main outcome of the Imd signaling is the production of antimicrobial peptides." [GOC:dph, PMID:18688280]	
EOG81K1TV	GO:0042834	name: peptidoglycan binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently, in a non-covalent manner, with peptidoglycan, any of a class of glycoconjugates found in bacterial cell walls." [GOC:go_curators, PMID:14698226]	
EOG8MGVNF	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8MGVNF	GO:0003723	name: RNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an RNA molecule or a portion thereof." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8MGVNF	GO:0003964	name: RNA-directed DNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: deoxynucleoside triphosphate + DNA(n) = diphosphate + DNA(n+1). Catalyzes RNA-template-directed extension of the 3'- end of a DNA strand by one deoxynucleotide at a time." [EC:2.7.7.49]	
EOG8MGVNF	GO:0003677	name: DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular function by which a gene product interacts selectively and non-covalently with DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid)." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:tb, GOC:vw]	
EOG8MGVNF	GO:0015074	name: DNA integration	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which a segment of DNA is incorporated into another, usually larger, DNA molecule such as a chromosome." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8MGVNF	GO:0045202	name: synapse	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The junction between a nerve fiber of one neuron and another neuron or muscle fiber or glial cell; the site of interneuronal communication. As the nerve fiber approaches the synapse it enlarges into a specialized structure, the presynaptic nerve ending, which contains mitochondria and synaptic vesicles. At the tip of the nerve ending is the presynaptic membrane; facing it, and separated from it by a minute cleft (the synaptic cleft) is a specialized area of membrane on the receiving cell, known as the postsynaptic membrane. In response to the arrival of nerve impulses, the presynaptic nerve ending secretes molecules of neurotransmitters into the synaptic cleft. These diffuse across the cleft and transmit the signal to the postsynaptic membrane." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8MGVNF	GO:0003012	name: muscle system process	namespace: biological_process	def: "A organ system process carried out at the level of a muscle. Muscle tissue is composed of contractile cells or fibers." [GOC:mtg_cardio]	
EOG8MGVNF	GO:0042595	name: behavioral response to starvation	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that results in a change in the behavior of an organism as a result of deprivation of nourishment." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8MGVNF	GO:0030017	name: sarcomere	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The repeating unit of a myofibril in a muscle cell, composed of an array of overlapping thick and thin filaments between two adjacent Z discs." [ISBN:0815316194]	
EOG84F8QM	GO:0004553	name: hydrolase activity, hydrolyzing O-glycosyl compounds	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of any O-glycosyl bond." [GOC:mah]	
EOG84F8QM	GO:0008422	name: beta-glucosidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of terminal, non-reducing beta-D-glucose residues with release of beta-D-glucose." [EC:3.2.1.21]	
EOG84F8QM	GO:0008970	name: phosphatidylcholine 1-acylhydrolase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: phosphatidylcholine + H2O = 2-acylglycerophosphocholine + a carboxylate." [EC:3.1.1.32]	
EOG84F8QM	GO:0052740	name: 1-acyl-2-lysophosphatidylserine acylhydrolase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: 1-acyl-2-lysophosphatidylserine + H2O = sn-glycerol-phosphoserine + a carboxylate." [BRENDA:3.1.1.32]	
EOG84F8QM	GO:0052739	name: phosphatidylserine 1-acylhydrolase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: phosphatidylserine + H2O = 2-acyl-sn-glycero-3-phosphoserine + fatty acid." [KEGG:R04034]	
EOG8ZSCHP	GO:0005634	name: nucleus	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A membrane-bounded organelle of eukaryotic cells in which chromosomes are housed and replicated. In most cells, the nucleus contains all of the cell's chromosomes except the organellar chromosomes, and is the site of RNA synthesis and processing. In some species, or in specialized cell types, RNA metabolism or DNA replication may be absent." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8ZSCHP	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8ZSCHP	GO:0046872	name: metal ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any metal ion." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8ZSCHP	GO:0005739	name: mitochondrion	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A semiautonomous, self replicating organelle that occurs in varying numbers, shapes, and sizes in the cytoplasm of virtually all eukaryotic cells. It is notably the site of tissue respiration." [GOC:giardia, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8ZSCHP	GO:0003677	name: DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular function by which a gene product interacts selectively and non-covalently with DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid)." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:tb, GOC:vw]	
EOG8ZSCHP	GO:0005840	name: ribosome	namespace: cellular_component	def: "An intracellular organelle, about 200 A in diameter, consisting of RNA and protein. It is the site of protein biosynthesis resulting from translation of messenger RNA (mRNA). It consists of two subunits, one large and one small, each containing only protein and RNA. Both the ribosome and its subunits are characterized by their sedimentation coefficients, expressed in Svedberg units (symbol: S). Hence, the prokaryotic ribosome (70S) comprises a large (50S) subunit and a small (30S) subunit, while the eukaryotic ribosome (80S) comprises a large (60S) subunit and a small (40S) subunit. Two sites on the ribosomal large subunit are involved in translation, namely the aminoacyl site (A site) and peptidyl site (P site). Ribosomes from prokaryotes, eukaryotes, mitochondria, and chloroplasts have characteristically distinct ribosomal proteins." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8ZSCHP	GO:0007349	name: cellularization	namespace: biological_process	def: "The separation of a multi-nucleate cell or syncytium into individual cells. An example of this is found in Drosophila melanogaster embryo development." [GOC:go_curators, GOC:mtg_sensu, ISBN:0716731363]	
EOG8ZSCHP	GO:0045143	name: homologous chromosome segregation	namespace: biological_process	def: "The cell cycle process in which replicated homologous chromosomes are organized and then physically separated and apportioned to two sets during the first division of the meiotic cell cycle. Each replicated chromosome, composed of two sister chromatids, aligns at the cell equator, paired with its homologous partner; this pairing off, referred to as synapsis, permits genetic recombination. One homolog (both sister chromatids) of each morphologic type goes into each of the resulting chromosome sets." [GOC:ai, ISBN:0815316194]	
EOG8ZSCHP	GO:0007143	name: female meiotic division	namespace: biological_process	def: "A cell cycle process by which the cell nucleus divides as part of a meiotic cell cycle in the female germline." [GOC:dph, GOC:ems, GOC:mah]	
EOG8ZSCHP	GO:0007279	name: pole cell formation	namespace: biological_process	def: "Formation of a small group of cells (pole cells) at the posterior pole of the insect blastula. They are the first cells to cellularize after the arrival of nuclei at the end of the syncytial blastula stage and are the precursors to the insect germ cells." [GOC:bf, PMID:9988212]	
EOG8ZSCHP	GO:0006366	name: transcription from RNA polymerase II promoter	namespace: biological_process	def: "The synthesis of RNA from a DNA template by RNA polymerase II, originating at an RNA polymerase II promoter. Includes transcription of messenger RNA (mRNA) and certain small nuclear RNAs (snRNAs)." [GOC:jl, GOC:txnOH, ISBN:0321000382]	
EOG8ZSCHP	GO:0006357	name: regulation of transcription from RNA polymerase II promoter	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that modulates the frequency, rate or extent of transcription from an RNA polymerase II promoter." [GOC:go_curators, GOC:txnOH]	
EOG8ZSCHP	GO:0007343	name: egg activation	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which the egg becomes metabolically active, initiates protein and DNA synthesis and undergoes structural changes to its cortex and/or cytoplasm." [GOC:bf, PMID:9630751]	
EOG8ZSCHP	GO:0000987	name: core promoter proximal region sequence-specific DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with a sequence of DNA that is in cis with and relatively close to the core promoter. The transcribed region might be described as a gene, cistron, or operon." [GOC:txnOH]	
EOG8ZSCHP	GO:0045944	name: positive regulation of transcription from RNA polymerase II promoter	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that activates or increases the frequency, rate or extent of transcription from an RNA polymerase II promoter." [GOC:go_curators, GOC:txnOH]	
