EOG883GNT	GO:0003723	name: RNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an RNA molecule or a portion thereof." [GOC:mah]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0003676	name: nucleic acid binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any nucleic acid." [GOC:jl]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0004519	name: endonuclease activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of ester linkages within nucleic acids by creating internal breaks." [GOC:mah, ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0004523	name: RNA-DNA hybrid ribonuclease activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the endonucleolytic cleavage of RNA in RNA-DNA hybrids to 5'-phosphomonoesters." [EC:3.1.26.4]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0006511	name: ubiquitin-dependent protein catabolic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways resulting in the breakdown of a protein or peptide by hydrolysis of its peptide bonds, initiated by the covalent attachment of a ubiquitin group, or multiple ubiquitin groups, to the protein." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0046872	name: metal ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any metal ion." [GOC:ai]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0005634	name: nucleus	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A membrane-bounded organelle of eukaryotic cells in which chromosomes are housed and replicated. In most cells, the nucleus contains all of the cell's chromosomes except the organellar chromosomes, and is the site of RNA synthesis and processing. In some species, or in specialized cell types, RNA metabolism or DNA replication may be absent." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0016020	name: membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A lipid bilayer along with all the proteins and protein complexes embedded in it an attached to it." [GOC:dos, GOC:mah, ISBN:0815316194]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0034450	name: ubiquitin-ubiquitin ligase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Isoenergetic transfer of ubiquitin from one protein to an existing ubiquitin chain via the reaction X-ubiquitin + Y-ubiquitin -> Y-ubiquitin-ubiquitin + X, where both the X-ubiquitin and Y-ubiquitin-ubiquitin linkages are thioester bonds between the C-terminal glycine of ubiquitin and a sulfhydryl side group of a cysteine residue." [GOC:mah, GOC:mcc, PMID:10089879, PMID:17190603]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0005524	name: ATP binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with ATP, adenosine 5'-triphosphate, a universally important coenzyme and enzyme regulator." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0004674	name: protein serine/threonine kinase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reactions: ATP + protein serine = ADP + protein serine phosphate, and ATP + protein threonine = ADP + protein threonine phosphate." [GOC:bf]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0015074	name: DNA integration	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which a segment of DNA is incorporated into another, usually larger, DNA molecule such as a chromosome." [GOC:mah]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0006281	name: DNA repair	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process of restoring DNA after damage. Genomes are subject to damage by chemical and physical agents in the environment (e.g. UV and ionizing radiations, chemical mutagens, fungal and bacterial toxins, etc.) and by free radicals or alkylating agents endogenously generated in metabolism. DNA is also damaged because of errors during its replication. A variety of different DNA repair pathways have been reported that include direct reversal, base excision repair, nucleotide excision repair, photoreactivation, bypass, double-strand break repair pathway, and mismatch repair pathway." [PMID:11563486]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0000723	name: telomere maintenance	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that contributes to the maintenance of proper telomeric length and structure by affecting and monitoring the activity of telomeric proteins and the length of telomeric DNA. These processes includes those that shorten and lengthen the telomeric DNA sequences." [GOC:elh, PMID:11092831]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0003677	name: DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular function by which a gene product interacts selectively and non-covalently with DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid)." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:tb, GOC:vw]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0000786	name: nucleosome	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A complex comprised of DNA wound around a multisubunit core and associated proteins, which forms the primary packing unit of DNA into higher order structures." [GOC:elh]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0003678	name: DNA helicase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: NTP + H2O = NDP + phosphate, to drive the unwinding of a DNA helix." [GOC:jl, GOC:mah]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0016758	name: transferase activity, transferring hexosyl groups	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the transfer of a hexosyl group from one compound (donor) to another (acceptor)." [GOC:jl]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0006334	name: nucleosome assembly	namespace: biological_process	def: "The aggregation, arrangement and bonding together of a nucleosome, the beadlike structural units of eukaryotic chromatin composed of histones and DNA." [GOC:mah]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0000151	name: ubiquitin ligase complex	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A protein complex that includes a ubiquitin-protein ligase and enables ubiquitin protein ligase activity. The complex also contains other proteins that may confer substrate specificity on the complex." [GOC:jh2, PMID:9529603]	
EOG8CNT6C	GO:0003723	name: RNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an RNA molecule or a portion thereof." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8CNT6C	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8CNT6C	GO:0003676	name: nucleic acid binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any nucleic acid." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8CNT6C	GO:0004523	name: RNA-DNA hybrid ribonuclease activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the endonucleolytic cleavage of RNA in RNA-DNA hybrids to 5'-phosphomonoesters." [EC:3.1.26.4]	
EOG8CNT6C	GO:0005198	name: structural molecule activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "The action of a molecule that contributes to the structural integrity of a complex or assembly within or outside a cell." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8CNT6C	GO:0005882	name: intermediate filament	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A cytoskeletal structure that forms a distinct elongated structure, characteristically 10 nm in diameter, that occurs in the cytoplasm of eukaryotic cells. Intermediate filaments form a fibrous system, composed of chemically heterogeneous subunits and involved in mechanically integrating the various components of the cytoplasmic space. Intermediate filaments may be divided into five chemically distinct classes: Type I, acidic keratins; Type II, basic keratins; Type III, including desmin, vimentin and others; Type IV, neurofilaments and related filaments; and Type V, lamins." [http://www.cytochemistry.net/Cell-biology/intermediate_filaments.htm, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8CNT6C	GO:0004519	name: endonuclease activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of ester linkages within nucleic acids by creating internal breaks." [GOC:mah, ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG8CNT6C	GO:0003677	name: DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular function by which a gene product interacts selectively and non-covalently with DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid)." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:tb, GOC:vw]	
EOG8CNT6C	GO:0046872	name: metal ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any metal ion." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8CNT6C	GO:0015074	name: DNA integration	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which a segment of DNA is incorporated into another, usually larger, DNA molecule such as a chromosome." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8CNT6C	GO:0016021	name: integral component of membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The component of a membrane consisting of the gene products and protein complexes having at least some part of their peptide sequence embedded in the hydrophobic region of the membrane." [GOC:dos, GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8CNT6C	GO:0004871	name: signal transducer activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Conveys a signal across a cell to trigger a change in cell function or state. A signal is a physical entity or change in state that is used to transfer information in order to trigger a response." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8CNT6C	GO:0000166	name: nucleotide binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with a nucleotide, any compound consisting of a nucleoside that is esterified with (ortho)phosphate or an oligophosphate at any hydroxyl group on the ribose or deoxyribose." [GOC:mah, ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG8CNT6C	GO:0006310	name: DNA recombination	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process in which a new genotype is formed by reassortment of genes resulting in gene combinations different from those that were present in the parents. In eukaryotes genetic recombination can occur by chromosome assortment, intrachromosomal recombination, or nonreciprocal interchromosomal recombination. Intrachromosomal recombination occurs by crossing over. In bacteria it may occur by genetic transformation, conjugation, transduction, or F-duction." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8CNT6C	GO:0004555	name: alpha,alpha-trehalase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: alpha,alpha-trehalose + H2O = 2 D-glucose." [EC:3.2.1.28]	
EOG8CNT6C	GO:0016874	name: ligase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the joining of two substances, or two groups within a single molecule, with the concomitant hydrolysis of the diphosphate bond in ATP or a similar triphosphate." [EC:6, GOC:mah]	
EOG8CNT6C	GO:0005991	name: trehalose metabolic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways involving trehalose, a disaccharide isomeric with sucrose and obtained from certain lichens and fungi." [GOC:jl, ISBN:0028623819]	
EOG8CNT6C	GO:0016881	name: acid-amino acid ligase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the ligation of an acid to an amino acid via a carbon-nitrogen bond, with the concomitant hydrolysis of the diphosphate bond in ATP or a similar triphosphate." [GOC:jl, GOC:mah]	
EOG8CNT6C	GO:0016020	name: membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A lipid bilayer along with all the proteins and protein complexes embedded in it an attached to it." [GOC:dos, GOC:mah, ISBN:0815316194]	
EOG8CNT6C	GO:0005549	name: odorant binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an odorant, any substance capable of stimulating the sense of smell." [GOC:jl, ISBN:0721662544]	
EOG8CNT6C	GO:0005622	name: intracellular	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The living contents of a cell; the matter contained within (but not including) the plasma membrane, usually taken to exclude large vacuoles and masses of secretory or ingested material. In eukaryotes it includes the nucleus and cytoplasm." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8CNT6C	GO:0005215	name: transporter activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Enables the directed movement of substances (such as macromolecules, small molecules, ions) into, out of or within a cell, or between cells." [GOC:ai, GOC:dgf]	
EOG8CNT6C	GO:0080019	name: fatty-acyl-CoA reductase (alcohol-forming) activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: a very long chain fatty acyl-CoA + NADPH + H+ = a very long chain primary alcohol + NADP+ + CoA." [PMID:16980563]	
EOG8CNT6C	GO:0003887	name: DNA-directed DNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: deoxynucleoside triphosphate + DNA(n) = diphosphate + DNA(n+1); the synthesis of DNA from deoxyribonucleotide triphosphates in the presence of a DNA template and a 3'hydroxyl group." [EC:2.7.7.7, GOC:vw, ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG8CNT6C	GO:0016787	name: hydrolase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of various bonds, e.g. C-O, C-N, C-C, phosphoric anhydride bonds, etc. Hydrolase is the systematic name for any enzyme of EC class 3." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8CNT6C	GO:0022857	name: transmembrane transporter activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Enables the transfer of a substance from one side of a membrane to the other." [GOC:mtg_transport, ISBN:0815340729]	
EOG8CNT6C	GO:0004984	name: olfactory receptor activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Combining with an odorant and transmitting the signal from one side of the membrane to the other to initiate a change in cell activity in response to detection of smell." [GOC:bf, GOC:dph, GOC:sart, PMID:19135896, PMID:21041441]	
EOG8WDGTK	GO:0019028	name: viral capsid	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The protein coat that surrounds the infective nucleic acid in some virus particles. It comprises numerous regularly arranged subunits, or capsomeres." [GOC:mtg_sensu, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG80P6ND	GO:0022891	name: substrate-specific transmembrane transporter activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Enables the transfer of a specific substance or group of related substances from one side of a membrane to the other." [GOC:jid, GOC:mtg_transport, ISBN:0815340729]	
EOG80P6ND	GO:0022857	name: transmembrane transporter activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Enables the transfer of a substance from one side of a membrane to the other." [GOC:mtg_transport, ISBN:0815340729]	
EOG80P6ND	GO:0008643	name: carbohydrate transport	namespace: biological_process	def: "The directed movement of carbohydrate into, out of or within a cell, or between cells, by means of some agent such as a transporter or pore. Carbohydrates are any of a group of organic compounds based of the general formula Cx(H2O)y." [GOC:ai]	
EOG80P6ND	GO:0005886	name: plasma membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The membrane surrounding a cell that separates the cell from its external environment. It consists of a phospholipid bilayer and associated proteins." [ISBN:0716731363]	
EOG80P6ND	GO:0015771	name: trehalose transport	namespace: biological_process	def: "The directed movement of trehalose into, out of or within a cell, or between cells, by means of some agent such as a transporter or pore. Trehalose is a disaccharide isomeric with sucrose and obtained from certain lichens and fungi." [GOC:ai]	
EOG80P6ND	GO:0015574	name: trehalose transmembrane transporter activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Enables the transfer of trehalose from one side of the membrane to the other. Trehalose is the disaccharide alpha-D-glucopyranosyl-alpha-D-glucopyranoside that acts of a reserve carbohydrate in certain fungi, algae and lichens." [GOC:mtg_transport, ISBN:0198506732, ISBN:0815340729]	
EOG80P6ND	GO:0032440	name: 2-alkenal reductase [NAD(P)] activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: n-alkanal + NAD(P)+ = alk-2-enal + NAD(P)H + H+." [EC:1.3.1.74, PMID:16299173]	
EOG80P6ND	GO:0016020	name: membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A lipid bilayer along with all the proteins and protein complexes embedded in it an attached to it." [GOC:dos, GOC:mah, ISBN:0815316194]	
EOG80P6ND	GO:0046427	name: positive regulation of JAK-STAT cascade	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that activates or increases the frequency, rate or extent of the JAK-STAT signaling pathway activity." [GOC:bf]	
EOG83R628	GO:0005634	name: nucleus	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A membrane-bounded organelle of eukaryotic cells in which chromosomes are housed and replicated. In most cells, the nucleus contains all of the cell's chromosomes except the organellar chromosomes, and is the site of RNA synthesis and processing. In some species, or in specialized cell types, RNA metabolism or DNA replication may be absent." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG83R628	GO:0046872	name: metal ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any metal ion." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8CRPGZ	GO:0006351	name: transcription, DNA-templated	namespace: biological_process	def: "The cellular synthesis of RNA on a template of DNA." [GOC:jl, GOC:txnOH]	
EOG8CRPGZ	GO:0003899	name: DNA-directed RNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: nucleoside triphosphate + RNA(n) = diphosphate + RNA(n+1). Utilizes a DNA template, i.e. the catalysis of DNA-template-directed extension of the 3'-end of an RNA strand by one nucleotide at a time. Can initiate a chain 'de novo'." [EC:2.7.7.6]	
EOG8CRPGZ	GO:0003676	name: nucleic acid binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any nucleic acid." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8Q87B6	GO:0046872	name: metal ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any metal ion." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8Q87B6	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8Q87B6	GO:0005634	name: nucleus	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A membrane-bounded organelle of eukaryotic cells in which chromosomes are housed and replicated. In most cells, the nucleus contains all of the cell's chromosomes except the organellar chromosomes, and is the site of RNA synthesis and processing. In some species, or in specialized cell types, RNA metabolism or DNA replication may be absent." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8Q87B6	GO:0005198	name: structural molecule activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "The action of a molecule that contributes to the structural integrity of a complex or assembly within or outside a cell." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8Q87B6	GO:0019953	name: sexual reproduction	namespace: biological_process	def: "A reproduction process that creates a new organism by combining the genetic material of two organisms. It occurs both in eukaryotes and prokaryotes: in multicellular eukaryotic organisms, an individual is created anew; in prokaryotes, the initial cell has additional or transformed genetic material. In a process called genetic recombination, genetic material (DNA) originating from two different individuals (parents) join up so that homologous sequences are aligned with each other, and this is followed by exchange of genetic information. After the new recombinant chromosome is formed, it is passed on to progeny." [GOC:jl, http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sexual_reproduction, ISBN:0387520546]	
EOG8Q87B6	GO:0030141	name: secretory granule	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A small subcellular vesicle, surrounded by a membrane, that is formed from the Golgi apparatus and contains a highly concentrated protein destined for secretion. Secretory granules move towards the periphery of the cell and upon stimulation, their membranes fuse with the cell membrane, and their protein load is exteriorized. Processing of the contained protein may take place in secretory granules." [GOC:mah, ISBN:0198596732]	
EOG8Q87B6	GO:0005576	name: extracellular region	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The space external to the outermost structure of a cell. For cells without external protective or external encapsulating structures this refers to space outside of the plasma membrane. This term covers the host cell environment outside an intracellular parasite." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8KM1JP	GO:0000723	name: telomere maintenance	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that contributes to the maintenance of proper telomeric length and structure by affecting and monitoring the activity of telomeric proteins and the length of telomeric DNA. These processes includes those that shorten and lengthen the telomeric DNA sequences." [GOC:elh, PMID:11092831]	
EOG8KM1JP	GO:0003678	name: DNA helicase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: NTP + H2O = NDP + phosphate, to drive the unwinding of a DNA helix." [GOC:jl, GOC:mah]	
EOG80ZTCF	GO:0003887	name: DNA-directed DNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: deoxynucleoside triphosphate + DNA(n) = diphosphate + DNA(n+1); the synthesis of DNA from deoxyribonucleotide triphosphates in the presence of a DNA template and a 3'hydroxyl group." [EC:2.7.7.7, GOC:vw, ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG80ZTCF	GO:0000166	name: nucleotide binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with a nucleotide, any compound consisting of a nucleoside that is esterified with (ortho)phosphate or an oligophosphate at any hydroxyl group on the ribose or deoxyribose." [GOC:mah, ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG80ZTCF	GO:0046872	name: metal ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any metal ion." [GOC:ai]	
EOG80ZTCF	GO:0008408	name: 3'-5' exonuclease activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of ester linkages within nucleic acids by removing nucleotide residues from the 3' end." [GOC:ai]	
EOG80ZTCF	GO:0003677	name: DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular function by which a gene product interacts selectively and non-covalently with DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid)." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:tb, GOC:vw]	
EOG80ZTCF	GO:0009103	name: lipopolysaccharide biosynthetic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways resulting in the formation of lipopolysaccharides, any of a group of related, structurally complex components of the outer membrane of Gram-negative bacteria." [GOC:ai, GOC:mr]	
EOG80ZTCF	GO:0006353	name: DNA-templated transcription, termination	namespace: biological_process	def: "The cellular process that completes DNA-templated transcription; the formation of phosphodiester bonds ceases, the RNA-DNA hybrid dissociates, and RNA polymerase releases the DNA." [GOC:txnOH, ISBN:0716720094, PMID:15020047, PMID:18280161]	
EOG83R62Q	GO:0005622	name: intracellular	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The living contents of a cell; the matter contained within (but not including) the plasma membrane, usually taken to exclude large vacuoles and masses of secretory or ingested material. In eukaryotes it includes the nucleus and cytoplasm." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG83R62Q	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG83R62Q	GO:0046872	name: metal ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any metal ion." [GOC:ai]	
EOG83R62Q	GO:0003964	name: RNA-directed DNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: deoxynucleoside triphosphate + DNA(n) = diphosphate + DNA(n+1). Catalyzes RNA-template-directed extension of the 3'- end of a DNA strand by one deoxynucleotide at a time." [EC:2.7.7.49]	
EOG83R62Q	GO:0003723	name: RNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an RNA molecule or a portion thereof." [GOC:mah]	
EOG83R62Q	GO:0042981	name: regulation of apoptotic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that modulates the occurrence or rate of cell death by apoptotic process." [GOC:jl, GOC:mtg_apoptosis]	
EOG8323CZ	GO:0003676	name: nucleic acid binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any nucleic acid." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8323CZ	GO:0046872	name: metal ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any metal ion." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8FJBR5	GO:0003677	name: DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular function by which a gene product interacts selectively and non-covalently with DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid)." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:tb, GOC:vw]	
EOG8GB9MZ	GO:0008812	name: choline dehydrogenase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: A + choline = AH(2) + betaine aldehyde." [EC:1.1.99.1, RHEA:17436]	
EOG8GB9MZ	GO:0006066	name: alcohol metabolic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways involving alcohols, any of a class of compounds containing one or more hydroxyl groups attached to a saturated carbon atom." [CHEBI:30879, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8GB9MZ	GO:0016614	name: oxidoreductase activity, acting on CH-OH group of donors	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of an oxidation-reduction (redox) reaction in which a CH-OH group act as a hydrogen or electron donor and reduces a hydrogen or electron acceptor." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8GB9MZ	GO:0004198	name: calcium-dependent cysteine-type endopeptidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of nonterminal peptide bonds in a polypeptide chain by a mechanism using a cysteine residue at the enzyme active center, and requiring the presence of calcium." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8GB9MZ	GO:0005622	name: intracellular	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The living contents of a cell; the matter contained within (but not including) the plasma membrane, usually taken to exclude large vacuoles and masses of secretory or ingested material. In eukaryotes it includes the nucleus and cytoplasm." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8GB9MZ	GO:0004344	name: glucose dehydrogenase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: D-glucose + acceptor = D-glucono-1,5-lactone + reduced acceptor." [EC:1.1.99.10]	
EOG8GB9MZ	GO:0005509	name: calcium ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with calcium ions (Ca2+)." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8GB9MZ	GO:0016491	name: oxidoreductase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of an oxidation-reduction (redox) reaction, a reversible chemical reaction in which the oxidation state of an atom or atoms within a molecule is altered. One substrate acts as a hydrogen or electron donor and becomes oxidized, while the other acts as hydrogen or electron acceptor and becomes reduced." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8GB9MZ	GO:0045455	name: ecdysteroid metabolic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways involving ecdysteroids, a group of polyhydroxylated ketosteroids ubiquitous in insects and other arthropods, in which they initiate post-embryonic development, including the metamorphosis of immature forms and the development of the reproductive system and the maturation of oocytes in adult females." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8GB9MZ	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8GB9MZ	GO:0006915	name: apoptotic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "A programmed cell death process which begins when a cell receives an internal (e.g. DNA damage) or external signal (e.g. an extracellular death ligand), and proceeds through a series of biochemical events (signaling pathway phase) which trigger an execution phase. The execution phase is the last step of an apoptotic process, and is typically characterized by rounding-up of the cell, retraction of pseudopodes, reduction of cellular volume (pyknosis), chromatin condensation, nuclear fragmentation (karyorrhexis), plasma membrane blebbing and fragmentation of the cell into apoptotic bodies. When the execution phase is completed, the cell has died." [GOC:cjm, GOC:dhl, GOC:ecd, GOC:go_curators, GOC:mtg_apoptosis, GOC:tb, ISBN:0198506732, PMID:18846107, PMID:21494263]	
EOG8GB9MZ	GO:0042600	name: chorion	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A protective, noncellular membrane that surrounds the eggs of various animals including insects and fish." [GOC:jl, ISBN:0721662544]	
EOG8GB9MZ	GO:0004190	name: aspartic-type endopeptidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of internal, alpha-peptide bonds in a polypeptide chain by a mechanism in which a water molecule bound by the side chains of aspartic residues at the active center acts as a nucleophile." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8GB9MZ	GO:0003676	name: nucleic acid binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any nucleic acid." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8GB9MZ	GO:0004197	name: cysteine-type endopeptidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of internal, alpha-peptide bonds in a polypeptide chain by a mechanism in which the sulfhydryl group of a cysteine residue at the active center acts as a nucleophile." [GOC:mah, http://merops.sanger.ac.uk/about/glossary.htm#CATTYPE, http://merops.sanger.ac.uk/about/glossary.htm#ENDOPEPTIDASE]	
EOG8GB9MZ	GO:0046331	name: lateral inhibition	namespace: biological_process	def: "Signaling between cells of equivalent developmental potential that results in these cells adopting different developmental fates. An example is the suppression by cells with a particular fate of the adoption of the same fate by surrounding cells." [GOC:bf, GOC:kmv]	
EOG8GB9MZ	GO:0015074	name: DNA integration	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which a segment of DNA is incorporated into another, usually larger, DNA molecule such as a chromosome." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8NCPTT	GO:0003677	name: DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular function by which a gene product interacts selectively and non-covalently with DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid)." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:tb, GOC:vw]	
EOG8NCPTT	GO:0003964	name: RNA-directed DNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: deoxynucleoside triphosphate + DNA(n) = diphosphate + DNA(n+1). Catalyzes RNA-template-directed extension of the 3'- end of a DNA strand by one deoxynucleotide at a time." [EC:2.7.7.49]	
EOG8NCPTT	GO:0003723	name: RNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an RNA molecule or a portion thereof." [GOC:mah]	
EOG880MB7	GO:0003964	name: RNA-directed DNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: deoxynucleoside triphosphate + DNA(n) = diphosphate + DNA(n+1). Catalyzes RNA-template-directed extension of the 3'- end of a DNA strand by one deoxynucleotide at a time." [EC:2.7.7.49]	
EOG880MB7	GO:0003723	name: RNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an RNA molecule or a portion thereof." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8616N8	GO:0003677	name: DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular function by which a gene product interacts selectively and non-covalently with DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid)." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:tb, GOC:vw]	
EOG8616N8	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8616N8	GO:0003964	name: RNA-directed DNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: deoxynucleoside triphosphate + DNA(n) = diphosphate + DNA(n+1). Catalyzes RNA-template-directed extension of the 3'- end of a DNA strand by one deoxynucleotide at a time." [EC:2.7.7.49]	
EOG8616N8	GO:0015074	name: DNA integration	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which a segment of DNA is incorporated into another, usually larger, DNA molecule such as a chromosome." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8616N8	GO:0003723	name: RNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an RNA molecule or a portion thereof." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8616N8	GO:0004190	name: aspartic-type endopeptidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of internal, alpha-peptide bonds in a polypeptide chain by a mechanism in which a water molecule bound by the side chains of aspartic residues at the active center acts as a nucleophile." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8616N8	GO:0008237	name: metallopeptidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of peptide bonds by a mechanism in which water acts as a nucleophile, one or two metal ions hold the water molecule in place, and charged amino acid side chains are ligands for the metal ions." [GOC:mah, http://merops.sanger.ac.uk/about/glossary.htm#CATTYPE]	
EOG8RZ1H0	GO:0008234	name: cysteine-type peptidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of peptide bonds in a polypeptide chain by a mechanism in which the sulfhydryl group of a cysteine residue at the active center acts as a nucleophile." [GOC:mah, http://merops.sanger.ac.uk/about/glossary.htm#CATTYPE]	
EOG8RZ1H0	GO:0003682	name: chromatin binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with chromatin, the network of fibers of DNA, protein, and sometimes RNA, that make up the chromosomes of the eukaryotic nucleus during interphase." [GOC:jl, ISBN:0198506732, PMID:20404130]	
EOG8HTC74	GO:0003723	name: RNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an RNA molecule or a portion thereof." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8HTC74	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8HTC74	GO:0035556	name: intracellular signal transduction	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which a signal is passed on to downstream components within the cell, which become activated themselves to further propagate the signal and finally trigger a change in the function or state of the cell." [GOC:bf, GOC:jl, GOC:signaling, ISBN:3527303782]	
EOG8HTC74	GO:0016787	name: hydrolase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of various bonds, e.g. C-O, C-N, C-C, phosphoric anhydride bonds, etc. Hydrolase is the systematic name for any enzyme of EC class 3." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8HTC74	GO:0000166	name: nucleotide binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with a nucleotide, any compound consisting of a nucleoside that is esterified with (ortho)phosphate or an oligophosphate at any hydroxyl group on the ribose or deoxyribose." [GOC:mah, ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG8HTC74	GO:0004519	name: endonuclease activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of ester linkages within nucleic acids by creating internal breaks." [GOC:mah, ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG8Z91BB	GO:0003676	name: nucleic acid binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any nucleic acid." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8Z91BB	GO:0003964	name: RNA-directed DNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: deoxynucleoside triphosphate + DNA(n) = diphosphate + DNA(n+1). Catalyzes RNA-template-directed extension of the 3'- end of a DNA strand by one deoxynucleotide at a time." [EC:2.7.7.49]	
EOG8Z91BB	GO:0003723	name: RNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an RNA molecule or a portion thereof." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8Z91BB	GO:0003677	name: DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular function by which a gene product interacts selectively and non-covalently with DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid)." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:tb, GOC:vw]	
EOG8Z91BB	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8Z91BB	GO:0004523	name: RNA-DNA hybrid ribonuclease activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the endonucleolytic cleavage of RNA in RNA-DNA hybrids to 5'-phosphomonoesters." [EC:3.1.26.4]	
EOG8Z91BB	GO:0005622	name: intracellular	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The living contents of a cell; the matter contained within (but not including) the plasma membrane, usually taken to exclude large vacuoles and masses of secretory or ingested material. In eukaryotes it includes the nucleus and cytoplasm." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8Z91BB	GO:0019028	name: viral capsid	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The protein coat that surrounds the infective nucleic acid in some virus particles. It comprises numerous regularly arranged subunits, or capsomeres." [GOC:mtg_sensu, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8Z91BB	GO:0046718	name: viral entry into host cell	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process that occurs after viral attachment by which a virus, or viral nucleic acid, breaches the plasma membrane or cell envelope and enters the host cell. The process ends when the viral nucleic acid is released into the host cell cytoplasm." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8Z91BB	GO:0019076	name: viral release from host cell	namespace: biological_process	def: "The dissemination of mature viral particles from the host cell, e.g. by cell lysis or the budding of virus particles from the cell membrane." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8Z91BB	GO:0006351	name: transcription, DNA-templated	namespace: biological_process	def: "The cellular synthesis of RNA on a template of DNA." [GOC:jl, GOC:txnOH]	
EOG8Z91BB	GO:0003899	name: DNA-directed RNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: nucleoside triphosphate + RNA(n) = diphosphate + RNA(n+1). Utilizes a DNA template, i.e. the catalysis of DNA-template-directed extension of the 3'-end of an RNA strand by one nucleotide at a time. Can initiate a chain 'de novo'." [EC:2.7.7.6]	
EOG8Z91BB	GO:0044163	name: host cytoskeleton	namespace: cellular_component	def: "Any of the various filamentous elements that form the internal framework of host cells, and typically remain after treatment of the cells with mild detergent to remove membrane constituents and soluble components of the host cytoplasm. The term embraces intermediate filaments, microfilaments, microtubules, the microtrabecular lattice, and other structures characterized by a polymeric filamentous nature and long-range order within the host cell. The various elements of the host cytoskeleton not only serve in the maintenance of host cellular shape but also have roles in other host cellular functions, including cellular movement, cell division, endocytosis, and movement of organelles." [GOC:rph]	
EOG8Z91BB	GO:0075521	name: microtubule-dependent intracellular transport of viral material towards nucleus	namespace: biological_process	def: "The directed movement of a virus, or part of a virus, towards the host cell nucleus using host microtubules." [UniProtKB-KW:KW-1177, VZ:983]	
EOG8Z91BB	GO:0042025	name: host cell nucleus	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A membrane-bounded organelle as it is found in the host cell in which chromosomes are housed and replicated. The host is defined as the larger of the organisms involved in a symbiotic interaction." [GOC:pamgo_curators]	
EOG8Z91BB	GO:0030430	name: host cell cytoplasm	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The cytoplasm of a host cell." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8Z91BB	GO:0004190	name: aspartic-type endopeptidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of internal, alpha-peptide bonds in a polypeptide chain by a mechanism in which a water molecule bound by the side chains of aspartic residues at the active center acts as a nucleophile." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8V9X72	GO:0003676	name: nucleic acid binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any nucleic acid." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8V9X72	GO:0003964	name: RNA-directed DNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: deoxynucleoside triphosphate + DNA(n) = diphosphate + DNA(n+1). Catalyzes RNA-template-directed extension of the 3'- end of a DNA strand by one deoxynucleotide at a time." [EC:2.7.7.49]	
EOG8V9X72	GO:0003723	name: RNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an RNA molecule or a portion thereof." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8V9X72	GO:0006811	name: ion transport	namespace: biological_process	def: "The directed movement of charged atoms or small charged molecules into, out of or within a cell, or between cells, by means of some agent such as a transporter or pore." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8V9X72	GO:0005921	name: gap junction	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A cell-cell junction that is composed of an array of small channels that permit small molecules to pass from one cell to another. At gap junctions, the membranes of two adjacent cells are separated by a uniform narrow gap of about 2-4 nm that is spanned by channel-forming proteins called connexins, which form hexagonal tubes called connexons." [GOC:mah, GOC:mtg_muscle, http://www.vivo.colostate.edu/hbooks/cmb/cells/pmemb/junctions_g.html, ISBN:0815332181]	
EOG8HB12K	GO:0003723	name: RNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an RNA molecule or a portion thereof." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8HB12K	GO:0003964	name: RNA-directed DNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: deoxynucleoside triphosphate + DNA(n) = diphosphate + DNA(n+1). Catalyzes RNA-template-directed extension of the 3'- end of a DNA strand by one deoxynucleotide at a time." [EC:2.7.7.49]	
EOG8HB12K	GO:0004842	name: ubiquitin-protein transferase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the transfer of ubiquitin from one protein to another via the reaction X-Ub + Y --> Y-Ub + X, where both X-Ub and Y-Ub are covalent linkages." [GOC:BioGRID, GOC:jh2, PMID:9635407]	
EOG805VHB	GO:0003676	name: nucleic acid binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any nucleic acid." [GOC:jl]	
EOG805VHB	GO:0004190	name: aspartic-type endopeptidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of internal, alpha-peptide bonds in a polypeptide chain by a mechanism in which a water molecule bound by the side chains of aspartic residues at the active center acts as a nucleophile." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG805VHB	GO:0003723	name: RNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an RNA molecule or a portion thereof." [GOC:mah]	
EOG805VHB	GO:0003964	name: RNA-directed DNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: deoxynucleoside triphosphate + DNA(n) = diphosphate + DNA(n+1). Catalyzes RNA-template-directed extension of the 3'- end of a DNA strand by one deoxynucleotide at a time." [EC:2.7.7.49]	
EOG8MKQW2	GO:0000166	name: nucleotide binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with a nucleotide, any compound consisting of a nucleoside that is esterified with (ortho)phosphate or an oligophosphate at any hydroxyl group on the ribose or deoxyribose." [GOC:mah, ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG8MKQW2	GO:0003677	name: DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular function by which a gene product interacts selectively and non-covalently with DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid)." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:tb, GOC:vw]	
EOG8MKQW2	GO:0006360	name: transcription from RNA polymerase I promoter	namespace: biological_process	def: "The synthesis of RNA from a DNA template by RNA polymerase I (RNAP I), originating at an RNAP I promoter." [GOC:jl, GOC:txnOH]	
EOG8MKQW2	GO:0042302	name: structural constituent of cuticle	namespace: molecular_function	def: "The action of a molecule that contributes to the structural integrity of a cuticle." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8MKQW2	GO:0005201	name: extracellular matrix structural constituent	namespace: molecular_function	def: "The action of a molecule that contributes to the structural integrity of the extracellular matrix." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8MKQW2	GO:0031012	name: extracellular matrix	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A structure lying external to one or more cells, which provides structural support for cells or tissues; may be completely external to the cell (as in animals and bacteria) or be part of the cell (as in plants)." [GOC:mah, NIF_Subcellular:nlx_subcell_20090513]	
EOG8MKQW2	GO:0000226	name: microtubule cytoskeleton organization	namespace: biological_process	def: "A process that is carried out at the cellular level which results in the assembly, arrangement of constituent parts, or disassembly of cytoskeletal structures comprising microtubules and their associated proteins." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8MKQW2	GO:0007304	name: chorion-containing eggshell formation	namespace: biological_process	def: "The construction of a chorion-containing eggshell. An example of this is found in Drosophila melanogaster." [GOC:mah, GOC:mtg_sensu]	
EOG8MKQW2	GO:0016787	name: hydrolase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of various bonds, e.g. C-O, C-N, C-C, phosphoric anhydride bonds, etc. Hydrolase is the systematic name for any enzyme of EC class 3." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8MKQW2	GO:0022008	name: neurogenesis	namespace: biological_process	def: "Generation of cells within the nervous system." [GO_REF:0000021, GOC:cls, GOC:curators, GOC:dgh, GOC:dph, GOC:jid, GOC:mtg_15jun06]	
EOG8MKQW2	GO:0005736	name: DNA-directed RNA polymerase I complex	namespace: cellular_component	def: "RNA polymerase I, one of three nuclear DNA-directed RNA polymerases found in all eukaryotes, is a multisubunit complex; typically it produces rRNAs. Two large subunits comprise the most conserved portion including the catalytic site and share similarity with other eukaryotic and bacterial multisubunit RNA polymerases. The remainder of the complex is composed of smaller subunits (generally ten or more), some of which are also found in RNA polymerase III and others of which are also found in RNA polymerases II and III. Although the core is competent to mediate ribonucleic acid synthesis, it requires additional factors to select the appropriate template." [GOC:krc, GOC:mtg_sensu]	
EOG8MKQW2	GO:0042600	name: chorion	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A protective, noncellular membrane that surrounds the eggs of various animals including insects and fish." [GOC:jl, ISBN:0721662544]	
EOG8MKQW2	GO:0005874	name: microtubule	namespace: cellular_component	def: "Any of the long, generally straight, hollow tubes of internal diameter 12-15 nm and external diameter 24 nm found in a wide variety of eukaryotic cells; each consists (usually) of 13 protofilaments of polymeric tubulin, staggered in such a manner that the tubulin monomers are arranged in a helical pattern on the microtubular surface, and with the alpha/beta axes of the tubulin subunits parallel to the long axis of the tubule; exist in equilibrium with pool of tubulin monomers and can be rapidly assembled or disassembled in response to physiological stimuli; concerned with force generation, e.g. in the spindle." [ISBN:0879693568]	
EOG8ZGRV6	GO:0004519	name: endonuclease activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of ester linkages within nucleic acids by creating internal breaks." [GOC:mah, ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG8ZGRV6	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8FJBS3	GO:0003964	name: RNA-directed DNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: deoxynucleoside triphosphate + DNA(n) = diphosphate + DNA(n+1). Catalyzes RNA-template-directed extension of the 3'- end of a DNA strand by one deoxynucleotide at a time." [EC:2.7.7.49]	
EOG8FJBS3	GO:0004523	name: RNA-DNA hybrid ribonuclease activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the endonucleolytic cleavage of RNA in RNA-DNA hybrids to 5'-phosphomonoesters." [EC:3.1.26.4]	
EOG8FJBS3	GO:0003723	name: RNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an RNA molecule or a portion thereof." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8FJBS3	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8FJBS3	GO:0004519	name: endonuclease activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of ester linkages within nucleic acids by creating internal breaks." [GOC:mah, ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG8FJBS3	GO:0004842	name: ubiquitin-protein transferase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the transfer of ubiquitin from one protein to another via the reaction X-Ub + Y --> Y-Ub + X, where both X-Ub and Y-Ub are covalent linkages." [GOC:BioGRID, GOC:jh2, PMID:9635407]	
EOG8W6RD1	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8W6RD1	GO:0003677	name: DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular function by which a gene product interacts selectively and non-covalently with DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid)." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:tb, GOC:vw]	
EOG8W6RD1	GO:0004523	name: RNA-DNA hybrid ribonuclease activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the endonucleolytic cleavage of RNA in RNA-DNA hybrids to 5'-phosphomonoesters." [EC:3.1.26.4]	
EOG8W6RD1	GO:0003964	name: RNA-directed DNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: deoxynucleoside triphosphate + DNA(n) = diphosphate + DNA(n+1). Catalyzes RNA-template-directed extension of the 3'- end of a DNA strand by one deoxynucleotide at a time." [EC:2.7.7.49]	
EOG8W6RD1	GO:0003723	name: RNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an RNA molecule or a portion thereof." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8XH2GQ	GO:0031012	name: extracellular matrix	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A structure lying external to one or more cells, which provides structural support for cells or tissues; may be completely external to the cell (as in animals and bacteria) or be part of the cell (as in plants)." [GOC:mah, NIF_Subcellular:nlx_subcell_20090513]	
EOG8XH2GQ	GO:0040003	name: chitin-based cuticle development	namespace: biological_process	def: "Synthesis and deposition of a chitin-based noncellular, hardened, or membranous secretion from an epithelial sheet. An example of this process is found in Drosophila melanogaster." [GOC:mtg_sensu]	
EOG8XH2GQ	GO:0008010	name: structural constituent of chitin-based larval cuticle	namespace: molecular_function	def: "The action of a molecule that contributes to the structural integrity of the chitin-based cuticle of a larva. An example of this is found in Drosophila melanogaster." [GOC:mah, GOC:mtg_sensu]	
EOG8XH2GQ	GO:0022008	name: neurogenesis	namespace: biological_process	def: "Generation of cells within the nervous system." [GO_REF:0000021, GOC:cls, GOC:curators, GOC:dgh, GOC:dph, GOC:jid, GOC:mtg_15jun06]	
EOG8XH2GQ	GO:0008011	name: structural constituent of pupal chitin-based cuticle	namespace: molecular_function	def: "The action of a molecule that contributes to the structural integrity of the chitin-based cuticle of a pupa. An example of this is found in Drosophila melanogaster." [GOC:mah, GOC:mtg_sensu]	
EOG8XH2GQ	GO:0032504	name: multicellular organism reproduction	namespace: biological_process	def: "The biological process in which new individuals are produced by one or two multicellular organisms. The new individuals inherit some proportion of their genetic material from the parent or parents." [GOC:isa_complete, GOC:jid]	
EOG8XH2GQ	GO:0048058	name: compound eye corneal lens development	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process whose specific outcome is the progression of the corneal lens in the compound eye over time, from its formation to the mature structure. The corneal lens is a chitinous extracellular secretion of the four underlying cone cells and the pigment cells." [GOC:jid]	
EOG8XH2GQ	GO:0005615	name: extracellular space	namespace: cellular_component	def: "That part of a multicellular organism outside the cells proper, usually taken to be outside the plasma membranes, and occupied by fluid." [ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG8XH2GQ	GO:0005212	name: structural constituent of eye lens	namespace: molecular_function	def: "The action of a molecule that contributes to the structural integrity of the lens of an eye." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8XH2GQ	GO:0005576	name: extracellular region	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The space external to the outermost structure of a cell. For cells without external protective or external encapsulating structures this refers to space outside of the plasma membrane. This term covers the host cell environment outside an intracellular parasite." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8XH2GQ	GO:0005509	name: calcium ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with calcium ions (Ca2+)." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8XH2GQ	GO:0007601	name: visual perception	namespace: biological_process	def: "The series of events required for an organism to receive a visual stimulus, convert it to a molecular signal, and recognize and characterize the signal. Visual stimuli are detected in the form of photons and are processed to form an image." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8XH2GQ	GO:0003824	name: catalytic activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of a biochemical reaction at physiological temperatures. In biologically catalyzed reactions, the reactants are known as substrates, and the catalysts are naturally occurring macromolecular substances known as enzymes. Enzymes possess specific binding sites for substrates, and are usually composed wholly or largely of protein, but RNA that has catalytic activity (ribozyme) is often also regarded as enzymatic." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8XH2GQ	GO:0005811	name: lipid particle	namespace: cellular_component	def: "An intracellular non-membrane-bounded organelle comprising a matrix of coalesced lipids surrounded by a phospholipid monolayer. May include associated proteins." [GOC:mah, GOC:tb]	
EOG88GZJ7	GO:0003677	name: DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular function by which a gene product interacts selectively and non-covalently with DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid)." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:tb, GOC:vw]	
EOG88GZJ7	GO:0003899	name: DNA-directed RNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: nucleoside triphosphate + RNA(n) = diphosphate + RNA(n+1). Utilizes a DNA template, i.e. the catalysis of DNA-template-directed extension of the 3'-end of an RNA strand by one nucleotide at a time. Can initiate a chain 'de novo'." [EC:2.7.7.6]	
EOG88GZJ7	GO:0006351	name: transcription, DNA-templated	namespace: biological_process	def: "The cellular synthesis of RNA on a template of DNA." [GOC:jl, GOC:txnOH]	
