EOG8CJZ12	GO:0003676	name: nucleic acid binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any nucleic acid." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8CJZ12	GO:0003964	name: RNA-directed DNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: deoxynucleoside triphosphate + DNA(n) = diphosphate + DNA(n+1). Catalyzes RNA-template-directed extension of the 3'- end of a DNA strand by one deoxynucleotide at a time." [EC:2.7.7.49]	
EOG8CJZ12	GO:0004190	name: aspartic-type endopeptidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of internal, alpha-peptide bonds in a polypeptide chain by a mechanism in which a water molecule bound by the side chains of aspartic residues at the active center acts as a nucleophile." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8CJZ12	GO:0003723	name: RNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an RNA molecule or a portion thereof." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8QNQ9Z	GO:0007605	name: sensory perception of sound	namespace: biological_process	def: "The series of events required for an organism to receive an auditory stimulus, convert it to a molecular signal, and recognize and characterize the signal. Sonic stimuli are detected in the form of vibrations and are processed to form a sound." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8QNQ9Z	GO:0016059	name: deactivation of rhodopsin mediated signaling	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process of restoring the photoreceptor cell to its unexcited state after termination of the stimulus (photon)." [PMID:8316831]	
EOG8X3KHJ	GO:0003676	name: nucleic acid binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any nucleic acid." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8X3KHJ	GO:0003964	name: RNA-directed DNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: deoxynucleoside triphosphate + DNA(n) = diphosphate + DNA(n+1). Catalyzes RNA-template-directed extension of the 3'- end of a DNA strand by one deoxynucleotide at a time." [EC:2.7.7.49]	
EOG8X3KHJ	GO:0003723	name: RNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an RNA molecule or a portion thereof." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8X3KHJ	GO:0003677	name: DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular function by which a gene product interacts selectively and non-covalently with DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid)." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:tb, GOC:vw]	
EOG8X3KHJ	GO:0016192	name: vesicle-mediated transport	namespace: biological_process	def: "A cellular transport process in which transported substances are moved in membrane-bounded vesicles; transported substances are enclosed in the vesicle lumen or located in the vesicle membrane. The process begins with a step that directs a substance to the forming vesicle, and includes vesicle budding and coating. Vesicles are then targeted to, and fuse with, an acceptor membrane." [GOC:ai, GOC:mah, ISBN:08789310662000]	
EOG8X3KHJ	GO:0015074	name: DNA integration	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which a segment of DNA is incorporated into another, usually larger, DNA molecule such as a chromosome." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8X3KHJ	GO:0016020	name: membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A lipid bilayer along with all the proteins and protein complexes embedded in it an attached to it." [GOC:dos, GOC:mah, ISBN:0815316194]	
EOG8HDW95	GO:0016491	name: oxidoreductase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of an oxidation-reduction (redox) reaction, a reversible chemical reaction in which the oxidation state of an atom or atoms within a molecule is altered. One substrate acts as a hydrogen or electron donor and becomes oxidized, while the other acts as hydrogen or electron acceptor and becomes reduced." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8HDW95	GO:0052854	name: medium-chain-(S)-2-hydroxy-acid oxidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: medium-chain-(S)-2-hydroxy-acid + O2 = medium-chain-2-oxo acid + hydrogen peroxide. Medium chain refers to a chain length of between 8 and 12 carbons." [EC:1.1.3.15]	
EOG8HDW95	GO:0052853	name: long-chain-(S)-2-hydroxy-long-chain-acid oxidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: long-chain-(S)-2-hydroxy-acid + O2 = long-chain-2-oxo acid + hydrogen peroxide. Long chain refers to a chain length of 14 to 18 carbons." [EC:1.1.3.15]	
EOG8HDW95	GO:0052852	name: very-long-chain-(S)-2-hydroxy-acid oxidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: very-long-chain (S)-2-hydroxy-acid + O2 = very-long-chain 2-oxo acid + hydrogen peroxide. Very long chain refers to a chain length of greater than 18 carbons." [EC:1.1.3.15]	
EOG8HDW95	GO:0005777	name: peroxisome	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A small organelle enclosed by a single membrane, and found in most eukaryotic cells. Contains peroxidases and other enzymes involved in a variety of metabolic processes including free radical detoxification, lipid catabolism and biosynthesis, and hydrogen peroxide metabolism." [GOC:pm, PMID:9302272, UniProtKB-KW:KW-0576]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0003723	name: RNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an RNA molecule or a portion thereof." [GOC:mah]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0003676	name: nucleic acid binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any nucleic acid." [GOC:jl]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0004519	name: endonuclease activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of ester linkages within nucleic acids by creating internal breaks." [GOC:mah, ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0004523	name: RNA-DNA hybrid ribonuclease activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the endonucleolytic cleavage of RNA in RNA-DNA hybrids to 5'-phosphomonoesters." [EC:3.1.26.4]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0006511	name: ubiquitin-dependent protein catabolic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways resulting in the breakdown of a protein or peptide by hydrolysis of its peptide bonds, initiated by the covalent attachment of a ubiquitin group, or multiple ubiquitin groups, to the protein." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0046872	name: metal ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any metal ion." [GOC:ai]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0005634	name: nucleus	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A membrane-bounded organelle of eukaryotic cells in which chromosomes are housed and replicated. In most cells, the nucleus contains all of the cell's chromosomes except the organellar chromosomes, and is the site of RNA synthesis and processing. In some species, or in specialized cell types, RNA metabolism or DNA replication may be absent." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0016020	name: membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A lipid bilayer along with all the proteins and protein complexes embedded in it an attached to it." [GOC:dos, GOC:mah, ISBN:0815316194]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0034450	name: ubiquitin-ubiquitin ligase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Isoenergetic transfer of ubiquitin from one protein to an existing ubiquitin chain via the reaction X-ubiquitin + Y-ubiquitin -> Y-ubiquitin-ubiquitin + X, where both the X-ubiquitin and Y-ubiquitin-ubiquitin linkages are thioester bonds between the C-terminal glycine of ubiquitin and a sulfhydryl side group of a cysteine residue." [GOC:mah, GOC:mcc, PMID:10089879, PMID:17190603]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0005524	name: ATP binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with ATP, adenosine 5'-triphosphate, a universally important coenzyme and enzyme regulator." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0004674	name: protein serine/threonine kinase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reactions: ATP + protein serine = ADP + protein serine phosphate, and ATP + protein threonine = ADP + protein threonine phosphate." [GOC:bf]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0015074	name: DNA integration	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which a segment of DNA is incorporated into another, usually larger, DNA molecule such as a chromosome." [GOC:mah]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0006281	name: DNA repair	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process of restoring DNA after damage. Genomes are subject to damage by chemical and physical agents in the environment (e.g. UV and ionizing radiations, chemical mutagens, fungal and bacterial toxins, etc.) and by free radicals or alkylating agents endogenously generated in metabolism. DNA is also damaged because of errors during its replication. A variety of different DNA repair pathways have been reported that include direct reversal, base excision repair, nucleotide excision repair, photoreactivation, bypass, double-strand break repair pathway, and mismatch repair pathway." [PMID:11563486]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0000723	name: telomere maintenance	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that contributes to the maintenance of proper telomeric length and structure by affecting and monitoring the activity of telomeric proteins and the length of telomeric DNA. These processes includes those that shorten and lengthen the telomeric DNA sequences." [GOC:elh, PMID:11092831]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0003677	name: DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular function by which a gene product interacts selectively and non-covalently with DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid)." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:tb, GOC:vw]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0000786	name: nucleosome	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A complex comprised of DNA wound around a multisubunit core and associated proteins, which forms the primary packing unit of DNA into higher order structures." [GOC:elh]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0003678	name: DNA helicase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: NTP + H2O = NDP + phosphate, to drive the unwinding of a DNA helix." [GOC:jl, GOC:mah]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0016758	name: transferase activity, transferring hexosyl groups	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the transfer of a hexosyl group from one compound (donor) to another (acceptor)." [GOC:jl]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0006334	name: nucleosome assembly	namespace: biological_process	def: "The aggregation, arrangement and bonding together of a nucleosome, the beadlike structural units of eukaryotic chromatin composed of histones and DNA." [GOC:mah]	
EOG883GNT	GO:0000151	name: ubiquitin ligase complex	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A protein complex that includes a ubiquitin-protein ligase and enables ubiquitin protein ligase activity. The complex also contains other proteins that may confer substrate specificity on the complex." [GOC:jh2, PMID:9529603]	
EOG8FJBPS	GO:0003676	name: nucleic acid binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any nucleic acid." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8QNQD6	GO:0003676	name: nucleic acid binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any nucleic acid." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8QNQD6	GO:0003964	name: RNA-directed DNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: deoxynucleoside triphosphate + DNA(n) = diphosphate + DNA(n+1). Catalyzes RNA-template-directed extension of the 3'- end of a DNA strand by one deoxynucleotide at a time." [EC:2.7.7.49]	
EOG8QNQD6	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8QNQD6	GO:0003723	name: RNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an RNA molecule or a portion thereof." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8QNQD6	GO:0015074	name: DNA integration	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which a segment of DNA is incorporated into another, usually larger, DNA molecule such as a chromosome." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8CG2R8	GO:0015074	name: DNA integration	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which a segment of DNA is incorporated into another, usually larger, DNA molecule such as a chromosome." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8CG2R8	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8CG2R8	GO:0003723	name: RNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an RNA molecule or a portion thereof." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8CG2R8	GO:0003964	name: RNA-directed DNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: deoxynucleoside triphosphate + DNA(n) = diphosphate + DNA(n+1). Catalyzes RNA-template-directed extension of the 3'- end of a DNA strand by one deoxynucleotide at a time." [EC:2.7.7.49]	
EOG8CG2R8	GO:0004190	name: aspartic-type endopeptidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of internal, alpha-peptide bonds in a polypeptide chain by a mechanism in which a water molecule bound by the side chains of aspartic residues at the active center acts as a nucleophile." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8CG2R8	GO:0005634	name: nucleus	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A membrane-bounded organelle of eukaryotic cells in which chromosomes are housed and replicated. In most cells, the nucleus contains all of the cell's chromosomes except the organellar chromosomes, and is the site of RNA synthesis and processing. In some species, or in specialized cell types, RNA metabolism or DNA replication may be absent." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8CG2R8	GO:0005509	name: calcium ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with calcium ions (Ca2+)." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8CG2R8	GO:0003677	name: DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular function by which a gene product interacts selectively and non-covalently with DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid)." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:tb, GOC:vw]	
EOG8CG2R8	GO:0016021	name: integral component of membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The component of a membrane consisting of the gene products and protein complexes having at least some part of their peptide sequence embedded in the hydrophobic region of the membrane." [GOC:dos, GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8CG2R8	GO:0007166	name: cell surface receptor signaling pathway	namespace: biological_process	def: "A series of molecular signals initiated by activation of a receptor on the surface of a cell. The pathway begins with binding of an extracellular ligand to a cell surface receptor, or for receptors that signal in the absence of a ligand, by ligand-withdrawal or the activity of a constitutively active receptor. The pathway ends with regulation of a downstream cellular process, e.g. transcription." [GOC:bf, GOC:mah, GOC:pr, GOC:signaling]	
EOG8CG2R8	GO:0004842	name: ubiquitin-protein transferase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the transfer of ubiquitin from one protein to another via the reaction X-Ub + Y --> Y-Ub + X, where both X-Ub and Y-Ub are covalent linkages." [GOC:BioGRID, GOC:jh2, PMID:9635407]	
EOG8CG2R8	GO:0023051	name: regulation of signaling	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that modulates the frequency, rate or extent of a signaling process." [GOC:mtg_signal]	
EOG8CG2R8	GO:0046872	name: metal ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any metal ion." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8CG2R8	GO:0004871	name: signal transducer activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Conveys a signal across a cell to trigger a change in cell function or state. A signal is a physical entity or change in state that is used to transfer information in order to trigger a response." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8CG2R8	GO:0003700	name: transcription factor activity, sequence-specific DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with a specific DNA sequence in order to modulate transcription. The transcription factor may or may not also interact selectively with a protein or macromolecular complex." [GOC:curators, GOC:txnOH]	
EOG8CG2R8	GO:0016620	name: oxidoreductase activity, acting on the aldehyde or oxo group of donors, NAD or NADP as acceptor	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of an oxidation-reduction (redox) reaction in which an aldehyde or ketone (oxo) group acts as a hydrogen or electron donor and reduces NAD or NADP." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8CG2R8	GO:0004527	name: exonuclease activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of ester linkages within nucleic acids by removing nucleotide residues from the 3' or 5' end." [GOC:mah, ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG8CG2R8	GO:0005524	name: ATP binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with ATP, adenosine 5'-triphosphate, a universally important coenzyme and enzyme regulator." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8CG2R8	GO:0055085	name: transmembrane transport	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which a solute is transported across a lipid bilayer, from one side of a membrane to the other" [GOC:dph, GOC:jid]	
EOG8CG2R8	GO:0043565	name: sequence-specific DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with DNA of a specific nucleotide composition, e.g. GC-rich DNA binding, or with a specific sequence motif or type of DNA e.g. promotor binding or rDNA binding." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8CG2R8	GO:0004518	name: nuclease activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of ester linkages within nucleic acids." [ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG8CG2R8	GO:0004672	name: protein kinase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the phosphorylation of an amino acid residue in a protein, usually according to the reaction: a protein + ATP = a phosphoprotein + ADP." [MetaCyc:PROTEIN-KINASE-RXN]	
EOG8CG2R8	GO:0004725	name: protein tyrosine phosphatase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: protein tyrosine phosphate + H2O = protein tyrosine + phosphate." [EC:3.1.3.48]	
EOG8CG2R8	GO:0005840	name: ribosome	namespace: cellular_component	def: "An intracellular organelle, about 200 A in diameter, consisting of RNA and protein. It is the site of protein biosynthesis resulting from translation of messenger RNA (mRNA). It consists of two subunits, one large and one small, each containing only protein and RNA. Both the ribosome and its subunits are characterized by their sedimentation coefficients, expressed in Svedberg units (symbol: S). Hence, the prokaryotic ribosome (70S) comprises a large (50S) subunit and a small (30S) subunit, while the eukaryotic ribosome (80S) comprises a large (60S) subunit and a small (40S) subunit. Two sites on the ribosomal large subunit are involved in translation, namely the aminoacyl site (A site) and peptidyl site (P site). Ribosomes from prokaryotes, eukaryotes, mitochondria, and chloroplasts have characteristically distinct ribosomal proteins." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8CG2R8	GO:0006412	name: translation	namespace: biological_process	def: "The cellular metabolic process in which a protein is formed, using the sequence of a mature mRNA molecule to specify the sequence of amino acids in a polypeptide chain. Translation is mediated by the ribosome, and begins with the formation of a ternary complex between aminoacylated initiator methionine tRNA, GTP, and initiation factor 2, which subsequently associates with the small subunit of the ribosome and an mRNA. Translation ends with the release of a polypeptide chain from the ribosome." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8CG2R8	GO:0022857	name: transmembrane transporter activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Enables the transfer of a substance from one side of a membrane to the other." [GOC:mtg_transport, ISBN:0815340729]	
EOG8CG2R8	GO:0019031	name: viral envelope	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The lipid bilayer of a virion that surrounds the protein capsid. May also contain glycoproteins." [GOC:bf, GOC:bm, GOC:jl, ISBN:0781718325, Wikipedia:Viral_envelope]	
EOG8CG2R8	GO:0003735	name: structural constituent of ribosome	namespace: molecular_function	def: "The action of a molecule that contributes to the structural integrity of the ribosome." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8CG2R8	GO:0016491	name: oxidoreductase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of an oxidation-reduction (redox) reaction, a reversible chemical reaction in which the oxidation state of an atom or atoms within a molecule is altered. One substrate acts as a hydrogen or electron donor and becomes oxidized, while the other acts as hydrogen or electron acceptor and becomes reduced." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8CG2R8	GO:0005975	name: carbohydrate metabolic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways involving carbohydrates, any of a group of organic compounds based of the general formula Cx(H2O)y. Includes the formation of carbohydrate derivatives by the addition of a carbohydrate residue to another molecule." [GOC:mah, ISBN:0198506732]	
