EOG844P1T	GO:0004090	name: carbonyl reductase (NADPH) activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: R-CHOH-R' + NADP+ = R-CO-R' + NADPH + H+." [EC:1.1.1.184]	
EOG844P1T	GO:0000166	name: nucleotide binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with a nucleotide, any compound consisting of a nucleoside that is esterified with (ortho)phosphate or an oligophosphate at any hydroxyl group on the ribose or deoxyribose." [GOC:mah, ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG8V45PN	GO:0003677	name: DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular function by which a gene product interacts selectively and non-covalently with DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid)." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:tb, GOC:vw]	
EOG8V45PN	GO:0015074	name: DNA integration	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which a segment of DNA is incorporated into another, usually larger, DNA molecule such as a chromosome." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8W9MK7	GO:0016021	name: integral component of membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The component of a membrane consisting of the gene products and protein complexes having at least some part of their peptide sequence embedded in the hydrophobic region of the membrane." [GOC:dos, GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8TF310	GO:0005634	name: nucleus	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A membrane-bounded organelle of eukaryotic cells in which chromosomes are housed and replicated. In most cells, the nucleus contains all of the cell's chromosomes except the organellar chromosomes, and is the site of RNA synthesis and processing. In some species, or in specialized cell types, RNA metabolism or DNA replication may be absent." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8TF310	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8TF310	GO:0003677	name: DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular function by which a gene product interacts selectively and non-covalently with DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid)." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:tb, GOC:vw]	
EOG8B2WBF	GO:0003678	name: DNA helicase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: NTP + H2O = NDP + phosphate, to drive the unwinding of a DNA helix." [GOC:jl, GOC:mah]	
EOG8B2WBF	GO:0000723	name: telomere maintenance	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that contributes to the maintenance of proper telomeric length and structure by affecting and monitoring the activity of telomeric proteins and the length of telomeric DNA. These processes includes those that shorten and lengthen the telomeric DNA sequences." [GOC:elh, PMID:11092831]	
EOG8B2WBF	GO:0005524	name: ATP binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with ATP, adenosine 5'-triphosphate, a universally important coenzyme and enzyme regulator." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8B2WBF	GO:0007018	name: microtubule-based movement	namespace: biological_process	def: "A microtubule-based process that is mediated by motor proteins and results in the movement of organelles, other microtubules, or other particles along microtubules." [GOC:cjm, ISBN:0815316194]	
EOG8B2WBF	GO:0006511	name: ubiquitin-dependent protein catabolic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways resulting in the breakdown of a protein or peptide by hydrolysis of its peptide bonds, initiated by the covalent attachment of a ubiquitin group, or multiple ubiquitin groups, to the protein." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8B2WBF	GO:0003777	name: microtubule motor activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of movement along a microtubule, coupled to the hydrolysis of a nucleoside triphosphate (usually ATP)." [GOC:mah, ISBN:0815316194]	
EOG85TG20	GO:0003678	name: DNA helicase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: NTP + H2O = NDP + phosphate, to drive the unwinding of a DNA helix." [GOC:jl, GOC:mah]	
EOG85TG20	GO:0006281	name: DNA repair	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process of restoring DNA after damage. Genomes are subject to damage by chemical and physical agents in the environment (e.g. UV and ionizing radiations, chemical mutagens, fungal and bacterial toxins, etc.) and by free radicals or alkylating agents endogenously generated in metabolism. DNA is also damaged because of errors during its replication. A variety of different DNA repair pathways have been reported that include direct reversal, base excision repair, nucleotide excision repair, photoreactivation, bypass, double-strand break repair pathway, and mismatch repair pathway." [PMID:11563486]	
EOG85TG20	GO:0005524	name: ATP binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with ATP, adenosine 5'-triphosphate, a universally important coenzyme and enzyme regulator." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG854CFB	GO:0003677	name: DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular function by which a gene product interacts selectively and non-covalently with DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid)." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:tb, GOC:vw]	
EOG854CFB	GO:0005576	name: extracellular region	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The space external to the outermost structure of a cell. For cells without external protective or external encapsulating structures this refers to space outside of the plasma membrane. This term covers the host cell environment outside an intracellular parasite." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8STVK8	GO:0004518	name: nuclease activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of ester linkages within nucleic acids." [ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG8STVK8	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8STVK8	GO:0004527	name: exonuclease activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of ester linkages within nucleic acids by removing nucleotide residues from the 3' or 5' end." [GOC:mah, ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG8STVK8	GO:0016568	name: chromatin modification	namespace: biological_process	def: "The alteration of DNA, protein, or sometimes RNA, in chromatin, which may result in changing the chromatin structure." [GOC:mah, PMID:20404130]	
EOG8STVK8	GO:0005634	name: nucleus	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A membrane-bounded organelle of eukaryotic cells in which chromosomes are housed and replicated. In most cells, the nucleus contains all of the cell's chromosomes except the organellar chromosomes, and is the site of RNA synthesis and processing. In some species, or in specialized cell types, RNA metabolism or DNA replication may be absent." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8WWV17	GO:0005634	name: nucleus	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A membrane-bounded organelle of eukaryotic cells in which chromosomes are housed and replicated. In most cells, the nucleus contains all of the cell's chromosomes except the organellar chromosomes, and is the site of RNA synthesis and processing. In some species, or in specialized cell types, RNA metabolism or DNA replication may be absent." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8WWV17	GO:0005524	name: ATP binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with ATP, adenosine 5'-triphosphate, a universally important coenzyme and enzyme regulator." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8WWV17	GO:0008026	name: ATP-dependent helicase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: ATP + H2O = ADP + phosphate, to drive the unwinding of a DNA or RNA helix." [EC:3.6.1.3, GOC:jl]	
EOG8WWV17	GO:0003676	name: nucleic acid binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any nucleic acid." [GOC:jl]	
EOG80VZ5F	GO:0005215	name: transporter activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Enables the directed movement of substances (such as macromolecules, small molecules, ions) into, out of or within a cell, or between cells." [GOC:ai, GOC:dgf]	
EOG80VZ5F	GO:0005524	name: ATP binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with ATP, adenosine 5'-triphosphate, a universally important coenzyme and enzyme regulator." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG80VZ5F	GO:0016021	name: integral component of membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The component of a membrane consisting of the gene products and protein complexes having at least some part of their peptide sequence embedded in the hydrophobic region of the membrane." [GOC:dos, GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8STVK6	GO:0016020	name: membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A lipid bilayer along with all the proteins and protein complexes embedded in it an attached to it." [GOC:dos, GOC:mah, ISBN:0815316194]	
EOG8STVK6	GO:0016021	name: integral component of membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The component of a membrane consisting of the gene products and protein complexes having at least some part of their peptide sequence embedded in the hydrophobic region of the membrane." [GOC:dos, GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8STVK6	GO:0004888	name: transmembrane signaling receptor activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Combining with an extracellular or intracellular signal and transmitting the signal from one side of the membrane to the other to initiate a change in cell activity." [GOC:go_curators, Wikipedia:Transmembrane_receptor]	
EOG8STVK6	GO:0005506	name: iron ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with iron (Fe) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8STVK6	GO:0006935	name: chemotaxis	namespace: biological_process	def: "The directed movement of a motile cell or organism, or the directed growth of a cell guided by a specific chemical concentration gradient. Movement may be towards a higher concentration (positive chemotaxis) or towards a lower concentration (negative chemotaxis)." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8STVK6	GO:0020037	name: heme binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with heme, any compound of iron complexed in a porphyrin (tetrapyrrole) ring." [CHEBI:30413, GOC:ai]	
EOG8STVK6	GO:0009055	name: electron carrier activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular entity that serves as an electron acceptor and electron donor in an electron transport chain. An electron transport chain is a process in which a series of electron carriers operate together to transfer electrons from donors to any of several different terminal electron acceptors to generate a transmembrane electrochemical gradient." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8STVK6	GO:0005215	name: transporter activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Enables the directed movement of substances (such as macromolecules, small molecules, ions) into, out of or within a cell, or between cells." [GOC:ai, GOC:dgf]	
EOG8DV81S	GO:0015074	name: DNA integration	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which a segment of DNA is incorporated into another, usually larger, DNA molecule such as a chromosome." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8DV81S	GO:0003677	name: DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular function by which a gene product interacts selectively and non-covalently with DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid)." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:tb, GOC:vw]	
EOG8DV81S	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8DV81S	GO:0003723	name: RNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an RNA molecule or a portion thereof." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8DV81S	GO:0003964	name: RNA-directed DNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: deoxynucleoside triphosphate + DNA(n) = diphosphate + DNA(n+1). Catalyzes RNA-template-directed extension of the 3'- end of a DNA strand by one deoxynucleotide at a time." [EC:2.7.7.49]	
EOG8DV81S	GO:0005524	name: ATP binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with ATP, adenosine 5'-triphosphate, a universally important coenzyme and enzyme regulator." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8DV81S	GO:0008234	name: cysteine-type peptidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of peptide bonds in a polypeptide chain by a mechanism in which the sulfhydryl group of a cysteine residue at the active center acts as a nucleophile." [GOC:mah, http://merops.sanger.ac.uk/about/glossary.htm#CATTYPE]	
EOG8DV81S	GO:0004518	name: nuclease activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of ester linkages within nucleic acids." [ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG8FXTPW	GO:0048477	name: oogenesis	namespace: biological_process	def: "The complete process of formation and maturation of an ovum or female gamete from a primordial female germ cell. Examples of this process are found in Mus musculus and Drosophila melanogaster." [GOC:kmv, GOC:mtg_sensu, GOC:pr]	
EOG8FXTPW	GO:0003676	name: nucleic acid binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any nucleic acid." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8FXTPW	GO:0001047	name: core promoter binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with the regulatory region composed of the transcription start site and binding sites for the basal transcription machinery. Binding may occur as a sequence specific interaction or as an interaction observed only once a factor has been recruited to the DNA by other factors." [GOC:txnOH]	
EOG8FXTPW	GO:0018024	name: histone-lysine N-methyltransferase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: S-adenosyl-L-methionine + histone L-lysine = S-adenosyl-L-homocysteine + histone N6-methyl-L-lysine. The methylation of peptidyl-lysine in histones forms N6-methyl-L-lysine, N6,N6-dimethyl-L-lysine and N6,N6,N6-trimethyl-L-lysine derivatives." [EC:2.1.1.43, RESID:AA0074, RESID:AA0075, RESID:AA0076]	
EOG8FXTPW	GO:0034401	name: chromatin organization involved in regulation of transcription	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any cellular process that results in the specification, formation or maintenance of the physical structure of eukaryotic chromatin that modulates the rate, frequency or extent of DNA-dependent transcription." [GOC:curators]	
EOG8FXTPW	GO:0005634	name: nucleus	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A membrane-bounded organelle of eukaryotic cells in which chromosomes are housed and replicated. In most cells, the nucleus contains all of the cell's chromosomes except the organellar chromosomes, and is the site of RNA synthesis and processing. In some species, or in specialized cell types, RNA metabolism or DNA replication may be absent." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8FXTPW	GO:0035327	name: transcriptionally active chromatin	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The ordered and organized complex of DNA and protein that forms regions of the chromosome that are being actively transcribed." [GOC:sart, PMID:17965872]	
EOG8FXTPW	GO:0005700	name: polytene chromosome	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A type of chromosome in a polyploid cell, formed when multiple copies of homologous chromosomes are aligned side by side to give a giant chromosome in which distinct chromosome bands are readily visible." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8P5NRX	GO:0005634	name: nucleus	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A membrane-bounded organelle of eukaryotic cells in which chromosomes are housed and replicated. In most cells, the nucleus contains all of the cell's chromosomes except the organellar chromosomes, and is the site of RNA synthesis and processing. In some species, or in specialized cell types, RNA metabolism or DNA replication may be absent." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8P5NRX	GO:0032183	name: SUMO binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with the small ubiquitin-like protein SUMO." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8P5NRX	GO:0045893	name: positive regulation of transcription, DNA-templated	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that activates or increases the frequency, rate or extent of cellular DNA-templated transcription." [GOC:go_curators, GOC:txnOH]	
EOG8P5NRX	GO:0004842	name: ubiquitin-protein transferase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the transfer of ubiquitin from one protein to another via the reaction X-Ub + Y --> Y-Ub + X, where both X-Ub and Y-Ub are covalent linkages." [GOC:BioGRID, GOC:jh2, PMID:9635407]	
EOG8P5NRX	GO:0070201	name: regulation of establishment of protein localization	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that modulates the frequency, rate or extent of the directed movement of a protein to a specific location." [GOC:BHF, GOC:mah]	
EOG8P5NRX	GO:0016567	name: protein ubiquitination	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which one or more ubiquitin groups are added to a protein." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8P5NRX	GO:0005737	name: cytoplasm	namespace: cellular_component	def: "All of the contents of a cell excluding the plasma membrane and nucleus, but including other subcellular structures." [ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG8P5NRX	GO:0033768	name: SUMO-targeted ubiquitin ligase complex	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A nuclear ubiquitin ligase complex that specifically targets SUMOylated proteins; the complex is formed of homodimers or heterodimers of RNF4 family ubiquitin ligases and is conserved in eukaryotes." [GOC:vw, PMID:17762864, PMID:17762865]	
EOG8P5NRX	GO:0007530	name: sex determination	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that establishes and transmits the specification of sexual status of an individual organism." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8P5NRX	GO:0001103	name: RNA polymerase II repressing transcription factor binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an RNA polymerase II transcription repressing factor, a protein involved in negative regulation of transcription." [GOC:txnOH]	
EOG8P5NRX	GO:0043393	name: regulation of protein binding	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that modulates the frequency, rate or extent of protein binding." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8P5NRX	GO:0022008	name: neurogenesis	namespace: biological_process	def: "Generation of cells within the nervous system." [GO_REF:0000021, GOC:cls, GOC:curators, GOC:dgh, GOC:dph, GOC:jid, GOC:mtg_15jun06]	
EOG8MKQZ3	GO:0015074	name: DNA integration	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which a segment of DNA is incorporated into another, usually larger, DNA molecule such as a chromosome." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8BS00V	GO:0003723	name: RNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an RNA molecule or a portion thereof." [GOC:mah]	
EOG808QQS	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8WDGTH	GO:0031012	name: extracellular matrix	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A structure lying external to one or more cells, which provides structural support for cells or tissues; may be completely external to the cell (as in animals and bacteria) or be part of the cell (as in plants)." [GOC:mah, NIF_Subcellular:nlx_subcell_20090513]	
EOG8WDGTH	GO:0008010	name: structural constituent of chitin-based larval cuticle	namespace: molecular_function	def: "The action of a molecule that contributes to the structural integrity of the chitin-based cuticle of a larva. An example of this is found in Drosophila melanogaster." [GOC:mah, GOC:mtg_sensu]	
EOG8WDGTH	GO:0040003	name: chitin-based cuticle development	namespace: biological_process	def: "Synthesis and deposition of a chitin-based noncellular, hardened, or membranous secretion from an epithelial sheet. An example of this process is found in Drosophila melanogaster." [GOC:mtg_sensu]	
EOG87SVV1	GO:0005634	name: nucleus	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A membrane-bounded organelle of eukaryotic cells in which chromosomes are housed and replicated. In most cells, the nucleus contains all of the cell's chromosomes except the organellar chromosomes, and is the site of RNA synthesis and processing. In some species, or in specialized cell types, RNA metabolism or DNA replication may be absent." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG87SVV1	GO:0003676	name: nucleic acid binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any nucleic acid." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8K0T40	GO:0007606	name: sensory perception of chemical stimulus	namespace: biological_process	def: "The series of events required for an organism to receive a sensory chemical stimulus, convert it to a molecular signal, and recognize and characterize the signal. This is a neurological process." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8K0T40	GO:0005576	name: extracellular region	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The space external to the outermost structure of a cell. For cells without external protective or external encapsulating structures this refers to space outside of the plasma membrane. This term covers the host cell environment outside an intracellular parasite." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8K0T40	GO:0003723	name: RNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an RNA molecule or a portion thereof." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8K0T40	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8K0T40	GO:0003964	name: RNA-directed DNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: deoxynucleoside triphosphate + DNA(n) = diphosphate + DNA(n+1). Catalyzes RNA-template-directed extension of the 3'- end of a DNA strand by one deoxynucleotide at a time." [EC:2.7.7.49]	
EOG85QKTX	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG85QKTX	GO:0005634	name: nucleus	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A membrane-bounded organelle of eukaryotic cells in which chromosomes are housed and replicated. In most cells, the nucleus contains all of the cell's chromosomes except the organellar chromosomes, and is the site of RNA synthesis and processing. In some species, or in specialized cell types, RNA metabolism or DNA replication may be absent." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8P5NQ9	GO:0000723	name: telomere maintenance	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that contributes to the maintenance of proper telomeric length and structure by affecting and monitoring the activity of telomeric proteins and the length of telomeric DNA. These processes includes those that shorten and lengthen the telomeric DNA sequences." [GOC:elh, PMID:11092831]	
EOG8P5NQ9	GO:0003678	name: DNA helicase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: NTP + H2O = NDP + phosphate, to drive the unwinding of a DNA helix." [GOC:jl, GOC:mah]	
EOG8P5NQ9	GO:0004386	name: helicase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: NTP + H2O = NDP + phosphate, to drive the unwinding of a DNA or RNA helix." [GOC:mah, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8P5NQ9	GO:0004519	name: endonuclease activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of ester linkages within nucleic acids by creating internal breaks." [GOC:mah, ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG81K1SR	GO:0043154	name: negative regulation of cysteine-type endopeptidase activity involved in apoptotic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that stops, prevents, or reduces the frequency, rate or extent of a cysteine-type endopeptidase activity involved in the apoptotic process." [GOC:jl, GOC:mtg_apoptosis]	
EOG81K1SR	GO:0007423	name: sensory organ development	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process whose specific outcome is the progression of sensory organs over time, from its formation to the mature structure." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG81K1SR	GO:0004842	name: ubiquitin-protein transferase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the transfer of ubiquitin from one protein to another via the reaction X-Ub + Y --> Y-Ub + X, where both X-Ub and Y-Ub are covalent linkages." [GOC:BioGRID, GOC:jh2, PMID:9635407]	
EOG81K1SR	GO:0003677	name: DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular function by which a gene product interacts selectively and non-covalently with DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid)." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:tb, GOC:vw]	
EOG81K1SR	GO:0007289	name: spermatid nucleus differentiation	namespace: biological_process	def: "The specialization of the spermatid nucleus during the development of a spermatid into a mature male gamete competent for fertilization." [GOC:bf, GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:mah]	
EOG81K1SR	GO:0007283	name: spermatogenesis	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process of formation of spermatozoa, including spermatocytogenesis and spermiogenesis." [GOC:jid, ISBN:9780878933846]	
EOG81K1SR	GO:0019788	name: NEDD8 transferase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the transfer of NEDD8 from one protein to another via the reaction X-NEDD8 + Y --> Y-NEDD8 + X, where both X-NEDD8 and Y-NEDD8 are covalent linkages." [GOC:mah]	
EOG81K1SR	GO:0005737	name: cytoplasm	namespace: cellular_component	def: "All of the contents of a cell excluding the plasma membrane and nucleus, but including other subcellular structures." [ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG81K1SR	GO:0007298	name: border follicle cell migration	namespace: biological_process	def: "The directed movement of a border cell through the nurse cells to reach the oocyte. An example of this is found in Drosophila melanogaster." [GOC:mtg_sensu, PMID:10822261]	
EOG81K1SR	GO:0051865	name: protein autoubiquitination	namespace: biological_process	def: "The ubiquitination by a protein of one or more of its own amino acid residues, or residues on an identical protein. Ubiquitination occurs on the lysine residue by formation of an isopeptide crosslink." [GOC:ai]	
EOG81K1SR	GO:0006352	name: DNA-templated transcription, initiation	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process involved in the assembly of the RNA polymerase preinitiation complex (PIC) at the core promoter region of a DNA template, resulting in the subsequent synthesis of RNA from that promoter. The initiation phase includes PIC assembly and the formation of the first few bonds in the RNA chain, including abortive initiation, which occurs when the first few nucleotides are repeatedly synthesized and then released. The initiation phase ends just before and does not include promoter clearance, or release, which is the transition between the initiation and elongation phases of transcription." [GOC:jid, GOC:txnOH, PMID:18280161]	
EOG81K1SR	GO:0008407	name: chaeta morphogenesis	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which the anatomical structures of the chaeta are generated and organized. A chaeta is a sensory multicellular cuticular outgrowth of a specifically differentiated cell." [FBbt:00005177, GOC:bf, GOC:cjm, GOC:dos, GOC:go_curators]	
EOG81K1SR	GO:0009987	name: cellular process	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that is carried out at the cellular level, but not necessarily restricted to a single cell. For example, cell communication occurs among more than one cell, but occurs at the cellular level." [GOC:go_curators, GOC:isa_complete]	
EOG81K1SR	GO:0007275	name: multicellular organismal development	namespace: biological_process	def: "The biological process whose specific outcome is the progression of a multicellular organism over time from an initial condition (e.g. a zygote or a young adult) to a later condition (e.g. a multicellular animal or an aged adult)." [GOC:dph, GOC:ems, GOC:isa_complete, GOC:tb]	
EOG81K1SR	GO:0008354	name: germ cell migration	namespace: biological_process	def: "The orderly movement of a cell specialized to produce haploid gametes through the embryo from its site of production to the place where the gonads will form." [GOC:bf, GOC:jl]	
EOG81K1SR	GO:0045035	name: sensory organ precursor cell division	namespace: biological_process	def: "The series of four asymmetric divisions undergone by the sensory organ precursor cells to generate cells that have distinct cell fates. For example, in the external sensory organ, the precursor cells give rise to one multidendritic neuron and four additional cells (the socket, shaft, sheath cells and the external sense neuron)." [GOC:mah, PMID:11171389, PMID:18295597]	
EOG81K1SR	GO:0048800	name: antennal morphogenesis	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which the anatomical structures of the antenna are generated and organized." [GOC:jid]	
EOG81K1SR	GO:1990001	name: inhibition of cysteine-type endopeptidase activity involved in apoptotic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that prevents the activation of an inactive cysteine-type endopeptidase involved in an apoptotic process." [GOC:mtg_apoptosis, PMID:11943137]	
EOG81K1SR	GO:0005634	name: nucleus	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A membrane-bounded organelle of eukaryotic cells in which chromosomes are housed and replicated. In most cells, the nucleus contains all of the cell's chromosomes except the organellar chromosomes, and is the site of RNA synthesis and processing. In some species, or in specialized cell types, RNA metabolism or DNA replication may be absent." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG81K1SR	GO:0005515	name: protein binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any protein or protein complex (a complex of two or more proteins that may include other nonprotein molecules)." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG81K1SR	GO:0046673	name: negative regulation of compound eye retinal cell programmed cell death	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that stops, prevents, or reduces the frequency, rate or extent of programmed cell death that occurs in the compound eye retina." [GOC:ai]	
EOG81K1SR	GO:0031398	name: positive regulation of protein ubiquitination	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that activates or increases the frequency, rate or extent of the addition of ubiquitin groups to a protein." [GOC:mah]	
EOG81K1SR	GO:0016055	name: Wnt signaling pathway	namespace: biological_process	def: "The series of molecular signals initiated by binding of a Wnt protein to a frizzled family receptor on the surface of the target cell and ending with a change in cell state." [GOC:dph, GOC:go_curators, PMID:11532397]	
EOG81K1SR	GO:0097340	name: inhibition of cysteine-type endopeptidase activity	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that prevents the activation of an inactive cysteine-type endopeptidase." [GOC:mtg_apoptosis, PMID:20383739]	
EOG81K1SR	GO:0019899	name: enzyme binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any enzyme." [GOC:jl]	
EOG81K1SR	GO:0090263	name: positive regulation of canonical Wnt signaling pathway	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that increases the rate, frequency, or extent of the Wnt signaling pathway through beta-catenin, the series of molecular signals initiated by binding of a Wnt protein to a frizzled family receptor on the surface of the target cell, followed by propagation of the signal via beta-catenin, and ending with a change in transcription of target genes." [GOC:tb]	
EOG81K1SR	GO:0043066	name: negative regulation of apoptotic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that stops, prevents, or reduces the frequency, rate or extent of cell death by apoptotic process." [GOC:jl, GOC:mtg_apoptosis]	
EOG81K1SR	GO:0042787	name: protein ubiquitination involved in ubiquitin-dependent protein catabolic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which a ubiquitin group, or multiple groups, are covalently attached to the target protein, thereby initiating the degradation of that protein." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG81K1SR	GO:0006915	name: apoptotic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "A programmed cell death process which begins when a cell receives an internal (e.g. DNA damage) or external signal (e.g. an extracellular death ligand), and proceeds through a series of biochemical events (signaling pathway phase) which trigger an execution phase. The execution phase is the last step of an apoptotic process, and is typically characterized by rounding-up of the cell, retraction of pseudopodes, reduction of cellular volume (pyknosis), chromatin condensation, nuclear fragmentation (karyorrhexis), plasma membrane blebbing and fragmentation of the cell into apoptotic bodies. When the execution phase is completed, the cell has died." [GOC:cjm, GOC:dhl, GOC:ecd, GOC:go_curators, GOC:mtg_apoptosis, GOC:tb, ISBN:0198506732, PMID:18846107, PMID:21494263]	
EOG81K1SR	GO:0004869	name: cysteine-type endopeptidase inhibitor activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Stops, prevents or reduces the activity of a cysteine-type endopeptidase, any enzyme that hydrolyzes peptide bonds in polypeptides by a mechanism in which the sulfhydryl group of a cysteine residue at the active center acts as a nucleophile." [GOC:dph, GOC:tb]	
EOG8H1D99	GO:0004812	name: aminoacyl-tRNA ligase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the formation of aminoacyl-tRNA from ATP, amino acid, and tRNA with the release of diphosphate and AMP." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8H1D99	GO:0003677	name: DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular function by which a gene product interacts selectively and non-covalently with DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid)." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:tb, GOC:vw]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0008745	name: N-acetylmuramoyl-L-alanine amidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of the link between N-acetylmuramoyl residues and L-amino acid residues in certain bacterial cell-wall glycopeptides." [EC:3.5.1.28]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0045087	name: innate immune response	namespace: biological_process	def: "Innate immune responses are defense responses mediated by germline encoded components that directly recognize components of potential pathogens." [GO_REF:0000022, GOC:add, GOC:ebc, GOC:mtg_15nov05, GOC:mtg_sensu]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0005576	name: extracellular region	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The space external to the outermost structure of a cell. For cells without external protective or external encapsulating structures this refers to space outside of the plasma membrane. This term covers the host cell environment outside an intracellular parasite." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0042834	name: peptidoglycan binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently, in a non-covalent manner, with peptidoglycan, any of a class of glycoconjugates found in bacterial cell walls." [GOC:go_curators, PMID:14698226]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0006955	name: immune response	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any immune system process that functions in the calibrated response of an organism to a potential internal or invasive threat." [GO_REF:0000022, GOC:add, GOC:mtg_15nov05]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0050830	name: defense response to Gram-positive bacterium	namespace: biological_process	def: "Reactions triggered in response to the presence of a Gram-positive bacterium that act to protect the cell or organism." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0005515	name: protein binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any protein or protein complex (a complex of two or more proteins that may include other nonprotein molecules)." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0061057	name: peptidoglycan recognition protein signaling pathway	namespace: biological_process	def: "A series of molecular signals initiated by binding of peptidoglycan to a receptor on the surface of the target cell and ending with regulation of a downstream cellular process. The main outcome of the Imd signaling is the production of antimicrobial peptides." [GOC:dph, PMID:18688280]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0002221	name: pattern recognition receptor signaling pathway	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any series of molecular signals generated as a consequence of a pattern recognition receptor (PRR) binding to one of its physiological ligands. PRRs bind pathogen-associated molecular pattern (PAMPs), structures conserved among microbial species, or damage-associated molecular pattern (DAMPs), endogenous molecules released from damaged cells." [GOC:add, GOC:ar, ISBN:0781735149, PMID:15199967]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0016019	name: peptidoglycan receptor activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Combining with a peptidoglycan and transmitting the signal to initiate a change in cell activity." [PMID:14698226]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0045824	name: negative regulation of innate immune response	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that stops, prevents, or reduces the frequency, rate or extent of the innate immune response." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0008329	name: signaling pattern recognition receptor activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Combining with a pathogen-associated molecular pattern (PAMP), a structure conserved among microbial species, or damage-associated molecular pattern (DAMP), an endogenous molecule released from damaged cells), and transmitting a signal to initiate a change in cell activity." [GOC:ar, PMID:12507420, PMID:12925128, PMID:14523544, Wikipedia:Pattern_recognition_receptor]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0008340	name: determination of adult lifespan	namespace: biological_process	def: "The control of viability and duration in the adult phase of the life-cycle." [GOC:ems]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0009617	name: response to bacterium	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that results in a change in state or activity of a cell or an organism (in terms of movement, secretion, enzyme production, gene expression, etc.) as a result of a stimulus from a bacterium." [GOC:hb]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0005887	name: integral component of plasma membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The component of the plasma membrane consisting of the gene products and protein complexes having at least some part of their peptide sequence embedded in the hydrophobic region of the membrane." [GOC:dos, GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0019731	name: antibacterial humoral response	namespace: biological_process	def: "An immune response against bacteria mediated through a body fluid. Examples of this process are the antibacterial humoral responses in Mus musculus and Drosophila melanogaster." [GOC:go_curators, GOC:mtg_sensu]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0006964	name: positive regulation of biosynthetic process of antibacterial peptides active against Gram-negative bacteria	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that activates or increases the frequency, rate, or extent of biosynthesis of antibacterial peptides active against Gram-negative bacteria." [GOC:mah, PMID:10973475]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0042742	name: defense response to bacterium	namespace: biological_process	def: "Reactions triggered in response to the presence of a bacterium that act to protect the cell or organism." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0044214	name: spanning component of plasma membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The component of the plasma membrane consisting of gene products and protein complexes that have some part that spans both leaflets of the membrane." [GOC:ecd]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0006965	name: positive regulation of biosynthetic process of antibacterial peptides active against Gram-positive bacteria	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that activates or increases the frequency, rate, or extent of biosynthesis of antibacterial peptides active against Gram-positive bacteria." [GOC:mah, PMID:10973475]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0001875	name: lipopolysaccharide receptor activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Combining with a lipopolysaccharide and transmitting the signal across the cell membrane to initiate a change in cell activity. Lipopolysaccharides (LPS) are major components of the outer membrane of Gram-negative bacteria, making them prime targets for recognition by the immune system." [PMID:14609719, PMID:15379975]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0000270	name: peptidoglycan metabolic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways involving peptidoglycans, any of a class of glycoconjugates found only in bacterial cell walls and consisting of strands of glycosaminoglycan cross-linked by oligopeptides to form a huge and rigid network." [http://www.dsmz.de/species/murein.htm, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0008233	name: peptidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of a peptide bond. A peptide bond is a covalent bond formed when the carbon atom from the carboxyl group of one amino acid shares electrons with the nitrogen atom from the amino group of a second amino acid." [GOC:jl, ISBN:0815332181]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0046983	name: protein dimerization activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "The formation of a protein dimer, a macromolecular structure consists of two noncovalently associated identical or nonidentical subunits." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0032500	name: muramyl dipeptide binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently, in a non-covalent manner, with muramyl dipeptide; muramyl dipeptide is derived from peptidoglycan." [GOC:rl]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0008592	name: regulation of Toll signaling pathway	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that modulates the frequency, rate or extent of the Tl signaling pathway." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0051607	name: defense response to virus	namespace: biological_process	def: "Reactions triggered in response to the presence of a virus that act to protect the cell or organism." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0031240	name: external side of cell outer membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The side of the outer membrane that is opposite to the side that faces the periplasm of the cell." [GOC:mlg, GOC:mtg_sensu]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0045089	name: positive regulation of innate immune response	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that activates or increases the frequency, rate or extent of the innate immune response, the organism's first line of defense against infection." [GOC:ebc]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0006963	name: positive regulation of antibacterial peptide biosynthetic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that activates or increases the frequency, rate, or extent of antibacterial peptide biosynthesis." [GOC:mah, PMID:10973475]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0008063	name: Toll signaling pathway	namespace: biological_process	def: "A series of molecular signals initiated by the binding of an extracellular ligand to the receptor Toll on the surface of a target cell, and ending with regulation of a downstream cellular process, e.g. transcription." [GOC:go_curators, PMID:11135568, PMID:19126860]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0016327	name: apicolateral plasma membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The apical end of the lateral plasma membrane of epithelial cells." [GOC:hb]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0005875	name: microtubule associated complex	namespace: cellular_component	def: "Any multimeric complex connected to a microtubule." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0016021	name: integral component of membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The component of a membrane consisting of the gene products and protein complexes having at least some part of their peptide sequence embedded in the hydrophobic region of the membrane." [GOC:dos, GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0007165	name: signal transduction	namespace: biological_process	def: "The cellular process in which a signal is conveyed to trigger a change in the activity or state of a cell. Signal transduction begins with reception of a signal (e.g. a ligand binding to a receptor or receptor activation by a stimulus such as light), or for signal transduction in the absence of ligand, signal-withdrawal or the activity of a constitutively active receptor. Signal transduction ends with regulation of a downstream cellular process, e.g. regulation of transcription or regulation of a metabolic process. Signal transduction covers signaling from receptors located on the surface of the cell and signaling via molecules located within the cell. For signaling between cells, signal transduction is restricted to events at and within the receiving cell." [GOC:go_curators, GOC:mtg_signaling_feb11]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0031663	name: lipopolysaccharide-mediated signaling pathway	namespace: biological_process	def: "A series of molecular signals initiated by the binding of a lipopolysaccharide (LPS) to a receptor on the surface of a target cell, and ending with regulation of a downstream cellular process, e.g. transcription. Lipopolysaccharides are major components of the outer membrane of Gram-negative bacteria, making them prime targets for recognition by the immune system." [GOC:mah, GOC:signaling, PMID:15379975]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0006909	name: phagocytosis	namespace: biological_process	def: "An endocytosis process that results in the engulfment of external particulate material by phagocytes. The particles are initially contained within phagocytic vacuoles (phagosomes), which then fuse with primary lysosomes to effect digestion of the particles." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0004040	name: amidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: a monocarboxylic acid amide + H2O = a monocarboxylate + NH3." [EC:3.5.1.4]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0032494	name: response to peptidoglycan	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that results in a change in state or activity of an organism (in terms of movement, secretion, enzyme production, gene expression, etc.) as a result of a peptidoglycan stimulus. Peptidoglycan is a bacterial cell wall macromolecule." [GOC:add, ISBN:0721601464]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0050829	name: defense response to Gram-negative bacterium	namespace: biological_process	def: "Reactions triggered in response to the presence of a Gram-negative bacterium that act to protect the cell or organism." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0035007	name: regulation of melanization defense response	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that affects the rate, extent or location of the melanization defense response during injury or invasion." [GOC:bf]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0019730	name: antimicrobial humoral response	namespace: biological_process	def: "An immune response against microbes mediated through a body fluid. Examples of this process are seen in the antimicrobial humoral response of Drosophila melanogaster and Mus musculus." [GOC:go_curators, GOC:mtg_sensu]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0004180	name: carboxypeptidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of the terminal or penultimate peptide bond at the C-terminal end of a peptide or polypeptide." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0046329	name: negative regulation of JNK cascade	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that stops, prevents, or reduces the frequency, rate or extent of signal transduction mediated by the JNK cascade." [GOC:bf]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0002920	name: regulation of humoral immune response	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that modulates the frequency, rate, or extent of a humoral immune response." [GOC:add]	
EOG8GF5WR	GO:0061060	name: negative regulation of peptidoglycan recognition protein signaling pathway	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that decreases the rate, frequency, or extent of the peptidoglycan recognition protein signaling pathway." [GOC:dph]	
EOG8X9B0N	GO:0003899	name: DNA-directed RNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: nucleoside triphosphate + RNA(n) = diphosphate + RNA(n+1). Utilizes a DNA template, i.e. the catalysis of DNA-template-directed extension of the 3'-end of an RNA strand by one nucleotide at a time. Can initiate a chain 'de novo'." [EC:2.7.7.6]	
EOG8X9B0N	GO:0003677	name: DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular function by which a gene product interacts selectively and non-covalently with DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid)." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:tb, GOC:vw]	
EOG8X9B0N	GO:0006351	name: transcription, DNA-templated	namespace: biological_process	def: "The cellular synthesis of RNA on a template of DNA." [GOC:jl, GOC:txnOH]	
EOG8X9B0N	GO:0031012	name: extracellular matrix	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A structure lying external to one or more cells, which provides structural support for cells or tissues; may be completely external to the cell (as in animals and bacteria) or be part of the cell (as in plants)." [GOC:mah, NIF_Subcellular:nlx_subcell_20090513]	
EOG8X9B0N	GO:0004222	name: metalloendopeptidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of internal, alpha-peptide bonds in a polypeptide chain by a mechanism in which water acts as a nucleophile, one or two metal ions hold the water molecule in place, and charged amino acid side chains are ligands for the metal ions." [GOC:mah, http://merops.sanger.ac.uk/about/glossary.htm#CATTYPE, http://merops.sanger.ac.uk/about/glossary.htm#ENDOPEPTIDASE]	
EOG8X9B0N	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8JMB44	GO:0016021	name: integral component of membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The component of a membrane consisting of the gene products and protein complexes having at least some part of their peptide sequence embedded in the hydrophobic region of the membrane." [GOC:dos, GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8JMB44	GO:0008643	name: carbohydrate transport	namespace: biological_process	def: "The directed movement of carbohydrate into, out of or within a cell, or between cells, by means of some agent such as a transporter or pore. Carbohydrates are any of a group of organic compounds based of the general formula Cx(H2O)y." [GOC:ai]	
