EOG84QWG5	GO:0003676	name: nucleic acid binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any nucleic acid." [GOC:jl]	
EOG886BT1	GO:0008810	name: cellulase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the endohydrolysis of (1->4)-beta-D-glucosidic linkages in cellulose, lichenin and cereal beta-D-glucans." [EC:3.2.1.4]	
EOG886BT1	GO:0030247	name: polysaccharide binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any polysaccharide, a polymer of many (typically more than 10) monosaccharide residues linked glycosidically." [CHEBI:18154, GOC:mah]	
EOG886BT1	GO:0004553	name: hydrolase activity, hydrolyzing O-glycosyl compounds	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of any O-glycosyl bond." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8NW21G	GO:0004983	name: neuropeptide Y receptor activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Combining with neuropeptide Y to initiate a change in cell activity." [PMID:9315606]	
EOG8NW21G	GO:0004930	name: G-protein coupled receptor activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Combining with an extracellular signal and transmitting the signal across the membrane by activating an associated G-protein; promotes the exchange of GDP for GTP on the alpha subunit of a heterotrimeric G-protein complex." [GOC:bf, http://www.iuphar-db.org, Wikipedia:GPCR]	
EOG8NW21G	GO:0007194	name: negative regulation of adenylate cyclase activity	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that stops, prevents, or reduces the frequency, rate or extent of adenylate cyclase activity." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8NW21G	GO:0004995	name: tachykinin receptor activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Combining with a tachykinin neuropeptide and transmitting the signal across the membrane by activating an associated G-protein." [GOC:ai, GOC:bf, PMID:7639617, Wikipedia:Tachykinin]	
EOG8NW21G	GO:0042263	name: neuropeptide F receptor activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Combining with neuropeptide F and transmitting the signal within the cell to initiate a change in cell activity. Neuropeptide F is an arthropod peptide of more than 28 residues (typically 28-45) with a consensus C-terminal RxRFamide (commonly RPRFa, but also RVRFa." [GOC:bf, GOC:ma, PMID:21440021]	
EOG8NW21G	GO:0030536	name: larval feeding behavior	namespace: biological_process	def: "Feeding behavior in a larval (immature) organism." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8NW21G	GO:0007218	name: neuropeptide signaling pathway	namespace: biological_process	def: "The series of molecular signals generated as a consequence of a peptide neurotransmitter binding to a cell surface receptor." [GOC:mah, ISBN:0815316194]	
EOG8NW21G	GO:0050254	name: rhodopsin kinase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: ATP + rhodopsin = ADP + phosphorhodopsin." [EC:2.7.11.14, MetaCyc:RHODOPSIN-KINASE-RXN]	
EOG8NW21G	GO:0005887	name: integral component of plasma membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The component of the plasma membrane consisting of the gene products and protein complexes having at least some part of their peptide sequence embedded in the hydrophobic region of the membrane." [GOC:dos, GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8NW21G	GO:0006950	name: response to stress	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that results in a change in state or activity of a cell or an organism (in terms of movement, secretion, enzyme production, gene expression, etc.) as a result of a disturbance in organismal or cellular homeostasis, usually, but not necessarily, exogenous (e.g. temperature, humidity, ionizing radiation)." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8NW21G	GO:0007217	name: tachykinin receptor signaling pathway	namespace: biological_process	def: "The series of molecular signals generated as a consequence of a tachykinin, i.e. a short peptide with the terminal sequence (Phe-X-Gly-Leu-Met-NH2), binding to a cell surface receptor." [GOC:mah, PMID:14723970]	
EOG8NW21G	GO:0008188	name: neuropeptide receptor activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Combining with a neuropeptide to initiate a change in cell activity." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8NW21G	GO:0007186	name: G-protein coupled receptor signaling pathway	namespace: biological_process	def: "A series of molecular signals that proceeds with an activated receptor promoting the exchange of GDP for GTP on the alpha-subunit of an associated heterotrimeric G-protein complex. The GTP-bound activated alpha-G-protein then dissociates from the beta- and gamma-subunits to further transmit the signal within the cell. The pathway begins with receptor-ligand interaction, or for basal GPCR signaling the pathway begins with the receptor activating its G protein in the absence of an agonist, and ends with regulation of a downstream cellular process, e.g. transcription.  The pathway can start from the plasma membrane, Golgi or nuclear membrane (PMID:24568158 and PMID:16902576)." [GOC:bf, GOC:mah, PMID:16902576PMID\:24568158, Wikipedia:G_protein-coupled_receptor]	
EOG8QJV2Z	GO:0005515	name: protein binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any protein or protein complex (a complex of two or more proteins that may include other nonprotein molecules)." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8QJV2Z	GO:0016021	name: integral component of membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The component of a membrane consisting of the gene products and protein complexes having at least some part of their peptide sequence embedded in the hydrophobic region of the membrane." [GOC:dos, GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8QJV2Z	GO:0008039	name: synaptic target recognition	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which a neuronal cell in a multicellular organism interprets signals produced by potential target cells, with which it may form synapses." [GOC:mah, ISBN:0878932437]	
EOG8QJV2Z	GO:0050914	name: sensory perception of salty taste	namespace: biological_process	def: "The series of events required to receive a salty taste stimulus, convert it to a molecular signal, and recognize and characterize the signal. This is a neurological process." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8QJV2Z	GO:0002115	name: store-operated calcium entry	namespace: biological_process	def: "A calcium ion entry mechanism in the plasma membrane activated by the depletion of calcium ion from the internal calcium ion store in the endoplasmic reticulum." [GOC:hjd, PMID:11120592, PMID:17956991]	
EOG8QJV2Z	GO:0035199	name: salt aversion	namespace: biological_process	def: "The specific avoidance actions or reactions of an organism in response to the perception of salt." [GOC:bf]	
EOG8QJV2Z	GO:0048149	name: behavioral response to ethanol	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that results in a change in the behavior of an organism as a result of an ethanol stimulus." [GOC:jid]	
EOG8QJV2Z	GO:0005886	name: plasma membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The membrane surrounding a cell that separates the cell from its external environment. It consists of a phospholipid bilayer and associated proteins." [ISBN:0716731363]	
EOG8T4GB5	GO:0003677	name: DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular function by which a gene product interacts selectively and non-covalently with DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid)." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:tb, GOC:vw]	
EOG8T4GB5	GO:0003676	name: nucleic acid binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any nucleic acid." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8M3CRM	GO:0008010	name: structural constituent of chitin-based larval cuticle	namespace: molecular_function	def: "The action of a molecule that contributes to the structural integrity of the chitin-based cuticle of a larva. An example of this is found in Drosophila melanogaster." [GOC:mah, GOC:mtg_sensu]	
EOG8M3CRM	GO:0005578	name: proteinaceous extracellular matrix	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A layer consisting mainly of proteins (especially collagen) and glycosaminoglycans (mostly as proteoglycans) that forms a sheet underlying or overlying cells such as endothelial and epithelial cells. The proteins are secreted by cells in the vicinity. An example of this component is found in Mus musculus." [GOC:mtg_sensu, ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG8M3CRM	GO:0005576	name: extracellular region	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The space external to the outermost structure of a cell. For cells without external protective or external encapsulating structures this refers to space outside of the plasma membrane. This term covers the host cell environment outside an intracellular parasite." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8M3CRM	GO:0008061	name: chitin binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with chitin, a linear polysaccharide consisting of beta-(1->4)-linked N-acetyl-D-glucosamine residues." [GOC:jl, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8M3CRM	GO:0040003	name: chitin-based cuticle development	namespace: biological_process	def: "Synthesis and deposition of a chitin-based noncellular, hardened, or membranous secretion from an epithelial sheet. An example of this process is found in Drosophila melanogaster." [GOC:mtg_sensu]	
EOG8M3CRM	GO:0022008	name: neurogenesis	namespace: biological_process	def: "Generation of cells within the nervous system." [GO_REF:0000021, GOC:cls, GOC:curators, GOC:dgh, GOC:dph, GOC:jid, GOC:mtg_15jun06]	
EOG89PDDF	GO:0005230	name: extracellular ligand-gated ion channel activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Enables the transmembrane transfer of an ion by a channel that opens when a specific extracellular ligand has been bound by the channel complex or one of its constituent parts." [GOC:mtg_transport, ISBN:0815340729]	
EOG89PDDF	GO:0005886	name: plasma membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The membrane surrounding a cell that separates the cell from its external environment. It consists of a phospholipid bilayer and associated proteins." [ISBN:0716731363]	
EOG89PDDF	GO:0030054	name: cell junction	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A cellular component that forms a specialized region of connection between two or more cells or between a cell and the extracellular matrix. At a cell junction, anchoring proteins extend through the plasma membrane to link cytoskeletal proteins in one cell to cytoskeletal proteins in neighboring cells or to proteins in the extracellular matrix." [GOC:mah, http://www.vivo.colostate.edu/hbooks/cmb/cells/pmemb/junctions_a.html, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG89PDDF	GO:0045202	name: synapse	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The junction between a nerve fiber of one neuron and another neuron or muscle fiber or glial cell; the site of interneuronal communication. As the nerve fiber approaches the synapse it enlarges into a specialized structure, the presynaptic nerve ending, which contains mitochondria and synaptic vesicles. At the tip of the nerve ending is the presynaptic membrane; facing it, and separated from it by a minute cleft (the synaptic cleft) is a specialized area of membrane on the receiving cell, known as the postsynaptic membrane. In response to the arrival of nerve impulses, the presynaptic nerve ending secretes molecules of neurotransmitters into the synaptic cleft. These diffuse across the cleft and transmit the signal to the postsynaptic membrane." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG89PDDF	GO:0006811	name: ion transport	namespace: biological_process	def: "The directed movement of charged atoms or small charged molecules into, out of or within a cell, or between cells, by means of some agent such as a transporter or pore." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8M67ZM	GO:0003677	name: DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular function by which a gene product interacts selectively and non-covalently with DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid)." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:tb, GOC:vw]	
EOG8M67ZM	GO:0006355	name: regulation of transcription, DNA-templated	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that modulates the frequency, rate or extent of cellular DNA-templated transcription." [GOC:go_curators, GOC:txnOH]	
EOG8M67ZM	GO:0016021	name: integral component of membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The component of a membrane consisting of the gene products and protein complexes having at least some part of their peptide sequence embedded in the hydrophobic region of the membrane." [GOC:dos, GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8M67ZM	GO:0016301	name: kinase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the transfer of a phosphate group, usually from ATP, to a substrate molecule." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8M67ZM	GO:0000155	name: phosphorelay sensor kinase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the phosphorylation of a histidine residue in response to detection of an extracellular signal such as a chemical ligand or change in environment, to initiate a change in cell state or activity. The two-component sensor is a histidine kinase that autophosphorylates a histidine residue in its active site. The phosphate is then transferred to an aspartate residue in a downstream response regulator, to trigger a response." [GOC:bf, GOC:mcc, PMID:10966457, PMID:20223701, PMID:9191038]	
EOG8M67ZM	GO:0046872	name: metal ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any metal ion." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8M67ZM	GO:0005524	name: ATP binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with ATP, adenosine 5'-triphosphate, a universally important coenzyme and enzyme regulator." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG81RS85	GO:0006685	name: sphingomyelin catabolic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways resulting in the breakdown of sphingomyelin, N-acyl-4-sphingenyl-1-O-phosphorylcholine." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG81RS85	GO:0016787	name: hydrolase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of various bonds, e.g. C-O, C-N, C-C, phosphoric anhydride bonds, etc. Hydrolase is the systematic name for any enzyme of EC class 3." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8XKXPH	GO:0005515	name: protein binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any protein or protein complex (a complex of two or more proteins that may include other nonprotein molecules)." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8XKXPH	GO:0015031	name: protein transport	namespace: biological_process	def: "The directed movement of proteins into, out of or within a cell, or between cells, by means of some agent such as a transporter or pore." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8XKXPH	GO:0046331	name: lateral inhibition	namespace: biological_process	def: "Signaling between cells of equivalent developmental potential that results in these cells adopting different developmental fates. An example is the suppression by cells with a particular fate of the adoption of the same fate by surrounding cells." [GOC:bf, GOC:kmv]	
EOG8XKXPH	GO:0005789	name: endoplasmic reticulum membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The lipid bilayer surrounding the endoplasmic reticulum." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8XKXPH	GO:0016021	name: integral component of membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The component of a membrane consisting of the gene products and protein complexes having at least some part of their peptide sequence embedded in the hydrophobic region of the membrane." [GOC:dos, GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8B2WDC	GO:0004518	name: nuclease activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of ester linkages within nucleic acids." [ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG8B2WDC	GO:0016747	name: transferase activity, transferring acyl groups other than amino-acyl groups	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the transfer of an acyl group, other than amino-acyl, from one compound (donor) to another (acceptor)." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8B2WDC	GO:0004527	name: exonuclease activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of ester linkages within nucleic acids by removing nucleotide residues from the 3' or 5' end." [GOC:mah, ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG8NS5RG	GO:0008045	name: motor neuron axon guidance	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which the migration of an axon growth cone of a motor neuron is directed to a specific target site in response to a combination of attractive and repulsive cues." [CL:0000100, GOC:pr, ISBN:0878932437]	
EOG8NS5RG	GO:0016201	name: synaptic target inhibition	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which a neuronal cell in a multicellular organism recognizes chemorepellent signals that inhibit its growth toward the source." [GOC:mah, ISBN:0878932437]	
EOG8NS5RG	GO:0005811	name: lipid particle	namespace: cellular_component	def: "An intracellular non-membrane-bounded organelle comprising a matrix of coalesced lipids surrounded by a phospholipid monolayer. May include associated proteins." [GOC:mah, GOC:tb]	
EOG8NS5RG	GO:0046872	name: metal ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any metal ion." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8NS5RG	GO:0005616	name: larval serum protein complex	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A multisubunit protein complex which, in Drosophila, is a heterohexamer of three subunits, alpha, beta and gamma. The complex is thought to store amino acids for synthesis of adult proteins." [GOC:jl, PMID:6781759]	
EOG8NS5RG	GO:0045735	name: nutrient reservoir activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Functions in the storage of nutritious substrates." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8NS5RG	GO:0016491	name: oxidoreductase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of an oxidation-reduction (redox) reaction, a reversible chemical reaction in which the oxidation state of an atom or atoms within a molecule is altered. One substrate acts as a hydrogen or electron donor and becomes oxidized, while the other acts as hydrogen or electron acceptor and becomes reduced." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG82RGN2	GO:0005509	name: calcium ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with calcium ions (Ca2+)." [GOC:ai]	
EOG82RGN2	GO:0007156	name: homophilic cell adhesion via plasma membrane adhesion molecules	namespace: biological_process	def: "The attachment of a plasma membrane adhesion molecule in one cell to an identical molecule in an adjacent cell." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG82RGN2	GO:0016021	name: integral component of membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The component of a membrane consisting of the gene products and protein complexes having at least some part of their peptide sequence embedded in the hydrophobic region of the membrane." [GOC:dos, GOC:go_curators]	
EOG82RGN2	GO:0004022	name: alcohol dehydrogenase (NAD) activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: an alcohol + NAD+ = an aldehyde or ketone + NADH + H+." [EC:1.1.1.1]	
EOG82RGN2	GO:0005887	name: integral component of plasma membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The component of the plasma membrane consisting of the gene products and protein complexes having at least some part of their peptide sequence embedded in the hydrophobic region of the membrane." [GOC:dos, GOC:go_curators]	
EOG82RGN2	GO:0030950	name: establishment or maintenance of actin cytoskeleton polarity	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any cellular process that results in the specification, formation or maintenance of polarized actin-based cytoskeletal structures." [GOC:mah]	
EOG82RGN2	GO:0004714	name: transmembrane receptor protein tyrosine kinase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Combining with a signal and transmitting the signal from one side of the membrane to the other to initiate a change in cell activity by catalysis of the reaction: ATP + a protein-L-tyrosine = ADP + a protein-L-tyrosine phosphate." [EC:2.7.10.1, GOC:mah]	
EOG82RGN2	GO:0005198	name: structural molecule activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "The action of a molecule that contributes to the structural integrity of a complex or assembly within or outside a cell." [GOC:mah]	
EOG82RGN2	GO:0007295	name: growth of a germarium-derived egg chamber	namespace: biological_process	def: "Growth of the egg chamber between the time it leaves the germarium and the onset of vitellogenesis. During this time both nurse cells and the oocyte undergo developmental changes including nuclear organization and cytoplasmic growth. An example of this is found in Drosophila melanogaster." [GOC:mtg_sensu, ISBN:0879694238]	
EOG82RGN2	GO:0050829	name: defense response to Gram-negative bacterium	namespace: biological_process	def: "Reactions triggered in response to the presence of a Gram-negative bacterium that act to protect the cell or organism." [GOC:ai]	
EOG82RGN2	GO:0048477	name: oogenesis	namespace: biological_process	def: "The complete process of formation and maturation of an ovum or female gamete from a primordial female germ cell. Examples of this process are found in Mus musculus and Drosophila melanogaster." [GOC:kmv, GOC:mtg_sensu, GOC:pr]	
EOG82RGN2	GO:0007442	name: hindgut morphogenesis	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which the anatomical structures of the hindgut are generated and organized." [GOC:jid]	
EOG82RGN2	GO:0005925	name: focal adhesion	namespace: cellular_component	def: "Small region on the surface of a cell that anchors the cell to the extracellular matrix and that forms a point of termination of actin filaments." [ISBN:0124325653, ISBN:0815316208]	
EOG82RGN2	GO:0016339	name: calcium-dependent cell-cell adhesion via plasma membrane cell adhesion molecules	namespace: biological_process	def: "The attachment of one cell to another cell via adhesion molecules that require the presence of calcium for the interaction." [GOC:hb]	
EOG82RGN2	GO:0050839	name: cell adhesion molecule binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with a cell adhesion molecule." [GOC:ai]	
EOG82RGN2	GO:0007440	name: foregut morphogenesis	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which the anatomical structures of the foregut are generated and organized." [GOC:jid]	
EOG82RGN2	GO:0042247	name: establishment of planar polarity of follicular epithelium	namespace: biological_process	def: "Coordinated organization of groups of cells in the plane of a follicular epithelium, such that they all orient to similar coordinates." [GOC:ascb_2009, GOC:bf, GOC:dph, GOC:tb]	
EOG82RGN2	GO:0045089	name: positive regulation of innate immune response	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that activates or increases the frequency, rate or extent of the innate immune response, the organism's first line of defense against infection." [GOC:ebc]	
EOG82RGN2	GO:0007431	name: salivary gland development	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process whose specific outcome is the progression of the salivary gland over time, from its formation to the mature structure. Salivary glands include any of the saliva-secreting exocrine glands of the oral cavity." [GOC:jid, UBERON:0001044]	
EOG82RGN2	GO:0007424	name: open tracheal system development	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process whose specific outcome is the progression of an open tracheal system over time, from its formation to the mature structure. An open tracheal system is a respiratory system, a branched network of epithelial tubes that supplies oxygen to target tissues via spiracles. An example of this is found in Drosophila melanogaster." [GOC:mtg_sensu, PMID:8625828]	
EOG82RGN2	GO:0009925	name: basal plasma membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The region of the plasma membrane located at the basal end of the cell. Often used in reference to animal polarized epithelial membranes, where the basal membrane is the part attached to the extracellular matrix, or in plant cells, where the basal membrane is defined with respect to the zygotic axis." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG82RGN2	GO:0004872	name: receptor activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Combining with an extracellular or intracellular messenger to initiate a change in cell activity." [GOC:ceb, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG82RGN2	GO:0045571	name: negative regulation of imaginal disc growth	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that stops, prevents, or reduces the frequency, rate or extent of imaginal disc growth." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8CC6FD	GO:0005634	name: nucleus	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A membrane-bounded organelle of eukaryotic cells in which chromosomes are housed and replicated. In most cells, the nucleus contains all of the cell's chromosomes except the organellar chromosomes, and is the site of RNA synthesis and processing. In some species, or in specialized cell types, RNA metabolism or DNA replication may be absent." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8CC6FD	GO:0032783	name: ELL-EAF complex	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A heterodimeric protein complex that acts as an RNA polymerase II elongation factor; the complex is conserved from yeast to humans, and is present in S. pombe, but absent from S. cerevisiae." [PMID:17150956]	
EOG8CC6FD	GO:0005674	name: transcription factor TFIIF complex	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A general transcription initiation factor which in humans consists of a heterodimer of an alpha and a beta subunit. Helps recruit RNA polymerase II to the initiation complex and promotes translation elongation." [GOC:jl, PMID:7597077]	
EOG8CC6FD	GO:0005669	name: transcription factor TFIID complex	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A complex composed of TATA binding protein (TBP) and TBP associated factors (TAFs); the total mass is typically about 800 kDa. Most of the TAFs are conserved across species. In TATA-containing promoters for RNA polymerase II (Pol II), TFIID is believed to recognize at least two distinct elements, the TATA element and a downstream promoter element. TFIID is also involved in recognition of TATA-less Pol II promoters. Binding of TFIID to DNA is necessary but not sufficient for transcription initiation from most RNA polymerase II promoters." [GOC:krc, GOC:mah, ISBN:0471953393, ISBN:0879695501]	
EOG8CC6FD	GO:0006367	name: transcription initiation from RNA polymerase II promoter	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process involved in the assembly of the RNA polymerase II preinitiation complex (PIC) at an RNA polymerase II promoter region of a DNA template, resulting in the subsequent synthesis of RNA from that promoter. The initiation phase includes PIC assembly and the formation of the first few bonds in the RNA chain, including abortive initiation, which occurs when the first few nucleotides are repeatedly synthesized and then released. Promoter clearance, or release, is the transition between the initiation and elongation phases of transcription." [GOC:mah, GOC:txnOH]	
EOG84QWHS	GO:0003676	name: nucleic acid binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any nucleic acid." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8PG8FK	GO:0009190	name: cyclic nucleotide biosynthetic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways resulting in the formation of a cyclic nucleotide, a nucleotide in which the phosphate group is in diester linkage to two positions on the sugar residue." [GOC:go_curators, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8PG8FK	GO:0016849	name: phosphorus-oxygen lyase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the cleavage of a phosphorus-oxygen bond by other means than by hydrolysis or oxidation, or conversely adding a group to a double bond." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8STVK6	GO:0016020	name: membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A lipid bilayer along with all the proteins and protein complexes embedded in it an attached to it." [GOC:dos, GOC:mah, ISBN:0815316194]	
EOG8STVK6	GO:0016021	name: integral component of membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The component of a membrane consisting of the gene products and protein complexes having at least some part of their peptide sequence embedded in the hydrophobic region of the membrane." [GOC:dos, GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8STVK6	GO:0004888	name: transmembrane signaling receptor activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Combining with an extracellular or intracellular signal and transmitting the signal from one side of the membrane to the other to initiate a change in cell activity." [GOC:go_curators, Wikipedia:Transmembrane_receptor]	
EOG8STVK6	GO:0005506	name: iron ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with iron (Fe) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8STVK6	GO:0006935	name: chemotaxis	namespace: biological_process	def: "The directed movement of a motile cell or organism, or the directed growth of a cell guided by a specific chemical concentration gradient. Movement may be towards a higher concentration (positive chemotaxis) or towards a lower concentration (negative chemotaxis)." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8STVK6	GO:0020037	name: heme binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with heme, any compound of iron complexed in a porphyrin (tetrapyrrole) ring." [CHEBI:30413, GOC:ai]	
EOG8STVK6	GO:0009055	name: electron carrier activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular entity that serves as an electron acceptor and electron donor in an electron transport chain. An electron transport chain is a process in which a series of electron carriers operate together to transfer electrons from donors to any of several different terminal electron acceptors to generate a transmembrane electrochemical gradient." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8STVK6	GO:0005215	name: transporter activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Enables the directed movement of substances (such as macromolecules, small molecules, ions) into, out of or within a cell, or between cells." [GOC:ai, GOC:dgf]	
EOG8VMHW4	GO:0004560	name: alpha-L-fucosidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: an alpha-L-fucoside + H2O = an alcohol + L-fucose." [EC:3.2.1.51]	
EOG8VMHW4	GO:0042742	name: defense response to bacterium	namespace: biological_process	def: "Reactions triggered in response to the presence of a bacterium that act to protect the cell or organism." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8VMHW4	GO:0005737	name: cytoplasm	namespace: cellular_component	def: "All of the contents of a cell excluding the plasma membrane and nucleus, but including other subcellular structures." [ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG8VMHW4	GO:0004725	name: protein tyrosine phosphatase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: protein tyrosine phosphate + H2O = protein tyrosine + phosphate." [EC:3.1.3.48]	
EOG8VMHW4	GO:0005764	name: lysosome	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A small lytic vacuole that has cell cycle-independent morphology and is found in most animal cells and that contains a variety of hydrolases, most of which have their maximal activities in the pH range 5-6. The contained enzymes display latency if properly isolated. About 40 different lysosomal hydrolases are known and lysosomes have a great variety of morphologies and functions." [GOC:mah, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8VMHW4	GO:0042806	name: fucose binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with fucose, the pentose 6-deoxygalactose." [CHEBI:33984, ISBN:0582227089]	
EOG8VMHW4	GO:0006027	name: glycosaminoglycan catabolic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways resulting in the breakdown of glycosaminoglycans, any one of a group of polysaccharides that contain amino sugars." [ISBN:0192800981]	
EOG8P2SH4	GO:0035071	name: salivary gland cell autophagic cell death	namespace: biological_process	def: "The stage-specific programmed cell death of salivary gland cells during salivary gland histolysis." [GOC:bf, GOC:mtg_apoptosis, PMID:10882130]	
EOG8P2SH4	GO:0005764	name: lysosome	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A small lytic vacuole that has cell cycle-independent morphology and is found in most animal cells and that contains a variety of hydrolases, most of which have their maximal activities in the pH range 5-6. The contained enzymes display latency if properly isolated. About 40 different lysosomal hydrolases are known and lysosomes have a great variety of morphologies and functions." [GOC:mah, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8P2SH4	GO:0045169	name: fusome	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A large intracellular spectrin-rich structure that has been found in insect germline cells and mammalian hematopoietic cells. The fusome is an elongated, branched structure, formed from the spherical spectrosome organelle." [GOC:bf, PMID:12655376]	
EOG8P2SH4	GO:0005524	name: ATP binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with ATP, adenosine 5'-triphosphate, a universally important coenzyme and enzyme regulator." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8P2SH4	GO:0007586	name: digestion	namespace: biological_process	def: "The whole of the physical, chemical, and biochemical processes carried out by multicellular organisms to break down ingested nutrients into components that may be easily absorbed and directed into metabolism." [GOC:isa_complete, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8P2SH4	GO:0048102	name: autophagic cell death	namespace: biological_process	def: "A form of programmed cell death that is accompanied by the formation of autophagosomes. Autophagic cell death is characterized by lack of chromatin condensation and massive vacuolization of the cytoplasm, with little or no uptake by phagocytic cells." [GOC:autophagy, GOC:mah, PMID:18846107]	
EOG8P2SH4	GO:0016021	name: integral component of membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The component of a membrane consisting of the gene products and protein complexes having at least some part of their peptide sequence embedded in the hydrophobic region of the membrane." [GOC:dos, GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8P2SH4	GO:0042626	name: ATPase activity, coupled to transmembrane movement of substances	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: ATP + H2O = ADP + phosphate, to directly drive the active transport of a substance across a membrane." [EC:3.6.1.3, GOC:jl]	
EOG805VFS	GO:0005886	name: plasma membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The membrane surrounding a cell that separates the cell from its external environment. It consists of a phospholipid bilayer and associated proteins." [ISBN:0716731363]	
EOG805VFS	GO:0050909	name: sensory perception of taste	namespace: biological_process	def: "The series of events required for an organism to receive a gustatory stimulus, convert it to a molecular signal, and recognize and characterize the signal. Gustation involves the direct detection of chemical composition, usually through contact with chemoreceptor cells. This is a neurological process." [GOC:ai, http://www.onelook.com/]	
EOG805VFS	GO:0008527	name: taste receptor activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Combining with soluble compounds to initiate a change in cell activity. These receptors are responsible for the sense of taste." [GOC:dph]	
EOG805VFS	GO:0050912	name: detection of chemical stimulus involved in sensory perception of taste	namespace: biological_process	def: "The series of events involved in the perception of taste in which a gustatory chemical stimulus is received and converted into a molecular signal." [GOC:ai]	
EOG805VFS	GO:0004930	name: G-protein coupled receptor activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Combining with an extracellular signal and transmitting the signal across the membrane by activating an associated G-protein; promotes the exchange of GDP for GTP on the alpha subunit of a heterotrimeric G-protein complex." [GOC:bf, http://www.iuphar-db.org, Wikipedia:GPCR]	
EOG805VFS	GO:0030425	name: dendrite	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A neuron projection that has a short, tapering, often branched, morphology, receives and integrates signals from other neurons or from sensory stimuli, and conducts a nerve impulse towards the axon or the cell body. In most neurons, the impulse is conveyed from dendrites to axon via the cell body, but in some types of unipolar neuron, the impulse does not travel via the cell body." [GOC:dos, GOC:mah, GOC:nln, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG805VFS	GO:0004984	name: olfactory receptor activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Combining with an odorant and transmitting the signal from one side of the membrane to the other to initiate a change in cell activity in response to detection of smell." [GOC:bf, GOC:dph, GOC:sart, PMID:19135896, PMID:21041441]	
EOG805VFS	GO:0017085	name: response to insecticide	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that results in a change in state or activity of a cell or an organism (in terms of movement, secretion, enzyme production, gene expression, etc.) as a result of an insecticide stimulus. Insecticides are chemicals used to kill insects." [GOC:curators]	
EOG805VFS	GO:0030424	name: axon	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The long process of a neuron that conducts nerve impulses, usually away from the cell body to the terminals and varicosities, which are sites of storage and release of neurotransmitter." [GOC:nln, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG805VFS	GO:0007635	name: chemosensory behavior	namespace: biological_process	def: "Behavior that is dependent upon the sensation of chemicals." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG805VFS	GO:0005549	name: odorant binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an odorant, any substance capable of stimulating the sense of smell." [GOC:jl, ISBN:0721662544]	
EOG805VFS	GO:0046957	name: negative phototaxis	namespace: biological_process	def: "The directed movement of a cell or organism away from a source of light." [GOC:ai]	
EOG805VFS	GO:0007631	name: feeding behavior	namespace: biological_process	def: "Behavior associated with the intake of food." [GOC:mah]	
EOG805VFS	GO:0040040	name: thermosensory behavior	namespace: biological_process	def: "Behavior that is dependent upon the sensation of temperature." [GOC:ems]	
EOG805VFS	GO:0031000	name: response to caffeine	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that results in a change in state or activity of a cell or an organism (in terms of movement, secretion, enzyme production, gene expression, etc.) as a result of a caffeine stimulus. Caffeine is an alkaloid found in numerous plant species, where it acts as a natural pesticide that paralyzes and kills certain insects feeding upon them." [CHEBI:27732, GOC:ef, GOC:mah]	
EOG805VFS	GO:0006955	name: immune response	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any immune system process that functions in the calibrated response of an organism to a potential internal or invasive threat." [GO_REF:0000022, GOC:add, GOC:mtg_15nov05]	
EOG805VFS	GO:0007602	name: phototransduction	namespace: biological_process	def: "The sequence of reactions within a cell required to convert absorbed photons into a molecular signal." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG805VFS	GO:0046982	name: protein heterodimerization activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with a nonidentical protein to form a heterodimer." [GOC:ai]	
EOG805VFS	GO:0008049	name: male courtship behavior	namespace: biological_process	def: "The behavior of a male, for the purpose of attracting a sexual partner. An example of this process is found in Drosophila melanogaster." [GOC:mtg_sensu, GOC:pr]	
EOG805VFS	GO:0035006	name: melanization defense response	namespace: biological_process	def: "The blackening of the wounded area of the cuticle or the surface of invading pathogens, parasites or parasitoids, resulting from a proteolytic cascade leading to the de novo synthesis and deposition of melanin." [GOC:bf, PMID:12408809]	
EOG805VFS	GO:0042742	name: defense response to bacterium	namespace: biological_process	def: "Reactions triggered in response to the presence of a bacterium that act to protect the cell or organism." [GOC:jl]	
EOG805VFS	GO:0044297	name: cell body	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The portion of a cell bearing surface projections such as axons, dendrites, cilia, or flagella that includes the nucleus, but excludes all cell projections." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8BZQHG	GO:0020037	name: heme binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with heme, any compound of iron complexed in a porphyrin (tetrapyrrole) ring." [CHEBI:30413, GOC:ai]	
EOG8BZQHG	GO:0016705	name: oxidoreductase activity, acting on paired donors, with incorporation or reduction of molecular oxygen	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of an oxidation-reduction (redox) reaction in which hydrogen or electrons are transferred from each of two donors, and molecular oxygen is reduced or incorporated into a donor." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8BZQHG	GO:0004497	name: monooxygenase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the incorporation of one atom from molecular oxygen into a compound and the reduction of the other atom of oxygen to water." [http://www.onelook.com/, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8BZQHG	GO:0004501	name: ecdysone 20-monooxygenase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: AH(2) + Ecdysone + O(2) = 20-hydroxyecdysone + A + H(2)O." [EC:1.14.99.22, RHEA:14024]	
EOG8BZQHG	GO:0008386	name: cholesterol monooxygenase (side-chain-cleaving) activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: cholesterol + reduced adrenal ferredoxin + O2 = pregnenolone + 4-methylpentanal + oxidized adrenal ferredoxin + H2O." [EC:1.14.15.6]	
EOG8BZQHG	GO:0031966	name: mitochondrial membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "Either of the lipid bilayers that surround the mitochondrion and form the mitochondrial envelope." [GOC:mah, NIF_Subcellular:sao1045389829]	
EOG8BZQHG	GO:0007494	name: midgut development	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process whose specific outcome is the progression of the midgut over time, from its formation to the mature structure. The midgut is the middle part of the alimentary canal from the stomach, or entrance of the bile duct, to, or including, the large intestine." [GOC:jid, UBERON:0001045]	
EOG8BZQHG	GO:0042767	name: ecdysteroid 22-hydroxylase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydroxylation of an ecdysteroid at carbon position 22." [PMID:12177427]	
EOG8BZQHG	GO:0005789	name: endoplasmic reticulum membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The lipid bilayer surrounding the endoplasmic reticulum." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8BZQHG	GO:0006697	name: ecdysone biosynthetic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways resulting in the formation of ecdysone, (22R)-2-beta,3-beta,14,22,25-pentahydroxycholest-7-en-6-one, an ecdysteroid found in insects." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8BZQHG	GO:0009055	name: electron carrier activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular entity that serves as an electron acceptor and electron donor in an electron transport chain. An electron transport chain is a process in which a series of electron carriers operate together to transfer electrons from donors to any of several different terminal electron acceptors to generate a transmembrane electrochemical gradient." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8BZQHG	GO:0008362	name: chitin-based embryonic cuticle biosynthetic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "Synthesis, including the chemical reactions and pathways resulting in the formation of chitin and other components, and deposition of a chitin-based embryonic cuticle by the underlying epidermal epithelium. This tough, waterproof cuticle layer is essential to provide structural integrity of the larval body. An example of this is found in Drosophila melanogaster." [GOC:bf, GOC:mtg_sensu, PMID:12019232]	
EOG8BZQHG	GO:0005739	name: mitochondrion	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A semiautonomous, self replicating organelle that occurs in varying numbers, shapes, and sizes in the cytoplasm of virtually all eukaryotic cells. It is notably the site of tissue respiration." [GOC:giardia, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8BZQHG	GO:0008258	name: head involution	namespace: biological_process	def: "Movement of the anterior ectoderm to the interior of the embryo." [ISBN:08795694238]	
EOG8BZQHG	GO:0007490	name: tergite morphogenesis	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which the anatomical structures of the tergite are generated and organized. The tergite is the primary plate or sclerite forming the dorsal surface of any insect body segment." [GOC:jid, http://www.earthlife.net]	
EOG8BZQHG	GO:0007391	name: dorsal closure	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process during Drosophila embryogenesis whereby the ectodermal cells of the lateral epithelium stretch in a coordinated fashion to internalize the amnioserosa cells and close the embryo dorsally." [PMID:9224720]	
EOG8BZQHG	GO:0007417	name: central nervous system development	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process whose specific outcome is the progression of the central nervous system over time, from its formation to the mature structure. The central nervous system is the core nervous system that serves an integrating and coordinating function. In vertebrates it consists of the brain and spinal cord. In those invertebrates with a central nervous system it typically consists of a brain, cerebral ganglia and a nerve cord." [GOC:bf, GOC:jid, ISBN:0582227089]	
EOG8NKF9Q	GO:0007157	name: heterophilic cell-cell adhesion via plasma membrane cell adhesion molecules	namespace: biological_process	def: "The attachment of an adhesion molecule in one cell to a nonidentical adhesion molecule in an adjacent cell." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8NKF9Q	GO:0005887	name: integral component of plasma membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The component of the plasma membrane consisting of the gene products and protein complexes having at least some part of their peptide sequence embedded in the hydrophobic region of the membrane." [GOC:dos, GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8NKF9Q	GO:0007415	name: defasciculation of motor neuron axon	namespace: biological_process	def: "Separation of a motor axon away from a bundle of axons known as a fascicle." [GOC:dgh]	
EOG8NKF9Q	GO:0007411	name: axon guidance	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemotaxis process that directs the migration of an axon growth cone to a specific target site in response to a combination of attractive and repulsive cues." [ISBN:0878932437]	
EOG8NKF9Q	GO:0004252	name: serine-type endopeptidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of internal, alpha-peptide bonds in a polypeptide chain by a catalytic mechanism that involves a catalytic triad consisting of a serine nucleophile that is activated by a proton relay involving an acidic residue (e.g. aspartate or glutamate) and a basic residue (usually histidine)." [GOC:mah, http://merops.sanger.ac.uk/about/glossary.htm#CATTYPE, ISBN:0716720094]	
EOG8NKF9Q	GO:0005576	name: extracellular region	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The space external to the outermost structure of a cell. For cells without external protective or external encapsulating structures this refers to space outside of the plasma membrane. This term covers the host cell environment outside an intracellular parasite." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8NKF9Q	GO:0005515	name: protein binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any protein or protein complex (a complex of two or more proteins that may include other nonprotein molecules)." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8NKF9Q	GO:0001746	name: Bolwig's organ morphogenesis	namespace: biological_process	def: "The morphogenetic process in which the anatomical structures of the larval eye in Drosophila are generated and organized. The larval eye in Drosophila is a relatively simple sensory system composed of Bolwig's organs: two clusters, each composed of 12 photoreceptor cells from which axons extend in a single fascicle to the brain." [http://sdb.bio.purdue.edu/fly/torstoll/tailess.htm#bolwigs, PMID:6185380]	
EOG8NKF9Q	GO:0016198	name: axon choice point recognition	namespace: biological_process	def: "The recognition of molecules at a choice point by an axon growth cone; at a choice point the growth cone determines the direction of its future growth." [PMID:10218152]	
EOG8NKF9Q	GO:0008045	name: motor neuron axon guidance	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which the migration of an axon growth cone of a motor neuron is directed to a specific target site in response to a combination of attractive and repulsive cues." [CL:0000100, GOC:pr, ISBN:0878932437]	
EOG8NKF9Q	GO:0016201	name: synaptic target inhibition	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which a neuronal cell in a multicellular organism recognizes chemorepellent signals that inhibit its growth toward the source." [GOC:mah, ISBN:0878932437]	
EOG8NKF9Q	GO:0031225	name: anchored component of membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The component of a membrane consisting of the gene products that are tethered to the membrane only by a covalently attached anchor, such as a lipid group that is embedded in the membrane. Gene products with peptide sequences that are embedded in the membrane are excluded from this grouping." [GOC:dos, GOC:mah]	
EOG8MKQZ3	GO:0015074	name: DNA integration	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which a segment of DNA is incorporated into another, usually larger, DNA molecule such as a chromosome." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8BS00Q	GO:0035335	name: peptidyl-tyrosine dephosphorylation	namespace: biological_process	def: "The removal of phosphoric residues from peptidyl-O-phospho-tyrosine to form peptidyl-tyrosine." [GOC:bf]	
EOG8BS00Q	GO:0008045	name: motor neuron axon guidance	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which the migration of an axon growth cone of a motor neuron is directed to a specific target site in response to a combination of attractive and repulsive cues." [CL:0000100, GOC:pr, ISBN:0878932437]	
EOG8BS00Q	GO:0007411	name: axon guidance	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemotaxis process that directs the migration of an axon growth cone to a specific target site in response to a combination of attractive and repulsive cues." [ISBN:0878932437]	
EOG8BS00Q	GO:0006470	name: protein dephosphorylation	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process of removing one or more phosphoric residues from a protein." [GOC:hb]	
EOG8DNHJQ	GO:0003676	name: nucleic acid binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any nucleic acid." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8P5NQ9	GO:0000723	name: telomere maintenance	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that contributes to the maintenance of proper telomeric length and structure by affecting and monitoring the activity of telomeric proteins and the length of telomeric DNA. These processes includes those that shorten and lengthen the telomeric DNA sequences." [GOC:elh, PMID:11092831]	
EOG8P5NQ9	GO:0003678	name: DNA helicase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: NTP + H2O = NDP + phosphate, to drive the unwinding of a DNA helix." [GOC:jl, GOC:mah]	
EOG8P5NQ9	GO:0004386	name: helicase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: NTP + H2O = NDP + phosphate, to drive the unwinding of a DNA or RNA helix." [GOC:mah, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8P5NQ9	GO:0004519	name: endonuclease activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of ester linkages within nucleic acids by creating internal breaks." [GOC:mah, ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG8RZ1FH	GO:0016021	name: integral component of membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The component of a membrane consisting of the gene products and protein complexes having at least some part of their peptide sequence embedded in the hydrophobic region of the membrane." [GOC:dos, GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8RZ1FH	GO:0016020	name: membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A lipid bilayer along with all the proteins and protein complexes embedded in it an attached to it." [GOC:dos, GOC:mah, ISBN:0815316194]	
EOG8RZ1FH	GO:0005634	name: nucleus	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A membrane-bounded organelle of eukaryotic cells in which chromosomes are housed and replicated. In most cells, the nucleus contains all of the cell's chromosomes except the organellar chromosomes, and is the site of RNA synthesis and processing. In some species, or in specialized cell types, RNA metabolism or DNA replication may be absent." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8RZ1FH	GO:0003700	name: transcription factor activity, sequence-specific DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with a specific DNA sequence in order to modulate transcription. The transcription factor may or may not also interact selectively with a protein or macromolecular complex." [GOC:curators, GOC:txnOH]	
EOG8W6R95	GO:0005525	name: GTP binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with GTP, guanosine triphosphate." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8W6R95	GO:0005783	name: endoplasmic reticulum	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The irregular network of unit membranes, visible only by electron microscopy, that occurs in the cytoplasm of many eukaryotic cells. The membranes form a complex meshwork of tubular channels, which are often expanded into slitlike cavities called cisternae. The ER takes two forms, rough (or granular), with ribosomes adhering to the outer surface, and smooth (with no ribosomes attached)." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8W6R95	GO:0007030	name: Golgi organization	namespace: biological_process	def: "A process that is carried out at the cellular level which results in the assembly, arrangement of constituent parts, or disassembly of the Golgi apparatus." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:mah]	
EOG8W6R95	GO:0016021	name: integral component of membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The component of a membrane consisting of the gene products and protein complexes having at least some part of their peptide sequence embedded in the hydrophobic region of the membrane." [GOC:dos, GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8W6R95	GO:0005509	name: calcium ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with calcium ions (Ca2+)." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8W6R95	GO:0005515	name: protein binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any protein or protein complex (a complex of two or more proteins that may include other nonprotein molecules)." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8W6R95	GO:0007528	name: neuromuscular junction development	namespace: biological_process	def: "A process that is carried out at the cellular level which results in the assembly, arrangement of constituent parts, or disassembly of a neuromuscular junction." [GOC:mtg_OBO2OWL_2013]	
EOG8W6R95	GO:0042802	name: identical protein binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an identical protein or proteins." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8W6R95	GO:0016320	name: endoplasmic reticulum membrane fusion	namespace: biological_process	def: "The joining of 2 or more lipid bilayer membranes that surround the endoplasmic reticulum." [GOC:elh, GOC:jid]	
EOG8W6R95	GO:0016020	name: membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A lipid bilayer along with all the proteins and protein complexes embedded in it an attached to it." [GOC:dos, GOC:mah, ISBN:0815316194]	
EOG8W6R95	GO:0042803	name: protein homodimerization activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an identical protein to form a homodimer." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8W6R95	GO:0006184	name: obsolete GTP catabolic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "OBSOLETE. The chemical reactions and pathways resulting in the breakdown of GTP, guanosine triphosphate." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8W6R95	GO:0000139	name: Golgi membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The lipid bilayer surrounding any of the compartments of the Golgi apparatus." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8W6R95	GO:0031227	name: intrinsic component of endoplasmic reticulum membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The component of the endoplasmic reticulum membrane consisting of the gene products and protein complexes having either part of their peptide sequence embedded in the hydrophobic region of the membrane or some other covalently attached group such as a GPI anchor that is similarly embedded in the membrane." [GOC:dos, GOC:mah]	
EOG8W6R95	GO:0007517	name: muscle organ development	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process whose specific outcome is the progression of the muscle over time, from its formation to the mature structure. The muscle is an organ consisting of a tissue made up of various elongated cells that are specialized to contract and thus to produce movement and mechanical work." [GOC:jid, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8W6R95	GO:0061025	name: membrane fusion	namespace: biological_process	def: "The membrane organization process that joins two lipid bilayers to form a single membrane." [GOC:dph, GOC:tb]	
EOG8W6R95	GO:0007029	name: endoplasmic reticulum organization	namespace: biological_process	def: "A process that is carried out at the cellular level which results in the assembly, arrangement of constituent parts, or disassembly of the endoplasmic reticulum." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:mah]	
EOG8W6R95	GO:0051124	name: synaptic growth at neuromuscular junction	namespace: biological_process	def: "The growth of a synapse at a neuromuscular junction, the site of apposition of a motor end plate and the subneural cleft of the skeletal muscle fiber that it innervates." [ISBN:0721662544]	
EOG8W6R95	GO:0006457	name: protein folding	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process of assisting in the covalent and noncovalent assembly of single chain polypeptides or multisubunit complexes into the correct tertiary structure." [GOC:go_curators, GOC:rb]	
EOG8W6R95	GO:0008582	name: regulation of synaptic growth at neuromuscular junction	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that modulates the frequency, rate or extent of synaptic growth at neuromuscular junctions." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8W6R95	GO:0032561	name: guanyl ribonucleotide binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with a guanyl ribonucleotide, any compound consisting of guanosine esterified with (ortho)phosphate or an oligophosphate at any hydroxyl group on the ribose moiety." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8W6R95	GO:0005794	name: Golgi apparatus	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A compound membranous cytoplasmic organelle of eukaryotic cells, consisting of flattened, ribosome-free vesicles arranged in a more or less regular stack. The Golgi apparatus differs from the endoplasmic reticulum in often having slightly thicker membranes, appearing in sections as a characteristic shallow semicircle so that the convex side (cis or entry face) abuts the endoplasmic reticulum, secretory vesicles emerging from the concave side (trans or exit face). In vertebrate cells there is usually one such organelle, while in invertebrates and plants, where they are known usually as dictyosomes, there may be several scattered in the cytoplasm. The Golgi apparatus processes proteins produced on the ribosomes of the rough endoplasmic reticulum; such processing includes modification of the core oligosaccharides of glycoproteins, and the sorting and packaging of proteins for transport to a variety of cellular locations. Three different regions of the Golgi are now recognized both in terms of structure and function: cis, in the vicinity of the cis face, trans, in the vicinity of the trans face, and medial, lying between the cis and trans regions." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8W6R95	GO:0007019	name: microtubule depolymerization	namespace: biological_process	def: "The removal of tubulin heterodimers from one or both ends of a microtubule." [ISBN:0815316194]	
EOG8W6R95	GO:0005737	name: cytoplasm	namespace: cellular_component	def: "All of the contents of a cell excluding the plasma membrane and nucleus, but including other subcellular structures." [ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG8W6R95	GO:0051260	name: protein homooligomerization	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process of creating protein oligomers, compounds composed of a small number, usually between three and ten, of identical component monomers. Oligomers may be formed by the polymerization of a number of monomers or the depolymerization of a large protein polymer." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8W6R95	GO:0031114	name: regulation of microtubule depolymerization	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that modulates the frequency, rate or extent of microtubule depolymerization." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8HHRGC	GO:0016021	name: integral component of membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The component of a membrane consisting of the gene products and protein complexes having at least some part of their peptide sequence embedded in the hydrophobic region of the membrane." [GOC:dos, GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8HHRGC	GO:0016020	name: membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A lipid bilayer along with all the proteins and protein complexes embedded in it an attached to it." [GOC:dos, GOC:mah, ISBN:0815316194]	
EOG8HHRGC	GO:0005509	name: calcium ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with calcium ions (Ca2+)." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8HHRGC	GO:0005886	name: plasma membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The membrane surrounding a cell that separates the cell from its external environment. It consists of a phospholipid bilayer and associated proteins." [ISBN:0716731363]	
EOG84J4XW	GO:0001786	name: phosphatidylserine binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with phosphatidylserine, a class of glycophospholipids in which a phosphatidyl group is esterified to the hydroxyl group of L-serine." [ISBN:0198506732, PMID:12000961]	
EOG84J4XW	GO:0043277	name: apoptotic cell clearance	namespace: biological_process	def: "The recognition and removal of an apoptotic cell by a neighboring cell or by a phagocyte." [GOC:rk, PMID:14685684]	
EOG84J4XW	GO:0035212	name: cell competition in a multicellular organism	namespace: biological_process	def: "Competitive interactions within multicellular organisms between cell populations that differ in growth rates, leading to the elimination of the slowest-growing cells." [GOC:bf, PMID:1116643, PMID:15066286]	
EOG84J4XW	GO:0048190	name: wing disc dorsal/ventral pattern formation	namespace: biological_process	def: "The establishment, maintenance and elaboration of the dorsal/ventral axis of the wing disc, a precursor to the adult wing." [GOC:jid]	
EOG84J4XW	GO:0016322	name: neuron remodeling	namespace: biological_process	def: "The developmentally regulated remodeling of neuronal projections such as pruning to eliminate the extra dendrites and axons projections set up in early stages of nervous system development." [GOC:hb]	
EOG84J4XW	GO:0003944	name: N-acetylglucosamine-1-phosphodiester alpha-N-acetylglucosaminidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: glycoprotein N-acetyl-D-glucosaminyl-phospho-D-mannose + H2O = N-acetyl-D-glucosamine + glycoprotein phospho-D-mannose." [EC:3.1.4.45]	
EOG84J4XW	GO:0007596	name: blood coagulation	namespace: biological_process	def: "The sequential process in which the multiple coagulation factors of the blood interact, ultimately resulting in the formation of an insoluble fibrin clot; it may be divided into three stages: stage 1, the formation of intrinsic and extrinsic prothrombin converting principle; stage 2, the formation of thrombin; stage 3, the formation of stable fibrin polymers." [http://www.graylab.ac.uk/omd/, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG84J4XW	GO:0004222	name: metalloendopeptidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of internal, alpha-peptide bonds in a polypeptide chain by a mechanism in which water acts as a nucleophile, one or two metal ions hold the water molecule in place, and charged amino acid side chains are ligands for the metal ions." [GOC:mah, http://merops.sanger.ac.uk/about/glossary.htm#CATTYPE, http://merops.sanger.ac.uk/about/glossary.htm#ENDOPEPTIDASE]	
EOG84J4XW	GO:0006911	name: phagocytosis, engulfment	namespace: biological_process	def: "The internalization of bacteria, immune complexes and other particulate matter or of an apoptotic cell by phagocytosis, including the membrane and cytoskeletal processes required, which involves one of three mechanisms: zippering of pseudopods around a target via repeated receptor-ligand interactions, sinking of the target directly into plasma membrane of the phagocytosing cell, or induced uptake via an enhanced membrane ruffling of the phagocytosing cell similar to macropinocytosis." [GOC:curators, ISBN:0781735149]	
EOG84J4XW	GO:0042742	name: defense response to bacterium	namespace: biological_process	def: "Reactions triggered in response to the presence of a bacterium that act to protect the cell or organism." [GOC:jl]	
EOG84J4XW	GO:0005509	name: calcium ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with calcium ions (Ca2+)." [GOC:ai]	
EOG84J4XW	GO:0006909	name: phagocytosis	namespace: biological_process	def: "An endocytosis process that results in the engulfment of external particulate material by phagocytes. The particles are initially contained within phagocytic vacuoles (phagosomes), which then fuse with primary lysosomes to effect digestion of the particles." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG84J4XW	GO:0004888	name: transmembrane signaling receptor activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Combining with an extracellular or intracellular signal and transmitting the signal from one side of the membrane to the other to initiate a change in cell activity." [GOC:go_curators, Wikipedia:Transmembrane_receptor]	
EOG84J4XW	GO:0031224	name: intrinsic component of membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The component of a membrane consisting of the gene products having some covalently attached portion, for example part of a peptide sequence or some other covalently attached group such as a GPI anchor, which spans or is embedded in one or both leaflets of the membrane." [GOC:mah]	
EOG84J4XW	GO:0008345	name: larval locomotory behavior	namespace: biological_process	def: "Locomotory behavior in a larval (immature) organism." [GOC:ai]	
EOG84J4XW	GO:0005524	name: ATP binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with ATP, adenosine 5'-triphosphate, a universally important coenzyme and enzyme regulator." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG84J4XW	GO:0043652	name: engulfment of apoptotic cell	namespace: biological_process	def: "The removal of the apoptotic cell by phagocytosis, by a neighboring cell or by a phagocyte." [GOC:rk, PMID:15536015]	
EOG84J4XW	GO:0035071	name: salivary gland cell autophagic cell death	namespace: biological_process	def: "The stage-specific programmed cell death of salivary gland cells during salivary gland histolysis." [GOC:bf, GOC:mtg_apoptosis, PMID:10882130]	
EOG84J4XW	GO:0004714	name: transmembrane receptor protein tyrosine kinase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Combining with a signal and transmitting the signal from one side of the membrane to the other to initiate a change in cell activity by catalysis of the reaction: ATP + a protein-L-tyrosine = ADP + a protein-L-tyrosine phosphate." [EC:2.7.10.1, GOC:mah]	
EOG84J4XW	GO:0017111	name: nucleoside-triphosphatase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: a nucleoside triphosphate + H2O = nucleoside diphosphate + phosphate." [EC:3.6.1.15]	
EOG8WM77F	GO:0007156	name: homophilic cell adhesion via plasma membrane adhesion molecules	namespace: biological_process	def: "The attachment of a plasma membrane adhesion molecule in one cell to an identical molecule in an adjacent cell." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8WM77F	GO:0005887	name: integral component of plasma membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The component of the plasma membrane consisting of the gene products and protein complexes having at least some part of their peptide sequence embedded in the hydrophobic region of the membrane." [GOC:dos, GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8WM77F	GO:0042802	name: identical protein binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an identical protein or proteins." [GOC:jl]	
EOG89KJ4Z	GO:0005525	name: GTP binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with GTP, guanosine triphosphate." [GOC:ai]	
EOG89KJ4Z	GO:0005200	name: structural constituent of cytoskeleton	namespace: molecular_function	def: "The action of a molecule that contributes to the structural integrity of a cytoskeletal structure." [GOC:mah]	
EOG89KJ4Z	GO:0003924	name: GTPase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: GTP + H2O = GDP + phosphate." [ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG89KJ4Z	GO:0007017	name: microtubule-based process	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any cellular process that depends upon or alters the microtubule cytoskeleton, that part of the cytoskeleton comprising microtubules and their associated proteins." [GOC:mah]	
EOG89KJ4Z	GO:0051258	name: protein polymerization	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process of creating protein polymers, compounds composed of a large number of component monomers; polymeric proteins may be made up of different or identical monomers. Polymerization occurs by the addition of extra monomers to an existing poly- or oligomeric protein." [GOC:ai]	
EOG89KJ4Z	GO:0005737	name: cytoplasm	namespace: cellular_component	def: "All of the contents of a cell excluding the plasma membrane and nucleus, but including other subcellular structures." [ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG89KJ4Z	GO:0051298	name: centrosome duplication	namespace: biological_process	def: "The replication of a centrosome, a structure comprised of a pair of centrioles and peri-centriolar material from which a microtubule spindle apparatus is organized." [GOC:ai]	
EOG89KJ4Z	GO:0007435	name: salivary gland morphogenesis	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which the anatomical structures of the salivary gland are generated and organized." [GOC:jid]	
EOG89KJ4Z	GO:0016203	name: muscle attachment	namespace: biological_process	def: "The developmental process in which a skeletal muscle attaches to its target (such as bone or body wall)." [GOC:isa_complete, GOC:sart]	
EOG8MPM58	GO:0016021	name: integral component of membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The component of a membrane consisting of the gene products and protein complexes having at least some part of their peptide sequence embedded in the hydrophobic region of the membrane." [GOC:dos, GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8MPM58	GO:0032580	name: Golgi cisterna membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The lipid bilayer surrounding any of the thin, flattened compartments that form the central portion of the Golgi complex." [GOC:ecd, GOC:mah]	
EOG8MPM58	GO:0008417	name: fucosyltransferase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the transfer of a fucosyl group to an acceptor molecule, typically another carbohydrate or a lipid." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8MPM58	GO:0017060	name: 3-galactosyl-N-acetylglucosaminide 4-alpha-L-fucosyltransferase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: GDP-L-fucose + beta-D-galactosyl-(1,3)-N-acetyl-D-glucosaminyl-R = GDP + beta-D-galactosyl-(1,3)-[alpha-L-fucosyl-(1,4)]-N-acetyl-D-glucosaminyl-R." [EC:2.4.1.65]	
