EOG8TTK15	GO:0004518	name: nuclease activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of ester linkages within nucleic acids." [ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG8TTK15	GO:0005634	name: nucleus	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A membrane-bounded organelle of eukaryotic cells in which chromosomes are housed and replicated. In most cells, the nucleus contains all of the cell's chromosomes except the organellar chromosomes, and is the site of RNA synthesis and processing. In some species, or in specialized cell types, RNA metabolism or DNA replication may be absent." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8TTK15	GO:0016568	name: chromatin modification	namespace: biological_process	def: "The alteration of DNA, protein, or sometimes RNA, in chromatin, which may result in changing the chromatin structure." [GOC:mah, PMID:20404130]	
EOG8X0Q7R	GO:0003677	name: DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular function by which a gene product interacts selectively and non-covalently with DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid)." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:tb, GOC:vw]	
EOG8X0Q7R	GO:0006351	name: transcription, DNA-templated	namespace: biological_process	def: "The cellular synthesis of RNA on a template of DNA." [GOC:jl, GOC:txnOH]	
EOG8X0Q7R	GO:0003676	name: nucleic acid binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any nucleic acid." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8X0Q7R	GO:0046872	name: metal ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any metal ion." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8X0Q7R	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8X0Q7R	GO:0005634	name: nucleus	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A membrane-bounded organelle of eukaryotic cells in which chromosomes are housed and replicated. In most cells, the nucleus contains all of the cell's chromosomes except the organellar chromosomes, and is the site of RNA synthesis and processing. In some species, or in specialized cell types, RNA metabolism or DNA replication may be absent." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8QFZV3	GO:0043169	name: cation binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with cations, charged atoms or groups of atoms with a net positive charge." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8QFZV3	GO:0003824	name: catalytic activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of a biochemical reaction at physiological temperatures. In biologically catalyzed reactions, the reactants are known as substrates, and the catalysts are naturally occurring macromolecular substances known as enzymes. Enzymes possess specific binding sites for substrates, and are usually composed wholly or largely of protein, but RNA that has catalytic activity (ribozyme) is often also regarded as enzymatic." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8QFZV3	GO:0032450	name: maltose alpha-glucosidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: alpha-maltose + H2O = 2 alpha-D-glucose." [MetaCyc:RXN-2141]	
EOG8QFZV3	GO:0016740	name: transferase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the transfer of a group, e.g. a methyl group, glycosyl group, acyl group, phosphorus-containing, or other groups, from one compound (generally regarded as the donor) to another compound (generally regarded as the acceptor). Transferase is the systematic name for any enzyme of EC class 2." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8QFZV3	GO:0003677	name: DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular function by which a gene product interacts selectively and non-covalently with DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid)." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:tb, GOC:vw]	
EOG8D55FK	GO:0032504	name: multicellular organism reproduction	namespace: biological_process	def: "The biological process in which new individuals are produced by one or two multicellular organisms. The new individuals inherit some proportion of their genetic material from the parent or parents." [GOC:isa_complete, GOC:jid]	
EOG8D55FK	GO:0008233	name: peptidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of a peptide bond. A peptide bond is a covalent bond formed when the carbon atom from the carboxyl group of one amino acid shares electrons with the nitrogen atom from the amino group of a second amino acid." [GOC:jl, ISBN:0815332181]	
EOG8D55FK	GO:0046692	name: sperm competition	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that contributes to the success of sperm fertilization in multiply-mated females." [PMID:10885514]	
EOG8D55FK	GO:0030414	name: peptidase inhibitor activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Stops, prevents or reduces the activity of a peptidase, any enzyme that catalyzes the hydrolysis peptide bonds." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8D55FK	GO:0030162	name: regulation of proteolysis	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that modulates the frequency, rate or extent of the hydrolysis of a peptide bond or bonds within a protein." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8D55FK	GO:0010951	name: negative regulation of endopeptidase activity	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that decreases the frequency, rate or extent of endopeptidase activity, the endohydrolysis of peptide bonds within proteins." [GOC:dph, GOC:tb]	
EOG8D55FK	GO:0010466	name: negative regulation of peptidase activity	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that stops or reduces the rate of peptidase activity, the hydrolysis of peptide bonds within proteins." [GOC:dph, GOC:tb]	
EOG8D55FK	GO:0004867	name: serine-type endopeptidase inhibitor activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Stops, prevents or reduces the activity of serine-type endopeptidases, enzymes that catalyze the hydrolysis of nonterminal peptide bonds in a polypeptide chain; a serine residue (and a histidine residue) are at the active center of the enzyme." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8D55FK	GO:0007610	name: behavior	namespace: biological_process	def: "The internally coordinated responses (actions or inactions) of whole living organisms (individuals or groups) to internal or external stimuli." [GOC:ems, GOC:jl, ISBN:0395448956, PMID:20160973]	
EOG8D55FK	GO:0045861	name: negative regulation of proteolysis	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that stops, prevents, or reduces the frequency, rate or extent of the hydrolysis of a peptide bond or bonds within a protein." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8QNQD6	GO:0003676	name: nucleic acid binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any nucleic acid." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8QNQD6	GO:0003964	name: RNA-directed DNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: deoxynucleoside triphosphate + DNA(n) = diphosphate + DNA(n+1). Catalyzes RNA-template-directed extension of the 3'- end of a DNA strand by one deoxynucleotide at a time." [EC:2.7.7.49]	
EOG8QNQD6	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8QNQD6	GO:0003723	name: RNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an RNA molecule or a portion thereof." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8QNQD6	GO:0015074	name: DNA integration	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which a segment of DNA is incorporated into another, usually larger, DNA molecule such as a chromosome." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8NGK1T	GO:0055085	name: transmembrane transport	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which a solute is transported across a lipid bilayer, from one side of a membrane to the other" [GOC:dph, GOC:jid]	
EOG876NDC	GO:0052689	name: carboxylic ester hydrolase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of a carboxylic ester bond." [EC:3.1.1, EC:3.1.1.1, GOC:curators]	
EOG876NDC	GO:0003990	name: acetylcholinesterase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: acetylcholine + H2O = choline + acetate." [EC:3.1.1.7]	
EOG876NDC	GO:0004104	name: cholinesterase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: an acylcholine + H2O = choline + a carboxylic acid anion." [EC:3.1.1.8]	
EOG8RZ1DV	GO:0015074	name: DNA integration	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which a segment of DNA is incorporated into another, usually larger, DNA molecule such as a chromosome." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8RZ1DV	GO:0006310	name: DNA recombination	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process in which a new genotype is formed by reassortment of genes resulting in gene combinations different from those that were present in the parents. In eukaryotes genetic recombination can occur by chromosome assortment, intrachromosomal recombination, or nonreciprocal interchromosomal recombination. Intrachromosomal recombination occurs by crossing over. In bacteria it may occur by genetic transformation, conjugation, transduction, or F-duction." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8RZ1DV	GO:0003676	name: nucleic acid binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any nucleic acid." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8RZ1DV	GO:0003723	name: RNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an RNA molecule or a portion thereof." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8RZ1DV	GO:0003964	name: RNA-directed DNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: deoxynucleoside triphosphate + DNA(n) = diphosphate + DNA(n+1). Catalyzes RNA-template-directed extension of the 3'- end of a DNA strand by one deoxynucleotide at a time." [EC:2.7.7.49]	
EOG8WDGV7	GO:0040003	name: chitin-based cuticle development	namespace: biological_process	def: "Synthesis and deposition of a chitin-based noncellular, hardened, or membranous secretion from an epithelial sheet. An example of this process is found in Drosophila melanogaster." [GOC:mtg_sensu]	
EOG8WDGV7	GO:0031012	name: extracellular matrix	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A structure lying external to one or more cells, which provides structural support for cells or tissues; may be completely external to the cell (as in animals and bacteria) or be part of the cell (as in plants)." [GOC:mah, NIF_Subcellular:nlx_subcell_20090513]	
EOG8WDGV7	GO:0008010	name: structural constituent of chitin-based larval cuticle	namespace: molecular_function	def: "The action of a molecule that contributes to the structural integrity of the chitin-based cuticle of a larva. An example of this is found in Drosophila melanogaster." [GOC:mah, GOC:mtg_sensu]	
EOG8WDGV7	GO:0022008	name: neurogenesis	namespace: biological_process	def: "Generation of cells within the nervous system." [GO_REF:0000021, GOC:cls, GOC:curators, GOC:dgh, GOC:dph, GOC:jid, GOC:mtg_15jun06]	
EOG83R62Q	GO:0005622	name: intracellular	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The living contents of a cell; the matter contained within (but not including) the plasma membrane, usually taken to exclude large vacuoles and masses of secretory or ingested material. In eukaryotes it includes the nucleus and cytoplasm." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG83R62Q	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG83R62Q	GO:0046872	name: metal ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any metal ion." [GOC:ai]	
EOG83R62Q	GO:0003964	name: RNA-directed DNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: deoxynucleoside triphosphate + DNA(n) = diphosphate + DNA(n+1). Catalyzes RNA-template-directed extension of the 3'- end of a DNA strand by one deoxynucleotide at a time." [EC:2.7.7.49]	
EOG83R62Q	GO:0003723	name: RNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an RNA molecule or a portion thereof." [GOC:mah]	
EOG83R62Q	GO:0042981	name: regulation of apoptotic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that modulates the occurrence or rate of cell death by apoptotic process." [GOC:jl, GOC:mtg_apoptosis]	
EOG8DFS4N	GO:0007165	name: signal transduction	namespace: biological_process	def: "The cellular process in which a signal is conveyed to trigger a change in the activity or state of a cell. Signal transduction begins with reception of a signal (e.g. a ligand binding to a receptor or receptor activation by a stimulus such as light), or for signal transduction in the absence of ligand, signal-withdrawal or the activity of a constitutively active receptor. Signal transduction ends with regulation of a downstream cellular process, e.g. regulation of transcription or regulation of a metabolic process. Signal transduction covers signaling from receptors located on the surface of the cell and signaling via molecules located within the cell. For signaling between cells, signal transduction is restricted to events at and within the receiving cell." [GOC:go_curators, GOC:mtg_signaling_feb11]	
EOG8DFS4N	GO:0004114	name: 3',5'-cyclic-nucleotide phosphodiesterase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: nucleoside 3',5'-cyclic phosphate + H2O = nucleoside 5'-phosphate." [EC:3.1.4.17]	
EOG8M0HHM	GO:0016491	name: oxidoreductase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of an oxidation-reduction (redox) reaction, a reversible chemical reaction in which the oxidation state of an atom or atoms within a molecule is altered. One substrate acts as a hydrogen or electron donor and becomes oxidized, while the other acts as hydrogen or electron acceptor and becomes reduced." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8M0HHM	GO:0017109	name: glutamate-cysteine ligase complex	namespace: cellular_component	def: "An enzyme complex that catalyzes the ligation of glutamate to cysteine, forming glutamylcysteine." [EC:6.3.2.2]	
EOG8M0HHM	GO:0048149	name: behavioral response to ethanol	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that results in a change in the behavior of an organism as a result of an ethanol stimulus." [GOC:jid]	
EOG8M0HHM	GO:0035229	name: positive regulation of glutamate-cysteine ligase activity	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that activates or increases the activity of glutamate-cysteine ligase, typically by lowering its sensitivity to inhibition by glutathione and by increasing its affinity for glutamate." [PMID:12954617]	
EOG8M0HHM	GO:0007611	name: learning or memory	namespace: biological_process	def: "The acquisition and processing of information and/or the storage and retrieval of this information over time." [GOC:jid, PMID:8938125]	
EOG8M0HHM	GO:0030234	name: enzyme regulator activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Binds to and modulates the activity of an enzyme." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8M0HHM	GO:0006974	name: cellular response to DNA damage stimulus	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that results in a change in state or activity of a cell (in terms of movement, secretion, enzyme production, gene expression, etc.) as a result of a stimulus indicating damage to its DNA from environmental insults or errors during metabolism." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8M0HHM	GO:0035226	name: glutamate-cysteine ligase catalytic subunit binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with the catalytic subunit of glutamate-cysteine ligase." [PMID:12954617]	
EOG8M0HHM	GO:0005829	name: cytosol	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The part of the cytoplasm that does not contain organelles but which does contain other particulate matter, such as protein complexes." [GOC:hjd, GOC:jl]	
EOG8M0HHM	GO:0016874	name: ligase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the joining of two substances, or two groups within a single molecule, with the concomitant hydrolysis of the diphosphate bond in ATP or a similar triphosphate." [EC:6, GOC:mah]	
EOG8M0HHM	GO:0019899	name: enzyme binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any enzyme." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8M0HHM	GO:0008355	name: olfactory learning	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process in an organism in which a relatively long-lasting adaptive behavioral change occurs in response to (repeated) exposure to an olfactory cue." [ISBN:0582227089]	
EOG8M0HHM	GO:0016020	name: membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A lipid bilayer along with all the proteins and protein complexes embedded in it an attached to it." [GOC:dos, GOC:mah, ISBN:0815316194]	
EOG8M0HHM	GO:0006750	name: glutathione biosynthetic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways resulting in the formation of glutathione, the tripeptide glutamylcysteinylglycine, which acts as a coenzyme for some enzymes and as an antioxidant in the protection of sulfhydryl groups in enzymes and other proteins." [CHEBI:16856, GOC:ai, GOC:al, GOC:pde, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8M0HHM	GO:0007616	name: long-term memory	namespace: biological_process	def: "The memory process that deals with the storage, retrieval and modification of information a long time (typically weeks, months or years) after receiving that information. This type of memory is typically dependent on gene transcription regulated by second messenger activation." [http://hebb.mit.edu/courses/9.03/lecture4.html, ISBN:0582227089]	
EOG8M0HHM	GO:0071722	name: detoxification of arsenic-containing substance	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that reduces or removes the toxicity of compounds containing arsenic, including arsenates, arsenites, and arsenides. These include transport of such compounds away from sensitive areas and to compartments or complexes whose purpose is sequestration of arsenic or arsenic-containing compounds." [GOC:kmv, PMID:11313333, PMID:20221439]	
EOG8MSGBZ	GO:0016787	name: hydrolase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of various bonds, e.g. C-O, C-N, C-C, phosphoric anhydride bonds, etc. Hydrolase is the systematic name for any enzyme of EC class 3." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8MSGBZ	GO:0030170	name: pyridoxal phosphate binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with pyridoxal 5' phosphate, 3-hydroxy-5-(hydroxymethyl)-2-methyl4-pyridine carboxaldehyde 5' phosphate, the biologically active form of vitamin B6." [GOC:mah, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8MSGBZ	GO:0008890	name: glycine C-acetyltransferase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: acetyl-CoA + glycine = L-2-amino-3-oxobutanoate + CoA + H(+)." [EC:2.3.1.29, RHEA:20739]	
EOG8MSGBZ	GO:0097206	name: nephrocyte filtration	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process by which hemolymph is filtered based on size and charge through a nephrocyte filtration barrier formed by the basement membrane and nephrocyte diaphragm." [GOC:sart, PMID:18971929]	
EOG8MSGBZ	GO:0005875	name: microtubule associated complex	namespace: cellular_component	def: "Any multimeric complex connected to a microtubule." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8MSGBZ	GO:0004714	name: transmembrane receptor protein tyrosine kinase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Combining with a signal and transmitting the signal from one side of the membrane to the other to initiate a change in cell activity by catalysis of the reaction: ATP + a protein-L-tyrosine = ADP + a protein-L-tyrosine phosphate." [EC:2.7.10.1, GOC:mah]	
EOG8MSGBZ	GO:0009058	name: biosynthetic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways resulting in the formation of substances; typically the energy-requiring part of metabolism in which simpler substances are transformed into more complex ones." [GOC:curators, ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG84QWFB	GO:0022857	name: transmembrane transporter activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Enables the transfer of a substance from one side of a membrane to the other." [GOC:mtg_transport, ISBN:0815340729]	
EOG84QWFB	GO:0055085	name: transmembrane transport	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which a solute is transported across a lipid bilayer, from one side of a membrane to the other" [GOC:dph, GOC:jid]	
EOG84QWFB	GO:0005215	name: transporter activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Enables the directed movement of substances (such as macromolecules, small molecules, ions) into, out of or within a cell, or between cells." [GOC:ai, GOC:dgf]	
EOG85F05D	GO:0016740	name: transferase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the transfer of a group, e.g. a methyl group, glycosyl group, acyl group, phosphorus-containing, or other groups, from one compound (generally regarded as the donor) to another compound (generally regarded as the acceptor). Transferase is the systematic name for any enzyme of EC class 2." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG85F05D	GO:0004667	name: prostaglandin-D synthase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: prostaglandin H(2) = prostaglandin D(2)." [EC:5.3.99.2, RHEA:10603]	
EOG85F05D	GO:0008152	name: metabolic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways, including anabolism and catabolism, by which living organisms transform chemical substances. Metabolic processes typically transform small molecules, but also include macromolecular processes such as DNA repair and replication, and protein synthesis and degradation." [GOC:go_curators, ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG85F05D	GO:0006749	name: glutathione metabolic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways involving glutathione, the tripeptide glutamylcysteinylglycine, which acts as a coenzyme for some enzymes and as an antioxidant in the protection of sulfhydryl groups in enzymes and other proteins; it has a specific role in the reduction of hydrogen peroxide (H2O2) and oxidized ascorbate, and it participates in the gamma-glutamyl cycle." [CHEBI:16856, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG85F05D	GO:0055114	name: oxidation-reduction process	namespace: biological_process	def: "A metabolic process that results in the removal or addition of one or more electrons to or from a substance, with or without the concomitant removal or addition of a proton or protons." [GOC:dhl, GOC:ecd, GOC:jh2, GOC:jid, GOC:mlg, GOC:rph]	
EOG85F05D	GO:0004602	name: glutathione peroxidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: 2 glutathione + hydrogen peroxide = oxidized glutathione + 2 H2O." [EC:1.11.1.9]	
EOG8S7N41	GO:0046872	name: metal ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any metal ion." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8S7N41	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG82FVXS	GO:0015020	name: glucuronosyltransferase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: UDP-glucuronate + acceptor = UDP + acceptor beta-D-glucuronoside." [EC:2.4.1.17]	
EOG82FVXS	GO:0030259	name: lipid glycosylation	namespace: biological_process	def: "Covalent attachment of a glycosyl residue to a lipid molecule." [GOC:mah]	
EOG82FVXS	GO:0016999	name: antibiotic metabolic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways involving an antibiotic, a substance produced by or derived from certain fungi, bacteria, and other organisms, that can destroy or inhibit the growth of other microorganisms." [GOC:cab2]	
EOG82FVXS	GO:0030246	name: carbohydrate binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any carbohydrate, which includes monosaccharides, oligosaccharides and polysaccharides as well as substances derived from monosaccharides by reduction of the carbonyl group (alditols), by oxidation of one or more hydroxy groups to afford the corresponding aldehydes, ketones, or carboxylic acids, or by replacement of one or more hydroxy group(s) by a hydrogen atom. Cyclitols are generally not regarded as carbohydrates." [CHEBI:16646, GOC:mah]	
EOG82FVXS	GO:0003851	name: 2-hydroxyacylsphingosine 1-beta-galactosyltransferase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: UDP-galactose + 2-(2-hydroxyacyl)sphingosine = UDP + 1-(beta-D-galactosyl)-2-(2-hydroxyacyl)sphingosine." [EC:2.4.1.45]	
EOG8FXTRF	GO:0003676	name: nucleic acid binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any nucleic acid." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8FXTRF	GO:0003964	name: RNA-directed DNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: deoxynucleoside triphosphate + DNA(n) = diphosphate + DNA(n+1). Catalyzes RNA-template-directed extension of the 3'- end of a DNA strand by one deoxynucleotide at a time." [EC:2.7.7.49]	
EOG8F20HJ	GO:0020037	name: heme binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with heme, any compound of iron complexed in a porphyrin (tetrapyrrole) ring." [CHEBI:30413, GOC:ai]	
EOG8F20HJ	GO:0016705	name: oxidoreductase activity, acting on paired donors, with incorporation or reduction of molecular oxygen	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of an oxidation-reduction (redox) reaction in which hydrogen or electrons are transferred from each of two donors, and molecular oxygen is reduced or incorporated into a donor." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8F20HJ	GO:0004497	name: monooxygenase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the incorporation of one atom from molecular oxygen into a compound and the reduction of the other atom of oxygen to water." [http://www.onelook.com/, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8F20HJ	GO:0005789	name: endoplasmic reticulum membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The lipid bilayer surrounding the endoplasmic reticulum." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8F20HJ	GO:0070330	name: aromatase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reduction of an aliphatic ring to yield an aromatic ring." [GOC:cb]	
EOG8F20HJ	GO:0033777	name: lithocholate 6beta-hydroxylase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: H(+) + lithocholate + NADPH + O(2) = 6-beta-hydroxylithocholate + H(2)O + NADP(+)." [EC:1.14.13.94, RHEA:18860]	
EOG8F20HJ	GO:0050591	name: quinine 3-monooxygenase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: H(+) + NADPH + O(2) + quinine = 3-hydroxyquinine + H(2)O + NADP(+)." [EC:1.14.13.67, RHEA:20152]	
EOG8F20HJ	GO:0033780	name: taurochenodeoxycholate 6alpha-hydroxylase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reactions: taurochenodeoxycholate + NADPH + H+ + O2 = taurohyocholate + NADP+ + H2O, and lithocholate + NADPH + H+ + O2 = hyodeoxycholate + NADP+ + H2O." [EC:1.14.13.97]	
EOG8F20HJ	GO:0035220	name: wing disc development	namespace: biological_process	def: "Progression of the wing disc over time, from its initial formation through to its metamorphosis to form adult structures including the wing hinge, wing blade and pleura." [GOC:bf, ISBN:0879694238]	
EOG82VBXK	GO:0005576	name: extracellular region	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The space external to the outermost structure of a cell. For cells without external protective or external encapsulating structures this refers to space outside of the plasma membrane. This term covers the host cell environment outside an intracellular parasite." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG82VBXK	GO:0006629	name: lipid metabolic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways involving lipids, compounds soluble in an organic solvent but not, or sparingly, in an aqueous solvent. Includes fatty acids; neutral fats, other fatty-acid esters, and soaps; long-chain (fatty) alcohols and waxes; sphingoids and other long-chain bases; glycolipids, phospholipids and sphingolipids; and carotenes, polyprenols, sterols, terpenes and other isoprenoids." [GOC:ma]	
EOG8NS5RG	GO:0008045	name: motor neuron axon guidance	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which the migration of an axon growth cone of a motor neuron is directed to a specific target site in response to a combination of attractive and repulsive cues." [CL:0000100, GOC:pr, ISBN:0878932437]	
EOG8NS5RG	GO:0016201	name: synaptic target inhibition	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which a neuronal cell in a multicellular organism recognizes chemorepellent signals that inhibit its growth toward the source." [GOC:mah, ISBN:0878932437]	
EOG8NS5RG	GO:0005811	name: lipid particle	namespace: cellular_component	def: "An intracellular non-membrane-bounded organelle comprising a matrix of coalesced lipids surrounded by a phospholipid monolayer. May include associated proteins." [GOC:mah, GOC:tb]	
EOG8NS5RG	GO:0046872	name: metal ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any metal ion." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8NS5RG	GO:0005616	name: larval serum protein complex	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A multisubunit protein complex which, in Drosophila, is a heterohexamer of three subunits, alpha, beta and gamma. The complex is thought to store amino acids for synthesis of adult proteins." [GOC:jl, PMID:6781759]	
EOG8NS5RG	GO:0045735	name: nutrient reservoir activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Functions in the storage of nutritious substrates." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8NS5RG	GO:0016491	name: oxidoreductase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of an oxidation-reduction (redox) reaction, a reversible chemical reaction in which the oxidation state of an atom or atoms within a molecule is altered. One substrate acts as a hydrogen or electron donor and becomes oxidized, while the other acts as hydrogen or electron acceptor and becomes reduced." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8616N8	GO:0003677	name: DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular function by which a gene product interacts selectively and non-covalently with DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid)." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:tb, GOC:vw]	
EOG8616N8	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8616N8	GO:0003964	name: RNA-directed DNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: deoxynucleoside triphosphate + DNA(n) = diphosphate + DNA(n+1). Catalyzes RNA-template-directed extension of the 3'- end of a DNA strand by one deoxynucleotide at a time." [EC:2.7.7.49]	
EOG8616N8	GO:0015074	name: DNA integration	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which a segment of DNA is incorporated into another, usually larger, DNA molecule such as a chromosome." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8616N8	GO:0003723	name: RNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an RNA molecule or a portion thereof." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8616N8	GO:0004190	name: aspartic-type endopeptidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of internal, alpha-peptide bonds in a polypeptide chain by a mechanism in which a water molecule bound by the side chains of aspartic residues at the active center acts as a nucleophile." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8616N8	GO:0008237	name: metallopeptidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of peptide bonds by a mechanism in which water acts as a nucleophile, one or two metal ions hold the water molecule in place, and charged amino acid side chains are ligands for the metal ions." [GOC:mah, http://merops.sanger.ac.uk/about/glossary.htm#CATTYPE]	
EOG8V71X1	GO:0005576	name: extracellular region	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The space external to the outermost structure of a cell. For cells without external protective or external encapsulating structures this refers to space outside of the plasma membrane. This term covers the host cell environment outside an intracellular parasite." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8V71X1	GO:0033227	name: dsRNA transport	namespace: biological_process	def: "The directed movement of dsRNA, double-stranded ribonucleic acid, into, out of or within a cell, or between cells, by means of some agent such as a transporter or pore." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8ZPH89	GO:0004930	name: G-protein coupled receptor activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Combining with an extracellular signal and transmitting the signal across the membrane by activating an associated G-protein; promotes the exchange of GDP for GTP on the alpha subunit of a heterotrimeric G-protein complex." [GOC:bf, http://www.iuphar-db.org, Wikipedia:GPCR]	
EOG8ZPH89	GO:0005886	name: plasma membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The membrane surrounding a cell that separates the cell from its external environment. It consists of a phospholipid bilayer and associated proteins." [ISBN:0716731363]	
EOG8ZPH89	GO:0007218	name: neuropeptide signaling pathway	namespace: biological_process	def: "The series of molecular signals generated as a consequence of a peptide neurotransmitter binding to a cell surface receptor." [GOC:mah, ISBN:0815316194]	
EOG8ZPH89	GO:0030246	name: carbohydrate binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any carbohydrate, which includes monosaccharides, oligosaccharides and polysaccharides as well as substances derived from monosaccharides by reduction of the carbonyl group (alditols), by oxidation of one or more hydroxy groups to afford the corresponding aldehydes, ketones, or carboxylic acids, or by replacement of one or more hydroxy group(s) by a hydrogen atom. Cyclitols are generally not regarded as carbohydrates." [CHEBI:16646, GOC:mah]	
