EOG805VG7	GO:0020037	name: heme binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with heme, any compound of iron complexed in a porphyrin (tetrapyrrole) ring." [CHEBI:30413, GOC:ai]	
EOG805VG7	GO:0016705	name: oxidoreductase activity, acting on paired donors, with incorporation or reduction of molecular oxygen	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of an oxidation-reduction (redox) reaction in which hydrogen or electrons are transferred from each of two donors, and molecular oxygen is reduced or incorporated into a donor." [GOC:mah]	
EOG805VG7	GO:0004497	name: monooxygenase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the incorporation of one atom from molecular oxygen into a compound and the reduction of the other atom of oxygen to water." [http://www.onelook.com/, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG805VG7	GO:0070330	name: aromatase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reduction of an aliphatic ring to yield an aromatic ring." [GOC:cb]	
EOG805VG7	GO:0005789	name: endoplasmic reticulum membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The lipid bilayer surrounding the endoplasmic reticulum." [GOC:mah]	
EOG805VG7	GO:0050591	name: quinine 3-monooxygenase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: H(+) + NADPH + O(2) + quinine = 3-hydroxyquinine + H(2)O + NADP(+)." [EC:1.14.13.67, RHEA:20152]	
EOG805VG7	GO:0004796	name: thromboxane-A synthase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: prostaglandin H(2) = thromboxane A(2)." [EC:5.3.99.5, RHEA:17140]	
EOG805VG7	GO:0031000	name: response to caffeine	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that results in a change in state or activity of a cell or an organism (in terms of movement, secretion, enzyme production, gene expression, etc.) as a result of a caffeine stimulus. Caffeine is an alkaloid found in numerous plant species, where it acts as a natural pesticide that paralyzes and kills certain insects feeding upon them." [CHEBI:27732, GOC:ef, GOC:mah]	
EOG805VG7	GO:0009055	name: electron carrier activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular entity that serves as an electron acceptor and electron donor in an electron transport chain. An electron transport chain is a process in which a series of electron carriers operate together to transfer electrons from donors to any of several different terminal electron acceptors to generate a transmembrane electrochemical gradient." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG805VG7	GO:0016712	name: oxidoreductase activity, acting on paired donors, with incorporation or reduction of molecular oxygen, reduced flavin or flavoprotein as one donor, and incorporation of one atom of oxygen	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of an oxidation-reduction (redox) reaction in which hydrogen or electrons are transferred from reduced flavin or flavoprotein and one other donor, and one atom of oxygen is incorporated into one donor." [GOC:mah]	
EOG805VG7	GO:0017085	name: response to insecticide	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that results in a change in state or activity of a cell or an organism (in terms of movement, secretion, enzyme production, gene expression, etc.) as a result of an insecticide stimulus. Insecticides are chemicals used to kill insects." [GOC:curators]	
EOG805VG7	GO:0006697	name: ecdysone biosynthetic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways resulting in the formation of ecdysone, (22R)-2-beta,3-beta,14,22,25-pentahydroxycholest-7-en-6-one, an ecdysteroid found in insects." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG805VG7	GO:0050829	name: defense response to Gram-negative bacterium	namespace: biological_process	def: "Reactions triggered in response to the presence of a Gram-negative bacterium that act to protect the cell or organism." [GOC:ai]	
EOG805VG7	GO:0030178	name: negative regulation of Wnt signaling pathway	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that stops, prevents, or reduces the frequency, rate or extent of the Wnt signaling pathway." [GOC:dph, GOC:go_curators, GOC:tb]	
EOG805VG7	GO:0017143	name: insecticide metabolic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways involving insecticides, chemicals used to kill insects." [GOC:ai]	
EOG805VG7	GO:0046701	name: insecticide catabolic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways resulting in the breakdown of insecticides, chemicals used to kill insects." [GOC:ai]	
EOG805VG7	GO:0022416	name: chaeta development	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process whose specific outcome is the progression of a chaeta over time, from its formation to the mature structure. A chaeta is a sensory multicellular cuticular outgrowth of a specifically differentiated cell." [FBbt:00005177, GOC:bf, GOC:cjm, GOC:dos, GOC:isa_complete]	
EOG805VG7	GO:0042742	name: defense response to bacterium	namespace: biological_process	def: "Reactions triggered in response to the presence of a bacterium that act to protect the cell or organism." [GOC:jl]	
EOG805VG7	GO:0048252	name: lauric acid metabolic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways involving lauric acid, a fatty acid with the formula CH3(CH2)10COOH. Derived from vegetable sources." [CHEBI:30805, GOC:jid]	
EOG805VG7	GO:0016020	name: membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A lipid bilayer along with all the proteins and protein complexes embedded in it an attached to it." [GOC:dos, GOC:mah, ISBN:0815316194]	
EOG805VG7	GO:1901563	name: response to camptothecin	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that results in a change in state or activity of a cell or an organism (in terms of movement, secretion, enzyme production, gene expression, etc.) as a result of a camptothecin stimulus." [GOC:TermGenie]	
EOG805VG7	GO:0018685	name: alkane 1-monooxygenase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: octane + reduced rubredoxin + O2 = 1-octanol + oxidized rubredoxin + H2O." [EC:1.14.15.3]	
EOG805VG7	GO:0033777	name: lithocholate 6beta-hydroxylase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: H(+) + lithocholate + NADPH + O(2) = 6-beta-hydroxylithocholate + H(2)O + NADP(+)." [EC:1.14.13.94, RHEA:18860]	
EOG805VG7	GO:0002118	name: aggressive behavior	namespace: biological_process	def: "A behavioral interaction between organisms in which one organism has the intention of inflicting physical damage on another individual." [GOC:hjd]	
EOG805VG7	GO:0046683	name: response to organophosphorus	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that results in a change in state or activity of a cell or an organism (in terms of movement, secretion, enzyme production, gene expression, etc.) as a result of an organophosphorus stimulus. Organophosphorus is a compound containing phosphorus bound to an organic molecule; several organophosphorus compounds are used as insecticides, and they are highly toxic cholinesterase inhibitors." [ISBN:0721662544]	
EOG805VG7	GO:0035220	name: wing disc development	namespace: biological_process	def: "Progression of the wing disc over time, from its initial formation through to its metamorphosis to form adult structures including the wing hinge, wing blade and pleura." [GOC:bf, ISBN:0879694238]	
EOG805VG7	GO:0048638	name: regulation of developmental growth	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that modulates the frequency, rate or extent of developmental growth." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG805VG7	GO:0040040	name: thermosensory behavior	namespace: biological_process	def: "Behavior that is dependent upon the sensation of temperature." [GOC:ems]	
EOG805VG7	GO:0046680	name: response to DDT	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that results in a change in state or activity of a cell or an organism (in terms of movement, secretion, enzyme production, gene expression, etc.) as a result of a DDT stimulus. DDT, dichlorodiphenyltrichloroethane, is a chlorinated hydrocarbon pesticide moderately toxic to humans and other animals." [ISBN:0721662544]	
EOG805VG7	GO:0046689	name: response to mercury ion	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that results in a change in state or activity of a cell or an organism (in terms of movement, secretion, enzyme production, gene expression, etc.) as a result of a mercury ion stimulus." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0006508	name: proteolysis	namespace: biological_process	def: "The hydrolysis of proteins into smaller polypeptides and/or amino acids by cleavage of their peptide bonds." [GOC:bf, GOC:mah]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0005615	name: extracellular space	namespace: cellular_component	def: "That part of a multicellular organism outside the cells proper, usually taken to be outside the plasma membranes, and occupied by fluid." [ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0005576	name: extracellular region	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The space external to the outermost structure of a cell. For cells without external protective or external encapsulating structures this refers to space outside of the plasma membrane. This term covers the host cell environment outside an intracellular parasite." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0007586	name: digestion	namespace: biological_process	def: "The whole of the physical, chemical, and biochemical processes carried out by multicellular organisms to break down ingested nutrients into components that may be easily absorbed and directed into metabolism." [GOC:isa_complete, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0004175	name: endopeptidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of internal, alpha-peptide bonds in a polypeptide chain." [http://merops.sanger.ac.uk/about/glossary.htm#ENDOPEPTIDASE]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0016021	name: integral component of membrane	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The component of a membrane consisting of the gene products and protein complexes having at least some part of their peptide sequence embedded in the hydrophobic region of the membrane." [GOC:dos, GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0016787	name: hydrolase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of various bonds, e.g. C-O, C-N, C-C, phosphoric anhydride bonds, etc. Hydrolase is the systematic name for any enzyme of EC class 3." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0016301	name: kinase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the transfer of a phosphate group, usually from ATP, to a substrate molecule." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0008236	name: serine-type peptidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of peptide bonds in a polypeptide chain by a catalytic mechanism that involves a catalytic triad consisting of a serine nucleophile that is activated by a proton relay involving an acidic residue (e.g. aspartate or glutamate) and a basic residue (usually histidine)." [http://merops.sanger.ac.uk/about/glossary.htm#CATTYPE, ISBN:0716720094]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0045087	name: innate immune response	namespace: biological_process	def: "Innate immune responses are defense responses mediated by germline encoded components that directly recognize components of potential pathogens." [GO_REF:0000022, GOC:add, GOC:ebc, GOC:mtg_15nov05, GOC:mtg_sensu]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0006629	name: lipid metabolic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways involving lipids, compounds soluble in an organic solvent but not, or sparingly, in an aqueous solvent. Includes fatty acids; neutral fats, other fatty-acid esters, and soaps; long-chain (fatty) alcohols and waxes; sphingoids and other long-chain bases; glycolipids, phospholipids and sphingolipids; and carotenes, polyprenols, sterols, terpenes and other isoprenoids." [GOC:ma]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0006952	name: defense response	namespace: biological_process	def: "Reactions, triggered in response to the presence of a foreign body or the occurrence of an injury, which result in restriction of damage to the organism attacked or prevention/recovery from the infection caused by the attack." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0045752	name: positive regulation of Toll signaling pathway	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that activates or increases the frequency, rate or extent of the Tl signaling pathway." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0050830	name: defense response to Gram-positive bacterium	namespace: biological_process	def: "Reactions triggered in response to the presence of a Gram-positive bacterium that act to protect the cell or organism." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0008063	name: Toll signaling pathway	namespace: biological_process	def: "A series of molecular signals initiated by the binding of an extracellular ligand to the receptor Toll on the surface of a target cell, and ending with regulation of a downstream cellular process, e.g. transcription." [GOC:go_curators, PMID:11135568, PMID:19126860]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0008233	name: peptidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of a peptide bond. A peptide bond is a covalent bond formed when the carbon atom from the carboxyl group of one amino acid shares electrons with the nitrogen atom from the amino group of a second amino acid." [GOC:jl, ISBN:0815332181]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0005829	name: cytosol	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The part of the cytoplasm that does not contain organelles but which does contain other particulate matter, such as protein complexes." [GOC:hjd, GOC:jl]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0008889	name: glycerophosphodiester phosphodiesterase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: a glycerophosphodiester + H2O = an alcohol + sn-glycerol 3-phosphate." [EC:3.1.4.46]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0006071	name: glycerol metabolic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways involving glycerol, 1,2,3-propanetriol, a sweet, hygroscopic, viscous liquid, widely distributed in nature as a constituent of many lipids." [GOC:ai, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0050832	name: defense response to fungus	namespace: biological_process	def: "Reactions triggered in response to the presence of a fungus that act to protect the cell or organism." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0022008	name: neurogenesis	namespace: biological_process	def: "Generation of cells within the nervous system." [GO_REF:0000021, GOC:cls, GOC:curators, GOC:dgh, GOC:dph, GOC:jid, GOC:mtg_15jun06]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0050829	name: defense response to Gram-negative bacterium	namespace: biological_process	def: "Reactions triggered in response to the presence of a Gram-negative bacterium that act to protect the cell or organism." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0009950	name: dorsal/ventral axis specification	namespace: biological_process	def: "The establishment, maintenance and elaboration of the dorsal/ventral axis. The dorsal/ventral axis is defined by a line that runs orthogonal to both the anterior/posterior and left/right axes. The dorsal end is defined by the upper or back side of an organism. The ventral end is defined by the lower or front side of an organism." [GOC:dph, GOC:go_curators, GOC:tb]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0035006	name: melanization defense response	namespace: biological_process	def: "The blackening of the wounded area of the cuticle or the surface of invading pathogens, parasites or parasitoids, resulting from a proteolytic cascade leading to the de novo synthesis and deposition of melanin." [GOC:bf, PMID:12408809]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0007311	name: maternal specification of dorsal/ventral axis, oocyte, germ-line encoded	namespace: biological_process	def: "Polarization of the oocyte along the dorsal-ventral axis, by a gene product encoded by cells of the germ line. An example of this is found in Drosophila melanogaster." [GOC:dph, GOC:mtg_sensu, GOC:tb, ISBN:0879694238]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0031638	name: zymogen activation	namespace: biological_process	def: "The proteolytic processing of an inactive enzyme to an active form." [GOC:hjd]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0006964	name: positive regulation of biosynthetic process of antibacterial peptides active against Gram-negative bacteria	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that activates or increases the frequency, rate, or extent of biosynthesis of antibacterial peptides active against Gram-negative bacteria." [GOC:mah, PMID:10973475]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0005515	name: protein binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any protein or protein complex (a complex of two or more proteins that may include other nonprotein molecules)." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0005622	name: intracellular	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The living contents of a cell; the matter contained within (but not including) the plasma membrane, usually taken to exclude large vacuoles and masses of secretory or ingested material. In eukaryotes it includes the nucleus and cytoplasm." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0004435	name: phosphatidylinositol phospholipase C activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: 1-phosphatidyl-1D-myo-inositol 4,5-bisphosphate + H(2)O = 1,2-diacylglycerol + 1D-myo-inositol 1,4,5-trisphosphate + H(+)." [EC:3.1.4.11, RHEA:23915]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0048812	name: neuron projection morphogenesis	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which the anatomical structures of a neuron projection are generated and organized. A neuron projection is any process extending from a neural cell, such as axons or dendrites." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0008592	name: regulation of Toll signaling pathway	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that modulates the frequency, rate or extent of the Tl signaling pathway." [GOC:go_curators]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0006967	name: positive regulation of antifungal peptide biosynthetic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that activates or increases the frequency, rate, or extent of antifungal peptide biosynthesis." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0003964	name: RNA-directed DNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: deoxynucleoside triphosphate + DNA(n) = diphosphate + DNA(n+1). Catalyzes RNA-template-directed extension of the 3'- end of a DNA strand by one deoxynucleotide at a time." [EC:2.7.7.49]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0035008	name: positive regulation of melanization defense response	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that increases the rate or extent of the melanization defense response during injury or invasion." [GOC:bf]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0035007	name: regulation of melanization defense response	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that affects the rate, extent or location of the melanization defense response during injury or invasion." [GOC:bf]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0035556	name: intracellular signal transduction	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process in which a signal is passed on to downstream components within the cell, which become activated themselves to further propagate the signal and finally trigger a change in the function or state of the cell." [GOC:bf, GOC:jl, GOC:signaling, ISBN:3527303782]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0003723	name: RNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an RNA molecule or a portion thereof." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0005581	name: collagen trimer	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A protein complex consisting of three collagen chains assembled into a left-handed triple helix. These trimers typically assemble into higher order structures." [GOC:dos, GOC:mah, ISBN:0721639976, PMID:19693541, PMID:21421911]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0004930	name: G-protein coupled receptor activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Combining with an extracellular signal and transmitting the signal across the membrane by activating an associated G-protein; promotes the exchange of GDP for GTP on the alpha subunit of a heterotrimeric G-protein complex." [GOC:bf, http://www.iuphar-db.org, Wikipedia:GPCR]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0006909	name: phagocytosis	namespace: biological_process	def: "An endocytosis process that results in the engulfment of external particulate material by phagocytes. The particles are initially contained within phagocytic vacuoles (phagosomes), which then fuse with primary lysosomes to effect digestion of the particles." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0004180	name: carboxypeptidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of the terminal or penultimate peptide bond at the C-terminal end of a peptide or polypeptide." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0006959	name: humoral immune response	namespace: biological_process	def: "An immune response mediated through a body fluid." [GOC:hb, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0004471	name: malate dehydrogenase (decarboxylating) (NAD+) activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: (S)-malate + NAD+ = pyruvate + CO2 + NADH + H+." [EC:1.1.1.38, EC:1.1.1.39]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0016485	name: protein processing	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any protein maturation process achieved by the cleavage of a peptide bond or bonds within a protein. Protein maturation is the process leading to the attainment of the full functional capacity of a protein." [GOC:curators, GOC:jl, GOC:jsg]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0003677	name: DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular function by which a gene product interacts selectively and non-covalently with DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid)." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:tb, GOC:vw]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0051287	name: NAD binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with nicotinamide adenine dinucleotide, a coenzyme involved in many redox and biosynthetic reactions; binding may be to either the oxidized form, NAD+, or the reduced form, NADH." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8C5G07	GO:0042060	name: wound healing	namespace: biological_process	def: "The series of events that restore integrity to a damaged tissue, following an injury." [GOC:bf, PMID:15269788]	
EOG8F4VSG	GO:0047886	name: farnesol dehydrogenase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: 2-trans,6-trans-farnesol + NADP(+) = 2-trans,6-trans-farnesal + H(+) + NADPH." [EC:1.1.1.216, RHEA:14700]	
EOG8F4VSG	GO:0004316	name: 3-oxoacyl-[acyl-carrier-protein] reductase (NADPH) activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: (3R)-3-hydroxyacyl-[acyl-carrier protein] + NADP+ = 3-oxoacyl-[acyl-carrier protein] + NADPH + H+." [EC:1.1.1.100]	
EOG8F4VSG	GO:0016063	name: rhodopsin biosynthetic process	namespace: biological_process	def: "The chemical reactions and pathways resulting in the formation of rhodopsin, a brilliant purplish-red, light-sensitive visual pigment found in the rod cells of the retinas." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8F4VSG	GO:0022008	name: neurogenesis	namespace: biological_process	def: "Generation of cells within the nervous system." [GO_REF:0000021, GOC:cls, GOC:curators, GOC:dgh, GOC:dph, GOC:jid, GOC:mtg_15jun06]	
EOG8BVV85	GO:0003964	name: RNA-directed DNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: deoxynucleoside triphosphate + DNA(n) = diphosphate + DNA(n+1). Catalyzes RNA-template-directed extension of the 3'- end of a DNA strand by one deoxynucleotide at a time." [EC:2.7.7.49]	
EOG8BVV85	GO:0004519	name: endonuclease activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of ester linkages within nucleic acids by creating internal breaks." [GOC:mah, ISBN:0198547684]	
EOG8BVV85	GO:0006355	name: regulation of transcription, DNA-templated	namespace: biological_process	def: "Any process that modulates the frequency, rate or extent of cellular DNA-templated transcription." [GOC:go_curators, GOC:txnOH]	
EOG8Z91BB	GO:0003676	name: nucleic acid binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with any nucleic acid." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8Z91BB	GO:0003964	name: RNA-directed DNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: deoxynucleoside triphosphate + DNA(n) = diphosphate + DNA(n+1). Catalyzes RNA-template-directed extension of the 3'- end of a DNA strand by one deoxynucleotide at a time." [EC:2.7.7.49]	
EOG8Z91BB	GO:0003723	name: RNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with an RNA molecule or a portion thereof." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8Z91BB	GO:0003677	name: DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular function by which a gene product interacts selectively and non-covalently with DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid)." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:tb, GOC:vw]	
EOG8Z91BB	GO:0008270	name: zinc ion binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Interacting selectively and non-covalently with zinc (Zn) ions." [GOC:ai]	
EOG8Z91BB	GO:0004523	name: RNA-DNA hybrid ribonuclease activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the endonucleolytic cleavage of RNA in RNA-DNA hybrids to 5'-phosphomonoesters." [EC:3.1.26.4]	
EOG8Z91BB	GO:0005622	name: intracellular	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The living contents of a cell; the matter contained within (but not including) the plasma membrane, usually taken to exclude large vacuoles and masses of secretory or ingested material. In eukaryotes it includes the nucleus and cytoplasm." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8Z91BB	GO:0019028	name: viral capsid	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The protein coat that surrounds the infective nucleic acid in some virus particles. It comprises numerous regularly arranged subunits, or capsomeres." [GOC:mtg_sensu, ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG8Z91BB	GO:0046718	name: viral entry into host cell	namespace: biological_process	def: "The process that occurs after viral attachment by which a virus, or viral nucleic acid, breaches the plasma membrane or cell envelope and enters the host cell. The process ends when the viral nucleic acid is released into the host cell cytoplasm." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8Z91BB	GO:0019076	name: viral release from host cell	namespace: biological_process	def: "The dissemination of mature viral particles from the host cell, e.g. by cell lysis or the budding of virus particles from the cell membrane." [GOC:jl]	
EOG8Z91BB	GO:0006351	name: transcription, DNA-templated	namespace: biological_process	def: "The cellular synthesis of RNA on a template of DNA." [GOC:jl, GOC:txnOH]	
EOG8Z91BB	GO:0003899	name: DNA-directed RNA polymerase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the reaction: nucleoside triphosphate + RNA(n) = diphosphate + RNA(n+1). Utilizes a DNA template, i.e. the catalysis of DNA-template-directed extension of the 3'-end of an RNA strand by one nucleotide at a time. Can initiate a chain 'de novo'." [EC:2.7.7.6]	
EOG8Z91BB	GO:0044163	name: host cytoskeleton	namespace: cellular_component	def: "Any of the various filamentous elements that form the internal framework of host cells, and typically remain after treatment of the cells with mild detergent to remove membrane constituents and soluble components of the host cytoplasm. The term embraces intermediate filaments, microfilaments, microtubules, the microtrabecular lattice, and other structures characterized by a polymeric filamentous nature and long-range order within the host cell. The various elements of the host cytoskeleton not only serve in the maintenance of host cellular shape but also have roles in other host cellular functions, including cellular movement, cell division, endocytosis, and movement of organelles." [GOC:rph]	
EOG8Z91BB	GO:0075521	name: microtubule-dependent intracellular transport of viral material towards nucleus	namespace: biological_process	def: "The directed movement of a virus, or part of a virus, towards the host cell nucleus using host microtubules." [UniProtKB-KW:KW-1177, VZ:983]	
EOG8Z91BB	GO:0042025	name: host cell nucleus	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A membrane-bounded organelle as it is found in the host cell in which chromosomes are housed and replicated. The host is defined as the larger of the organisms involved in a symbiotic interaction." [GOC:pamgo_curators]	
EOG8Z91BB	GO:0030430	name: host cell cytoplasm	namespace: cellular_component	def: "The cytoplasm of a host cell." [GOC:mah]	
EOG8Z91BB	GO:0004190	name: aspartic-type endopeptidase activity	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Catalysis of the hydrolysis of internal, alpha-peptide bonds in a polypeptide chain by a mechanism in which a water molecule bound by the side chains of aspartic residues at the active center acts as a nucleophile." [ISBN:0198506732]	
EOG88KTTR	GO:0003677	name: DNA binding	namespace: molecular_function	def: "Any molecular function by which a gene product interacts selectively and non-covalently with DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid)." [GOC:dph, GOC:jl, GOC:tb, GOC:vw]	
EOG88KTTR	GO:0000786	name: nucleosome	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A complex comprised of DNA wound around a multisubunit core and associated proteins, which forms the primary packing unit of DNA into higher order structures." [GOC:elh]	
EOG88KTTR	GO:0005634	name: nucleus	namespace: cellular_component	def: "A membrane-bounded organelle of eukaryotic cells in which chromosomes are housed and replicated. In most cells, the nucleus contains all of the cell's chromosomes except the organellar chromosomes, and is the site of RNA synthesis and processing. In some species, or in specialized cell types, RNA metabolism or DNA replication may be absent." [GOC:go_curators]	
